<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2018-09-28T21:09:26+01:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jaws]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/jaws" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/jaws</id>
  <published>2018-09-28T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2018-09-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since the last post, us Lawley’s have just been bimbling along nicely. We had time up on the North East coast with my family which was a lovely break and good to see everyone.
I also had my scan in August, which thankfully gave us the news that the tumours in my hip and shoulder have successfully shrunk and hopefully will continue to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, recently, things have been less great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A week ago, I started having pain in my left side jaw, teeth and gums.  Come Sunday, the pain was so much worse, I’d had no sleep, my mouth was feeling numb and I had maxed out on all painkillers - I’d reached the end of my tether.  I decided to phone 111 and get some medical advice.  Thankfully, things moved pretty quickly from there, and I was sent to see an out of hours GP in Stevenage.  Ross ended up missing Felix’s rugby so he could take me, but thankfully Duncan, another coach and dad of Felix’s friend, took him off and kept ahold of him all day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GP could see there was an infection there, but when I pointed out some exposed jaw, she said she thought it might be Osteonecrosis of the Jaw caused by one of the infusions I have to keep my bone mets under control.  She got a second opinion, but as he didn’t see the exposed jaw, he said it was just an infection, I needed antibiotics, which she gave me a prescription for, and told me to see a dentist that day, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I was onto 111 again, this time to ask to see an out of hours dentist.  It started getting tricky here, as Ross needed to take Imy up to Northampton as she was captaining her u13 rugby team (they drew), and they were already one coach down.  Thankfully, after a quick shout out, my friend Tash dropped everything and took me down to Stevenage, again, to the dentist.  After explaining the problem, giving my history and extensive list of medications, her having a look, and an X-ray, she said it was Osteonecrosis caused by the same drug the GP mentioned and to see my own dentist asap as I was deemed a High Risk Patient (!).  She agreed with the antibiotics the GP had give me and sent me on my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2018teethxray.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dental X-Ray&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
To a dentist, this X-ray shows what BONJ is...
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this happened before 1pm on Sunday afternoon, which was brilliant.  I’d have been out of my mind if I’d had to wait until Monday.  Thank goodness for the NHS!  I then went to sleep for a long nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come Monday, Ross was straight on the phone to my dentist to get an emergency appointment.  They know my dental and medical history, so would be able to see any changes that have happened recently.&lt;br /&gt;
The pain had started to reduce as the antibiotics kicked in, thank goodness, as the dentist (who was lovely) was prodding around, and also wanted a whole mouth X-ray.  Again, he mentioned Osteonecrosis but gave it an acronym as BONJ, which standards for ‘Bisphosphonate-associated Osteonecrosis of the Jaw’.  He said he would put a referral into my local hospital’s MaxFax (Maxillofacial) department as the X-ray indicated that the jaw below my left lower teeth had started to soften, and the fact I had exposed jaw meant that I was a High Risk Patient (that again!!).  I was told the gum infection wasn’t really an issue, as he see’s them every single day and are easily dealt with using antibiotics, but the fact I have looked after my teeth and they are in good condition, and that the infection was only in one place told him something wasn’t right.  So off we went again, to go home and think about what was happening.  I was still in discomfort, so much so, I’d told my manager that I wouldn’t be able to work this week, as I couldn’t think far beside the pain in my jaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this time, my appetite has decreased to all but nothing, so Ross has been encouraging me to eat soft food, soup, shakes, etc.  It’s all very well and good, but I just don’t feel like eating.  Especially as when I do eat, I’m not 100% I am dribbling due to my mouth being numb. (Imagine you’ve had a numbing injection in your mouth to have dental work done.  It feel’s like that, all the time.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been exhausted as I can’t wear my CPAP machine due to it hurting my jaw, so my sleeping has been disturbed.  It’s meant I’m either sleeping in longer in the morning, or getting up and having to have serious naps during the day.  Today I missed meeting up with friends, and a Pamper Plus session at the Hospice.  Meh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, using Ross’s BUPA membership, we managed to get to see a MaxFax consultant on Tuesday evening.  He was very nice, and really knew his stuff, being a hybrid between a doctor and a dentist with a whole lot of training on top.  I had a whole mouth X-ray (again), and after examining me, confirmed the BONJ diagnosis, and explained to us why it happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gist is, the bisphosphonate infusions I have as part of my regime to keep the cancer at bay. It’s a 1 in 100 side-effect of the treatment. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cancerresearchuk.org/about-cancer/cancer-in-general/treatment/bisphosphonates/how-bisphosphonates-work&quot;&gt; Cancer Research&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Bisphosphonates target the areas of higher bone turnover. The osteoclast cells absorb the bisphosphonate drug, which slows down their activity and reduces bone breakdown.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consultant explained to Ross and I that whilst the Bisphosphonate was slowing down the osteocloasts, which are type of bone cell that recycle dead bone cells, this in turn slows down the chance a cancer cell getting ahold of a normal bone cell and turning it into a cancerous one.  This slowing down is a problem in cases where there is trauma, and the mouth is constantly undergoing trauma when eating, which is why this condition affects patients who take this treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I’ll hopefully fight off this infection, the pain will stop and I’ll start feeling my mouth again.  I’ll then be kept a close on my the MaxFax team at the hospital, as I’m a High Risk Patient (stop!), and any dental work that needs doing will need to be done under their care.&lt;br /&gt;
Longterm, I may be susceptible to more infections, which may lead to me being permanently on antibiotics.  Also, my teeth may start to fall out as the bone softens underneath them.  As they fall out, the healing will be more difficult, leaving the next tooth exposed…like dominoes. Of course I googled the condition…I wish I hadn’t.  Some of the pictures were pretty grim.  I’ve just got to hope mine don’t get that bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst the condition has been found early, I’m feeling angry with the world that this is happening.  Just when we start to think things are settling, and we are plodding along, thinking we are ok, and the rug gets pulled out from under us - again. I’m trying to be the happy, positive person everyone expects me to be, but even smiling hurts.  I want to curl up in a ball and pretend none of this is happening.  Just because we had good news from the scan, doesn’t mean it has to be cancelled out by this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, next we need to see what happens with the referral and in the meantime, I’ll keep on, keeping on.  Unfortunately, it’s getting harder to do when I keep having these things thrown at me.  But what else can I can do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/jaws&quot;&gt;Jaws&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 28, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer Sun]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/summer-sun" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/summer-sun</id>
  <published>2018-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2018-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Cor what a Scorcha!&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to write a catch up for a while, but despite only working 10 hours a week, I never seem to find the time.  I suppose it’s because I know I’m going to have to concentrate for a decent amount of time.  Something that I find difficult to do.  Even when I’m working I struggle to concentrate, and trying to find apply logic to a software problem can sometimes have embarrassing results.  Thankfully my line manager accepts these limitations and is glad of anything I produce, and if it actually works properly, then that’s a bonus! :-D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it may take me a few days to complete this post…but I will complete this post! So far, I’m a week in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title of this blog post is a nod to the fact we are in the midst of a two month (and counting) heat wave.  Everyone has a sweat sheen on them, and the ice cream van is doing a roaring business.  In fact Imy saw 3 outside the local waterpark last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the last post not knowing whether I’d be able to have Cyberknife or not, and looking forward to our holiday in Sherwood Forest and Felix’s 10th birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left the decision making re. the Cyberknife to my Oncologist and went on a break to Forest Holiday’s in May half term.  It was just what we needed to take our mind of things.  We stayed in a cabin in the forest with it’s own hot tub.  We knew I’d be limited in what I was able to do due to my levels of pain and fatigue, so I was careful not to overdo it. There were activities we could take part in nearby, so we went on a wildlife walk (which despite being short, wiped me out for the rest of the day), Ross and the kids went on bike rides, Imy and I did an art class, and the highlight was doing archery and air rifle shooting on Felix’s birthday.  Also for his birthday, we organised for a cake, present and decorations to be delivered to our cabin whilst we were out. It was a lovely surprise for him when we got back.  One of the best things was seeing the wildlife coming right down to the patio of our cabin to feed on the seeds and snacks we put out for them.  We saw squirrels, Jays, sparrows, crows and a lizard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2018squirrel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Squirrel&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once home, we were given the news that the Cyberknife was going ahead and I needed to go down to Mount Vernon for a planning session.  This involved a  CT scan so the team could create a plan to make sure that the tumour was targeted, whilst minimizing the damage to nearby healthy tissue and creating a mould of me with a vacuum packed beanbag.  This was to be used so that I wouldn’t be able to move and stay in exactly the same position for all sessions.  I was to have 5 hourly sessions on my hip, and 3 on my shoulder.  We decided that in order to reduce the traveling to and from Mount Vernon, I would have a hip session and then a shoulder session immediately after, so I only needed to travel there 5 times rather than 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2018cyberknife.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyber Knife&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things went to plan for the most part, apart from a small delay due to a faulty part.  All we have to do now is wait until the next scan in August to see if it has been successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up in the list of events in the Lawley House came Ross’s visit to New York for a work for a week.  The airline he was having flying with had problems with it’s operations, and his return flight was cancelled.  Thankfully, he managed to get on the one scheduled to leave before his and he was home earlier than expected.  Had he not done that, he would have been stuck in New York for an extra 2-3 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we began with the school end of term wind down and all that came with it.  Kids coming home with bags of books, work done throughout the year, p.e. kits that were in varying states of use, our attendance was required at dance displays and music concerts, and everyone was generally very sweaty due to a very heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the first decent rain decided to start the week our building work commenced.  At the minute it’s all groundwork to level the garden, but it can’t be done in the rain.  Hopefully things will be back on track soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that’s everything and I’m up to date now…  We’ll be going up to visit my Dad and Step Mum later on in the holidays which we are looking forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, keep on keeping on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s.  It seems appropriate to mention a fellow school mum who I met as she has a boy the same age as Felix, as well as a younger son.  Last month after dealing with cancer for 8 years, she sadly died.  It makes me so cross that cancer is so indiscriminate in who gets the disease.  Donna and her family deserved better.  I think of her often as she was a very plucky, no nonsense woman, and did everything he could to spend as much time as she could with her boys. Rest in peace. xx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/summer-sun&quot;&gt;Summer Sun&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on August 10, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peas In A Pod]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/peas-in-a-pod" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/peas-in-a-pod</id>
  <published>2018-05-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Peas - small, green, innocuous vegetables. &lt;p&gt;I had a full body MRI scan 2 weeks ago to see if I had any new growths.  I have them every 3-4 months at the Paul Srictland Scanner Centre at Mount Vernon Cancer Centre in North West London.  I’m not a fan of that hospital, but we do what we must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three days ago I went to see my Oncologist for the results.  We had a quick update on the CPAP diagnosis and treatment, and then we got onto the scan results. Unfortunately, despite having a 9 week course of Chemo and then also adding Perjeta to my 3 weekly Herceptin infusion last summer, the tumours which were first diagnosed in May 2017, have grown.  Here’s where the peas come in…  They were now each just less than 1cm in diameter, the size of a pea, and both in the same relative place, the ball joint in my shoulder, and the ball joint in my hip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what’s next?  The existing treatment is keeping everything under control except in these two areas, so there is no need for an overall change to treatment just yet.  The ideal scenario would be to have 3 to 5 sessions of Cyberknife, with both areas being treated one after the other, making for a very long stretch at Mount Vernon.  Cyberknife is targeted high dose radiotherapy, and is a new technology.  I had it in February 2016 on my back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Oncologist is trying to clear this, but there are two other options.  One is standard radiotherapy, which is at a lower dose and wider area than the Cyberknife.  The last, and least preferred option, is joint replacements.  Obviously, that is very invasive surgery and has a long recovery period. No thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m next seeing the Oncologist in 3 weeks, and we’ll have a plan of attack then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a shitty bit of news, but it could have been worse.  The two areas are painful, but I can always increase the amount of Morphine I’m taking.  The Palliative Consultant in the Hospice is keeping an eye on me and encouraging me to alter my meds should I feel the need and giving me the knowledge and confidence in order to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with Imy’s exams, half term holiday and Felix’s birthday, we’ll continue on with life as normally as we can and keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/peas-in-a-pod&quot;&gt;Peas In A Pod&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 23, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Can't Get No Sleep]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/i-cant-get-no-sleep" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/i-cant-get-no-sleep</id>
  <published>2018-04-26T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2018-04-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">In 1995 Faithless sang to us about Insomnia.&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably noticed that one of the recurring topics I keep bringing up is how tired I am, and how much fatigue affects my ability to lead a normal life.  It’s not Insomnia as such, as I do get sleep.  I’m asleep for up to 11 hours a night, but the quality of my sleep is dreadful.  I’ll often get up in the night to go to the loo, or for no reason at all.  I also sleep walk, sleep talk, and wave my arms around.  (I am fully aware of how weird that all sounds, especially the last bit!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had test after test to try and get to the bottom of it.  All anyone could tell me was that it was most possibly just culmination of the affects of all the treatments that I’ve had over the past 4 to 5 years.  I sat in the GP’s office and sobbed because I was so tired all the time, and yet their seemed to be no real or concrete explanation.  I was not waking up refreshed.  I had headaches.  I felt like I had cotton wool behind my eyes.  I’d hit a wall at 3pm and have to have a nap. My energy levels were so low, I’d find it hard to muster any enthusiasm to leave the house. I was finding it difficult to concentrate and I was starting to think I should stop driving as although I don’t drive far, or very often, I knew things were deteriorating.  It was all a mystery…until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst seeing my oncologist in February, we spoke again about my tiredness, and what could be causing it.  He suggested that he could refer me to a Sleep Clinic, as he’d recently had a patient who was also complaining of tiredness and fatigue and had been diagnosed with Obstructive Sleep Apnoea.  He did warn me that if it was this condition, then it would have life changing repercussions.  This suggestion was a new one, so even with the potential consequences, we got the ball rolling asap, and in March, I went to my local hospital which very handily has a Sleep Clinic.  I was given a piece of machinery which would record my blood oxygen saturation levels via a clip on my finger, and how often I breathe by having little air tubes by my nose.  I was to use this for one night only, return the machine, and they would review the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April, I went to see the Sleep Clinic Consultant, who after a short preamble, told me I had severe Obstructive Sleep Apnoea (OSA). OK, great, so what’s that then!  According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/obstructive-sleep-apnoea/&quot;&gt;NHS Website&lt;/a&gt; it’s:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Obstructive sleep apnoea (OSA) is a relatively common condition where the walls of the throat relax and narrow during sleep, interrupting normal breathing.
This may lead to regularly interrupted sleep, which can have a big impact on quality of life and increases the risk of developing certain conditions”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the consultant, everyone wakes up naturally up to four times an hour. The test machine was recording any drop in my blood oxygen saturation levels of 4% or more, and also how many times I stopped breathing.  For reference these are the levels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mild OSA - 5-15 apnoea episodes an hour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medium OSA - 15-30 apnoea episodes an hour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Severe OSA - 30+ apnoea episodes an hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My results were 50+ apnoea episodes an hour.  That’s about 1 a minute.  And in each episode my brain picks up that not enough oxygen is coming in, so kick starts everything and wakes me up.  Some of these I will remember, some I won’t but it’s stopping me from getting into a normal sleep cycle and therefore I’m not getting enough sleep.  In fact the quality is very poor indeed.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consultant then went on to tell me about the treatment and other ramifications.  The first one being that I have to stop driving immediately.  I can’t even just pop to Tesco.  A full informal ban on it until the treatment starts and is proven to work, then I can tell the DVLA I have this condition, but I am being treated successfully for it, with the Sleep Clinic providing proof.  Of course I need to start the treatment first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment comes in the form of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blf.org.uk/support-for-you/obstructive-sleep-apnoea-osa/cpap-machines&quot;&gt;CPAP machine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“CPAP is a simple machine that pumps air through a mask you wear at night. It’s designed to hold your airway open while you’re asleep. It sends air at pressure into your upper airway to stop it collapsing or narrowing. “&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, this week, I went to a CPAP session for new users.  There were 3 of us there, me, and two older gentlemen.  According to the NHS, there are lots of different people who get OSA for lots of different reasons, however the most common in older overweight men and post menopausal women.  So once again, I find myself with a condition that technically I’m too young for.  ANd once again, I have to just suck it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CPAP machine is very quiet, and once I’m wearing it, Ross can’t hear it at all.  It’s a very odd feeling having to wear it, as it’s unlike anything I’ve worn before.  The mask is pressurised so it is sucked onto my face, unlike an oxygen mask you may wear in hospital or similar which just sit on your face.  Ross says I look like a fighter pilot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2018cpap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CPAP&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using it for two nights now, and whilst some people get used to it straight away, I’m still not quite there yet.  Hopefully, it won’t be long and I can stop feeling like a zombie during the day, and more like a normal person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ll do as I always do and keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/i-cant-get-no-sleep&quot;&gt;I Can't Get No Sleep&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 26, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ooph! Surgery!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/ooph" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/ooph</id>
  <published>2018-04-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2018-04-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">More surgery and a Funeral&lt;p&gt;The type of Breast Cancer that I have feeds off oestrogen (er+). A woman mainly produces it in their ovaries, but both men and women also produce it in their adrenal glands and in fat tissue.  In order to suppress the production of oestrogen, to stop it being used by cancer cells to grow, my treatment included taking daily tablets, and monthly implants/injections.  Not a huge part of my treatment put still something on the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finished treatment for my primary cancer in January 2015, a scan revealed that I had a cyst on my right ovary, and after much discussion, it was decided that given my history, I should have both the cyst and ovary removed.  This happened in May 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was diagnosed with secondary cancer, I was keen to have the other ovary removed to eliminate the monthly implants/injections.  A procedure called an Oophorectomy.  My oncologist agreed, but he wanted me to have 2 stable scans under my belt before I went in for surgery.  After waiting for those scans, I was given the date of 26th March for the surgery which was Ross and my wedding anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately two weeks before the surgery, my Gran, Irene, died.  She was 88, and living in a care home, so it was not unexpected, despite this, it was a sad occasion. I was close to my Gran growing up and I have a lot of fond and funny memories of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2018gran.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gran&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funeral was organised to be on the Thursday after my surgery on the Monday.  With this in mind, I was keen to leave hospital on the day of surgery as it had gone to plan.  Unfortunately, my surgeon disagreed, due to a high pulse, low blood pressure, and being sick.  Meh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, my Dad and Julie came in to visit to let me know they were heading home after spending a couple of days with us to look after the kids, whilst Ross looked after me.  They took Imy with them as she’d started her school holidays a week earlier than Felix, to help them out with little things before the funeral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that morning, I was discharged and given express instructions that I needed to take the painkillers and rest for a couple of days.  On Wednesday afternoon, once Felix had taken his Grade 1 guitar exam (which he passed with merit), we headed up to my Dad’s in Newcastle, where we were going to stay for the funeral and a week afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, the surgery, the drive, the funeral, the wake, and our little holiday up there, all went to plan and I was able to recuperate, whilst Ross and the kids were able to have some down time and enjoy some fun activities, including ice skating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will miss my Gran very much, but as she was the one to say, I’ll keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/ooph&quot;&gt;Ooph! Surgery!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 01, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello 2018]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hello-2018" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hello-2018</id>
  <published>2018-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2018-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Please be kind...&lt;p&gt;We saw 2018 in at our very good friends, The Martin’s, with more good friends attending. I’m still suffering with fatigue, so it was decided that I would drive the family back from the party.  Our hosts even had a bed made up incase I needed to have a nap mid-celebrations.  Thankfully I didn’t need to take them up on their offer.  The evening was very enjoyable, indeed, made even more enjoyable by not having to walk home, and being there five minutes after we left the party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days into the New Year I had to go down to Mount Vernon for my regular full body MRI scan. I have to admit, it’s not my favourite drive, place or experience, being strapped down onto a bed, with a mask put over my head, and then slid into a long enclosed tube.  I’m then left there for nearly an hour, with ear plugs and headphones playing music to try and drown out the very loud noises the machine makes…it doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A week later we were given the results, which were positive.  My shoulder tumour has shrunk slightly, and my hip one is showing no sign of activity.  There’s still no reason found for my fatigue, so I’m being referred to a couple of consultants to see if they can figure anything out.  More waiting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medical news aside, back to family life, Imy wanted to take part in a Trampolining competition, but it took part on a mid-January Sunday morning, when Ross takes Felix to rugby.  After much soul-searching and encouragement from Ross, we decided that Ross would get a lift to the rugby club, and I would drive Imy to Cambridge for the competition.  This was a big thing for me as it involves driving about 25 miles.  I haven’t drive more than 5 miles in a while.  So when the day came, I got up early, put my Big Girl Pants on, and drove Imy to Cambridge University Sports Centre for the Eastern Region Qualifier.  She had practiced very hard with her club, and after doing her routine twice in front of the judges.  As she hadn’t finished in the top 3, we came home, and relaxed for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, she went to Trampolining club, and they told her that her overall score meant that she had qualified for the regional quarter final.  She was delighted, and we were very proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I think that’s us pretty much up to date.  I’m still having treatment every 3 weeks, I’m still tired, but we’re plodding on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hello-2018&quot;&gt;Hello 2018&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 24, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodbye 2017]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/goodbye-2017" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/goodbye-2017</id>
  <published>2017-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">At the end of 2017, I had time to reflect on what had happened during the year.&lt;p&gt;My last post was back in October, and in Lawley Land, when things are quiet, I tend not to write a post as there’s not much to write about.  It’s a good thing really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the purpose of this post is just to recap on what has been going on over the past few months of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been regularly attending sessions at the Garden House Hospice for a number of reasons:&lt;br /&gt;
Reflexology - I normally have 6 weekly sessions, every 3 or 4 months, with a lovely Complementary Therapist who uses specific aromatherapy oils depending on how I’m feeling that day.  I always come out of each session feeling very relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music Therapy - This is usually every 3 weeks where I meet with a Music Therapist.  I give her music I want to use during the session, and she plays the piano and I sing!  I’ve always loved singing, but I don’t have the confidence to do it on my own, only in a choir, or with my family, or in the therapy session. The session gives me space to do something I love, allowing me to make mistakes, sing out of tune, and just enjoying it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Consultations - I see a palliative doctor every 6-8 weeks who keeps an eye on my mental, emotional and physical wellbeing. He is the one who I talk to about my painkillers, and keeping on top of my pain levels. He is great, and I always feel more positive after seeing him.  However, back in September it was obvious that things weren’t right, and he diagnosed me with Depression, put me on the relevant medication, and got me on the list for counselling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1-2-1 Counselling - I’m currently in the middle of a course of 12 sessions.  I’m trying to get my head around the fact that however normal (!) I may look on the outside, I am not a normal 40 year old, and my life expectancy is substantially shorter.  This is really hard to do, and I’m not there yet.  It’s taking a while.  I live between scans, and at any point the rug can be pulled from underneath me.  It’s a case of trying to live as much as possible when things are stable, and take things as they come when they don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, we went up to the North East to visit my family in October half term.  I’ve been suffering with extreme fatigue, but there was one thing that I know I wanted to do when we were there.  And that was to go to Beamish Outdoor Museum.  I used to go frequently with school as a child, and I was keen for my kids to see it.  I knew the site was very large, so in order to get the best out of it, Ross and I decided that we would invest in a wheelchair, the idea was that instead of using energy walking about, I could use it engaging with the family.  Very generously, Ross’s Mum helped us out financially, so that we could buy one, and as a result we had a lovely day at the museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2017beamish.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beamish&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the year plodded towards the end, we had a few family outings:  Imy’s school music concert and Carol concert, Felix’s Christmas Show, a trip to the cinema to see Star Wars in 4DX where the chairs move and you get sprayed in the face with water, a trip into London to watch a Pantomime organised by Ross’s work.  In it, were Elaine Paige and Diversity!  Two things ticked off the Bucket List!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we knew it the Christmas holidays arrived and Ross produced his usual, amazing Christmas Dinner, enjoyed by us as well as visiting Uncle Max, Dad and Julie.
The rest of the year we weren’t quite sure what day we were on, but our diet consisted of chocolate, gin, with a treatment day thrown in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017 started well.  There was a dip in the middle, another dip in September, which I’m still coming up from, but it’s ended ok.  Let’s hope for a quiet 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/goodbye-2017&quot;&gt;Goodbye 2017&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strictly Fab-u-lous]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/strictly-funtimes" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/strictly-funtimes</id>
  <published>2017-10-06T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-10-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">A month or so ago, I had a phone call from Grandma Julie asking me what I was doing on Saturday 30th of September.&lt;p&gt;After checking the diary, I confirmed that I wasn’t doing anything, and she then announced that she had managed to get tickets to be in the audience for Strictly Come Dancing that night, and would I like to go with her.  Would I?  Would I!!  Of course I would!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, plans were made for Dad and Julie came down to stay on the Friday and spend a little bit of time with us over that weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, here’s the thing, just because you’ve received the tickets, it doesn’t actually guarantee you a seat in the audience.  They send out twice as many tickets as there are seats, and then you queue up at Elstree Studios on the Saturday morning for them to be validated.  These tickets are like gold dust.  Millions of people apply for them, and only 500 actually get in to see the show live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross and Julie came up with a plan that would see them get to the Studios at about 8:15am.  (Thankfully I didn’t need to be there for that bit.)  But it’s a good job they didn’t leave it any later as some people had been queuing with chairs/blankets/tents since 4am!  Once the tickets were validated, all that remained was for Julie and I to come back at 4pm with our Glad Rags on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d spent the majority of Thursday, Friday and Saturday in bed because I knew this event was going to take it out of me, but I wasn’t going to miss out.  By 3:45pm, we were dressed to impress, and on our way down the A1 to dazzle with the best of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/strictly.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Strictly&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had our tickets and ID checked, went through security and found ourselves  in a waiting area.  After finding somewhere for me to sit, Julie went off to get us some Strictly Swag and when she came back we chatted to some nearby people.  Phones were banned so there was no taking photo’s unless you wanted an official one taken against a Strictly backdrop.  The queue was massive, so we opted out.  There was lots of glitter, sparkle, excitement and prosecco in this room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At about 5:30pm, just before they started to get people organised into queues to go into the studio, we thought about asking a steward if I needed to do anything differently because of my mobility issues.  We did, as it happened.  I had to stand in a “Special” queue, which got let into the studio first.   Yippee!! We were escorted into an area which was directly below the “Clauditorium”, beside the staircase that the dancers run up to be interviewed after their performance.  Great seats, but we weren’t likely to be seen on the tv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The warm up man came out and after a few gag’s, rehearsed lines, recorded links, it was time for the main show.  What can I say - it was amazing!  The energy given off by some of the dancers was intense.  Some wowed us, others less so.  At one point, Aljaz came over, shook my hand and asked if I was enjoying myself.  Yes - I definitely was! The whole atmosphere was electric…and before we knew it, it was all over.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole thing was Fab-U-Lous.  Am-Az-Ing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An experience never to be repeated, and one that left me exhausted and in my PJ’s for most of Sunday.  Would I recommend it to any other Strictly fans?  Absolutely.  Have a look on the BBC website and register.  You’ve got to be in it, to win it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on that note…keep dancing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/strictly-funtimes&quot;&gt;Strictly Fab-u-lous&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 06, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Versions of Me]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/version-of-me" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/version-of-me</id>
  <published>2017-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">In June this year, when we received the news that the cancer had spread into my shoulder and hips, Imy was upset that I was going to lose my hair again.&lt;p&gt;She said that she didn’t like the “No Hair” version of me, and that she wished it didn’t have to happen.  We explained that it was an unfortunate inevitability to my treatment, and it was better to lose my hair, than let the cancer grow any more, and also I wouldn’t be bald forever, it would grow back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then got into a discussion about different versions of me, and I’ve decided to document it in pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-1&quot;&gt;Version 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the Pre-Cancer version of me.  I was working 4 days a week as a Software Team Leader.  Family life was good.  I had Friday as my Mummy Day and we were in a good routine with the kids enjoying their swimming, gymnastics, Little Ruggers, etc.  Then we sere served a curve ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-2&quot;&gt;Version 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is me during my Primary Breast Cancer treatment.  Treatment that involved two lots of surgery, (Sentinal Node Biopsy and Double Mastectomy), chemotherapy, Herceptin, radiotherapy and hormone therapy. From diagnosis in October 2013, to finishing Herceptin in 2015, I had treatment for 15 grueling months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-3&quot;&gt;Version 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is me when I finished most of my primary treatments (except Herceptin) and was adjusting to the New Normal.  During this time I had 2 lots of surgery, an Oophorectomy and my DIEP reconstruction.  It gave us time to regroup as a family and take a long needed breath of fresh air.  Literally as well as figuratively, with a week spent in the Peak District and a week in the Lake District.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-4&quot;&gt;Version 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the version of me that was diagnosed with Secondary Breast Cancer in January 2016.  I had only had 12 months as Version 3.  When I was in so much pain that I would wake up screaming with the pain, and when I had to have two weeks in the Garden House Hospice to get it under control.  I had been put on enough Morphine to fell an elephant.  I had a difficult, delicate, and potentially life changing surgery to remove and reconstruct a vertebrae after it collapsed.  After that was the long road to recovery with a few clear scans along the way.  Things were starting to look up.
I was able to have an extended celebration for my 40th birthday with friends and family.  By June 2017, I felt the best I had done since Version 3, but then we had another curve ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-5&quot;&gt;Version 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version5&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the current version of me.  The version that has just finished another course of chemotherapy.  I have no hair, although as I’ve finished, it is growing back, but I am struggling with low mood and fatigue.  Hopefully with support of my medical team, this version won’t last long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-6&quot;&gt;Version 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the future version of me, when I will still be dealing with Secondary cancer, but I’ll have my hair back, and look more like Version 1 or 3.  Hopefully it won’t be too long, at least until I have a covering of hair so I don’t feel I have to cover up with a hat/scarf or wig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/version-of-me&quot;&gt;Versions of Me&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 20, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemo Catch-up, etc.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/catchup" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/catchup</id>
  <published>2017-09-07T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-09-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Since the last post I&#39;ve finished chemo, the kids have had their school holidays, we&#39;ve been on our highly anticipated family summer holiday and Imy has started a new school.&lt;p&gt;For some reason it’s harder to write the blog posts now than it was when I was dealing with my Primary diagnosis nearly 4 years ago.  I don’t know if it’s because I’ve done a lot of it before, fatigue, or general “Cantbearseditis”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last post, I’ve finished my course of chemo and am now completely bald.  To be fair, there’s a little bit of fluff, but not much.  I got to ring the End of Treatment Bell at the hospital - very exciting!.  It was a bit of a cheat really, as although I’d finished the course of 7 sessions of chemo, I will still be returning to the unit every 3 weeks for Herceptin, Zoledronic Acid and Perjeta.  Technically my treatment will never end, so I took this opportunity to ring that bell!&lt;br /&gt;
(Note the hat, I crocheted that myself out of bamboo yarn!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FSpireHarpendenHospital%2Fvideos%2F2195347237157793%2F&amp;amp;show_text=1&amp;amp;width=560&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;528&quot; style=&quot;border:none;overflow:hidden&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late July, Imy finished primary school.  She’s not going to the same secondary school as the majority of her old classmates, so during the Leavers Assembly, she got very tearful.  There was lots of hugs and love being shared. Later on in the day they all got together at our local Muddy Obstacle Arena, where they had one last blow out together which involved lots of water, mud, laughs and daftness.  It was a great way to end her time at a lovely school.  A school that holds lots of fond memories and which has supported her when she needed supporting the most.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fast forward to Tuesday this week, and she started secondary school.  She has to get up just before 7am (she’s not a morning person) so she can catch the train there.  The majority of her primary school classmates decided to go to the local secondary school, but Imy preferred the Girl’s School, the downside being a longer commute.  Ross accompanied her on the train on her first day, her friend’s mum went with them yesterday, and today they went by themselves - armed with their travel passes. Already so independent!  They get the 7:54am train in the morning, walk for 15 minutes from the station to school and then return home at about 4:10pm in the afternoon.  So far, she’s loving it, making lots of new friends, and enjoying the new experiences.  Long may it continue!  I really do think it’ll be great for her and allow her to unlock all the potential she has.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/newschool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New School&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
During the summer holiday’s we tried to continue as normal, and the kids had a lot of free time whilst I recovered from the weekly chemo sessions.  They went on a rugby camp, spent a few days with their Granny and Grandad Lawley, and saw their cousins which was fun as it involved sleeping in a tent in Uncle Rich’s garden!&lt;br /&gt;
My Dad and Julie came down for a visit, and amongst other fun things, took the kids out to the zoo, and to the local trampolining centre.  Dad also did a few bits of DIY that Ross hadn’t had time to do.&lt;br /&gt;
Then before we knew it, we were off on our holiday to Portugal!  We had thought about cancelling it when we got the news of the cancer spread, but my Oncologist said he would work the treatment dates around it, and that it would be best all around if we went on holiday. Doctor’s Orders!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m so glad we went.  We’d rented a villa with it’s own pool, in the middle of no-where on the Algarve, about an hour away from Faro through James Villas.  We hired a car and therefore we were on our own timetable, could eat when we wanted, go in the pool when we wanted, explore if and when we wanted, and it was a resounding success.  We all had a great time.  A lot of time was spent at the villa, just relaxing (and swimming).  But we did go out and about to have a look at a few beaches, look at some tourist shops, ate out a few times and navigate around a huge hypermarket, marveling at the local delicacies…chicken toes anyone?  It was a fabulous holiday which we will remember for a long time to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/portugalaug2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Portugal Holiday&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I think that brings us up to date.  The day after we got back, I was back on treatment, and this afternoon I’m off to have an MRI to see if the chemo/Perjeta has made any difference to the two new spots.  Fingers crossed!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/catchup&quot;&gt;Chemo Catch-up, etc.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 07, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shovel List]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/shovel-list" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/shovel-list</id>
  <published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">In Marian Keyes&#39; book, The Mystery of Mercy Close, we meet the main character, Helen Walsh.&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently listened to this book which I borrowed as a digital download from the library for free.  Clever stuff, but I digress…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helen has a “Shovel List”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A shovel..?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“No, a shovel list. It’s more of a conceptual thing. It’s a list of all the people and things I hate so much I want to hit them in the face with a shovel.” [^fn]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a similar list for a while, but since reading the book I have been inspired to give it the name ‘The Shovel List’.  A small part of it is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wine being referred as “Vino”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calling someone “Hun”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The word “Bliss”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The phrase “I can’t believe it’s been &lt;em&gt;insert time period&lt;/em&gt; since &lt;em&gt;insert event&lt;/em&gt;”.  E.g.  “I can’t believe it’s been 11 years since I was in labour with Imy!  Where did the time go!?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I may have mentioned these peeves before in a previous blog post, but I can’t find it.  If I find it, I’ll add the link here.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I’m going to break my rule and say “I can’t believe it’s been a month since my last blog post”.  In that blog post, I was saying how we didn’t have a set plan in place for the next part of treatment and that we’d just have to wait and see, and it was business as usual until then including the bairns birthday party, Imy’s 11th birthday and Ross’s 40th birthday.  Great fun on all fronts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/muddybirthdays.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Muddy Birthday Party Fun&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 68%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ross40.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ross is 40&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 28%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; New Treatment Regime&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The treatment regime is changing by adding Perjeta (Pertuzumab – HER2 targeted) alongside the 3 weekly Herceptin (Trastuzumab - HER2 targeted) and Zoledronic acid (bone strengthener).  This combination will be ongoing until it doesn&#39;t or stops working.  In addition, I&#39;m having a course of up to 7 sessions of chemotherapy (Paclitaxel ), which I&#39;ll receive weekly.
&lt;br /&gt;
My first Perjeta was on Tuesday 27th June, with the chemo starting the day after.  There’s been one Perjeta and three chemo sessions since, and so far, things are going to plan, with only minor side effects in the form of an upset stomach and an increase in fatigue levels.
&lt;br /&gt;
Thankfully, and helpfully, my Dad came down to stay for the first week so he could take some of the weight by the kids to and from school and feeding us all. Grandma Julie came down this week for my third chemo session to help out in the same way. (In fact she&#39;s just gone home :-( ). It was one less thing for Ross and myself to worry about. Thank you both for coming and helping, it really does take the pressure off Ross, who is working full-time and accompanying me to my appointments, and stops me from &quot;sweating the small stuff&quot;.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Going, Going, Going...&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Since Monday, my hair has started falling out.  It started slowly, but it&#39;s now coming out in handfuls.  I washed my hair on Wednesday, and I couldn&#39;t believe (Shovel List) how much came out whilst washing, brushing and drying.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/goodbye_hair.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goodbye Hair&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 68%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I have a lot of hair, so despite there being hair shed all over the house, there&#39;s still quite a lot on my head.  I&#39;m having to wear a hat for bed as I&#39;ve woken up with so much hair on my pillow I made me quite upset.  The hair is collateral damage.  Another local Mum, Donna, who also has Stage 4 Cancer and looking at yet another lot of chemo and hair loss says, when it comes to the choice of Hair or Death, it&#39;s a no brainer.  (Check out her blog here:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://itsallgonetitsoff.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;It&#39;s All Gone Tit&#39;s Off. &lt;/a&gt;  She&#39;s amazing.)
&lt;br /&gt;
After seeing how much hair had come out on Wednesday, and after it had been recommended, I went to see &lt;a href=&quot;http://cancerhaircare.com/&quot;&gt; Cancer Hair Care&lt;/a&gt; in Stevenage to seek their advice. Having such a marvelous resource so close, I&#39;m annoyed with myself that I hadn&#39;t gone when I had chemo previously!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My visit was very successful and I came away with a lot of information. From looking after my hair as it falls out, how to care for my scalp, recommendations for scalp/hair products, a couple of head coverings, and best of all, a new wig that actually suited me! &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d bought a wig off the Internet in 2014, but it didn&#39;t look right, so I didn&#39;t wear it. I took it with me to see if they could do anything with it, as amongst everything else they do, they work with the hair salon next door to offer a cutting service. The lady was very honest with me and told me that my wig was never going to look right: it was too heavy, too shiny and too big for my head as I have no forehead. Not to be defeated, she disappeared for a few minutes before reappearing with a wig which was very similar to a previous hairstyle I&#39;ve had.  Win! A few adjustments to the fringe and I now have a wig that I can wear should I go somewhere where I think a wig would be more appropriate than a hat or scarf.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The services I received were for a nominal donation. Considering how much wigs can cost, it has saved a lot of money, but it&#39;s not about the money, it&#39;s about how they treated me with dignity and respect from the moment I stepped into the room. All the ladies who were working for the charity had all lost their hair through chemo, so they knew how I was feeling. They were so knowledgeable and empathetic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To anyone who is local to Stevenage and faces losing their hair, I wholeheartedly recommend them. Not only can you pop into their studio, but they run sessions at Barnet Hospital, Chase Farm Hospital in Enfield, Lister Hospital in Stevenage and the Princess Alexandra Hospital in Essex.&lt;br /&gt;
And to everyone else, if you see a charity box for them, stick a bit of spare change in it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[^fn] http://www.mariankeyes.com/books/the-mystery-of-mercy-close &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/shovel-list&quot;&gt;Shovel List&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on July 14, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last still counts.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-still-counts" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-still-counts</id>
  <published>2017-07-09T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">On Sunday 9th June, accompanied by a group of friends, I managed to complete the Race For Life.  &lt;p&gt;I had warned my fellow Racers, (ladies from my work, school Mum’s and original Gin Club Members),  that I would be walking very slowly and wouldn’t be surprised if I finished towards the back of the crowd.  As it turns out, I finished last!  (There were ladies doing the 10km run, so we weren’t the final ones to cross the line). I felt no shame in coming last, in fact, I was very pleased to have actually finished!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rfl_2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Race For Life 2017&quot; /&gt;
Photo credits. Top and bottom left:  James McClung.  Bottom right:  Ross Lawley
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a previous life, I was quite good at doing a 5km, (ok I was never the fastest, but I could do them with fairly little training involved), and I’ve got a fair few medals!  However, after last year’s surgery on my spine, the new tumour in my hip, treatment related fatigue and the new chemo regime, this year was always going to be a lot tougher.  I don’t think I appreciated how hard it would be, though.  Mentally as well as physically.  But after about an hour and a quarter, my walking buddies, Caroline, Rachel, Rebecca, Rachel and myself, accompanied by the cheers of the crowds, we crossed the line.  I was hugged by Courtney, the CRUK Event Coordinator, and the rest of the teamies who had waited around for me to finish.  I kept a lid on things until I got a hug from Ross, but that was the final straw and I was reduced to a blubbering mess, moaning about my hurty hip. (You can probably see from my face in the photo how much pain I was in.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once home, after a shower, I went to bed, and didn’t get up until the next morning.  In years gone by, I’d have gone to a beer garden to celebrate the Race’s success, but this year, I had to bow out and the celebrations had to go on without me.  Thankfully, my hip hasn’t been hurting as a consequence of the Race, so I’m pretty pleased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundraising page is still open, so if anyone has any spare pennies &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mariankeyes.com/books/the-mystery-of-mercy-close&quot;&gt; head over here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-still-counts&quot;&gt;Last still counts.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on July 09, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holidays, Birthdays & Bad News]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/holidays-birthdays-bumps" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/holidays-birthdays-bumps</id>
  <published>2017-06-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-06-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">As a family, the past month has been great!&lt;p&gt;Over half term Felix turned 9, and we went on holiday to Norfolk.  We didn’t quite march the kids for miles as we’ve done on holidays in the past, but we did go for short walks and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.treasuretrails.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Treasure Trails&lt;/a&gt;, which were great fun.  We went for a (very short) swim in the sea, caught some crabs off Cromer Pier, ate out for Felix’s birthday treat and had a thoroughly relaxing time.  In fact it’s fair to say, that apart from the fatigue, I’m feeling the best I have in 18 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/norfolkmay2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norfolk Holiday&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad and Julie came down to visit for the weekend to look after the kids whilst Ross and I went off to a fancy hotel as a joint 40th present from them. I’d managed to forget my handbag, so after an emergency run to Boots for a private prescription (top tip: carry your repeat prescription with you, or have it in the car at all times), and then a purchase of a new handbag, we were able to relax.  We had a great time - saw a man walking his parrot down the street, we drank cocktails, ate like lords, chatted, laughed a lot and saw Rod Stewart in a garden centre on the way home.  Thank you Dad &amp;amp; Julie. xx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/downhall2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Down Hall&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we went to see the Oncologist for the results of the scan I’d had the week before.  Given how well I’m feeling, we were quite optimistic, but as it turns out, that optimism was misplaced.  The scan has picked up two new tumours, one in my shoulder and one in my hip.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple of weeks, the change in treatment will be finalised, and I may have to have another course of chemo.  I don’t know the full details as it’s being decided between my Oncologist and the health insurance company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s fair to say, that Ross and I are both gutted.  We had thought we were on a winning streak, and things would continue on an even keel.  Sadly, this is not to be.  Family and friends are rallying once again, getting ready to step into the breach should Ross and I need any help. Help that is completely priceless, and for which we are very thankful and humbled by.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, whilst we wait, I’m keen to keep things as normal as possible, and then we’ll deal with whatever happens next when it happens.  But first things first, family life goes on, and we’ve got Imy and Felix’s joint birthday party on Saturday to organise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/holidays-birthdays-bumps&quot;&gt;Holidays, Birthdays & Bad News&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Headaches & Flashbacks]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/headaches-flashbacks" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/headaches-flashbacks</id>
  <published>2017-05-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-05-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">For the third time in 10 months I&#39;ve been trying to come off Morphine.&lt;p&gt;** &lt;strong&gt;I wrote this post at the beginning of May but didn’t get around to publishing it.  Better late than never!&lt;/strong&gt; **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The surgeon who did my back operation has said that he wouldn’t be surprised if I am permanently on painkillers.  The surgery was very invasive, and caused a lot of trauma around my spine.  In an area that has a lot of nerves, it’s logical to expect that painkillers would be on the cards long term.  Except, for me, I don’t want to take the painkillers.  I don’t want to take Morphine long term, for no other reason than failure to stop taking the painkillers is just that - Failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is completely illogical.  I know there are no prizes for not taking painkillers.  For grinning and bearing it.  But I don’t want to be reliant on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly, I’ve reduced the Morphine and instead of being on 130mg twice a day, as I was before my surgery, (enough to knock a grown man off his feet), I’m now on 10mg twice a day.  I’ve also stopped taking Gabapentin for nerve pain, and Naproxen which is similar but stronger than Ibuprofen.  Two weeks ago, I tried to swap the Morphine for Codeine.  Previously, I’d taken it before with no problems, but this time it gave me an incredible headache.  I managed a week on codeine before I relented and went back to the Morphine.  Unfortunately, my Headache didn’t get the memo and I’m still suffering with the headaches.  Hopefully with time, they’ll get better.  Of course, it doesn’t stop me thinking that the Cancer has come back.  I’ve developed a bit of hip pain too, which is annoying.  I have a scan in 4 weeks so all will be clear then.  I’m not bringing it forward…what happens happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every so often I find a photo and I try and think when it was taken.  Was it before the Shit hit the fan?  Or was it in the period before, when life was normal?  When it was straightforward?  I sometimes forget than Felix was only 5 when I was diagnosed the first time.  5 -  only in Year One.  Imy was 7, and in Year 3.  So small.  Like yesterday, but forever at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to think back to what you remember about being in Year 1.  What about before that?  It breaks my heart that my kids will have there childhood memories tainted by Cancer.  I shouldn’t have to explain to my eight-year-old boy that there is no Stage 5 Cancer.  Stage 4 is the highest it goes.  No-one goes from Stage 4 Cancer to nothing, even though technically I have No Evidence of Disease, it basically means the cancer cells aren’t big enough to be picked up in a scan, and that the treatment regime is keeping everything under control.  It can turn on a sixpence, and I could be on chemo before you can say “My Goodness!  What rotten Luck!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as life goes on, we’re planning our holiday in Norfolk, Felix’s birthday, shortly followed by Imy’s and then Ross’s.  Busy, busy.  Live is for living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/headaches-flashbacks&quot;&gt;Headaches & Flashbacks&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Singing, SATs and Flying Solo]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-sats-solo" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-sats-solo</id>
  <published>2017-05-11T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-05-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The past few weeks have been quite busy!&lt;p&gt;The Bank Holiday weekend saw the 10th Independent Baldock Beer Festival take place.  This event is a firm Lawley favourite, having been to them all so far.  Over the past 3 years, we’ve started volunteering as well as being (very) willing customers.  Ross is a dab hand behind the bar now, and I decided that this year, I’d have a go too.  It was fun!  I selected the Cider and Wine bar as it was quieter, the drinks easier to pour, and I can now tick “Work behind a Bar” off my Bucket List.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My choir, Singing Aloud, performed at the Festival, and it was great to be part of something that had such good feedback. Very generously, the choir gave their performance fee to the Garden House Hospice which has helped my family and I so much over the past year and a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following week involved both bairns going to their Rugby Award’s Ceremony.  As Imy is part of a junior team which is a collaboration of three rugby clubs, she went off for an evening sit down formal do on a school night!  I had bought her a lovely dress to wear, but after a conversation with her teammates, it seemed jeans, funky t-shirts and high tops were the order of the day.  She did relent to wearing some makeup.  (Unusually for a 10 year old girl, she doesn’t like wearing make up!)  She came home delighted to have been nominated for Most Improved Player and was very happy for the person who won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix’s awards were an altogether different affair, as it was for the Mini’s section, and they were a bit rowdier!  They had a few fun games to start with, and then it was time for the awards bit.  There were 6 age groups, and at least 3 prizes per age group, so it took a bit of time to get through…
Felix picked up the under 9’s Tackle Machine award and the Player’s Player Of The Year award.  He was also nominated for Player of The Year, and so came back with two trophies and lots of sweets.  He was so chuffed, and I was so proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross now coaches Felix’s age group, but unfortunately due to him having to go to New York, he was unable to see Felix pick up his awards, or collect his own gift of Beer for giving up his Sunday morning’s to train the kids.  More on that in a bit.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/felix_rugbyawards2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Felix Awards&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week has been the week of Imy’s SATs.  We decided that the weekend preceding it was not to be for school work, but for fun.  We knew we had the rugby awards to look forward to, and planned a visit to the Splash Park too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning, the postman brought us a rather unexpected parcel. On Facebook, I had seen an advert for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/mrsbeesemporium&quot;&gt;Mrs Bee’s Emporium&lt;/a&gt;, and she was sending out good luck letters and small token gift to the kids doing their SATs.  I thought this was a brilliant idea, so I ordered one for Imy, to show how much we were thinking about her.  However, when it arrived, the parcel was A LOT BIGGER than I had expected.  Little did I know that a group of ladies who I knew from years ago, on an online forum, had decided to club together and get a gift of a Pug, Star and Letter for Imy, a Pug for Felix and a Star and Letter for me.  Once a few dots had been joined and we realised what had happened, Ross and I both had to have a moment!  Sometimes we are so engrossed in being in The Eye Of The Storm, and just getting through the day, that we forget that we have a legion of people rooting for us, and understanding that, yes, all families with Year 6 kids are under pressure, but we’ve got an extra layer of unpleasantness going on. Imy has had the star in her pocket all week, and my star has been close to hand too. The gifts were completely unexpected, and very much appreciated.  Thank you. xx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mrsbee_starspugs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mrs Bee&#39;s Gifts&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so we get to this week.  The week of the Dreaded SATs.  In an unfortunate piece of bad timing, Ross had to be in the US with work.  So it was up to me to steer the Lawley ship solo. The first time I’ve had to do it on my own for some time.  It’s Thursday, and we’ve done ok!  Everyone has got to where they need to be, on time, wearing the appropriate clothes.  All tummies have been filled with easy to cook meals, and I have only had to call in help once to get Felix to school on Wednesday morning.  I’m very tired, so anything that hasn’t been absolutely necessary, has not been done.  It can wait.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one sense it’s good that I have proven to myself that I am capable of doing things on my own, but it has also made me appreciate how much Ross does when he’s around, and how much I rely on him.  In general, he takes the kids to school, and will pick them up if I’m too tired.  I try and make all meals, but he will step in if it looks like dinner isn’t going to cook itself.  He’s back tomorrow, and it can’t come soon enough.  I’m looking forward to an epic nap!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imy has taken the SATs, so far, in her stride, and we’ll all be thankful when the last one is over and she can go back to being a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as always, we’ll just keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-sats-solo&quot;&gt;Singing, SATs and Flying Solo&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 11, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'll Do It My Way]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/my-way" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/my-way</id>
  <published>2017-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Like most people, I follow some newspapers on Facebook to keep up to date with the news.&lt;p&gt;Last week The Independent, re-shared a story about a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/91-year-old-inspired-thousands-skipping-chemotherapy-to-go-on-end-of-life-road-trip-dies-a7345951.html?cmpid=facebook-post&quot; target=&quot;new&quot;&gt;a 90 year old American lady, Ms Bauerschmidt, who was diagnosed with uterine cancer&lt;/a&gt; in the summer of 2015 and rather than go along with the standard treatment of surgery, radiotherapy and chemotherapy, she decided that she would, instead, go on the roadtrip of a lifetime.  After a year on the road, driving 13,000 miles, staying in over 75 locations in 32 states, she died in October 2016.  The article wasn’t a sad one, it was a happy one.  Ms Bauerschmidt’s motto was “Say ‘Yes’ to Living”, and she packed in so much that year.  It looked like she had a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading the heartwarming article, it got me thinking about my treatment and if saying “No” to it was an option.  (Spoiler Alert…it’s not.)  Ms Bauerschmidt was 90 when she was diagnosed with her primary cancer.  I was 36, and at the time, Imy and Felix were 5 and 7.  Ross and I had been married for less than 10 years.  So, I decided to comment on the post and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p width=&quot;50%&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/TheIndependentOnline/posts/10154620732761636&quot; target=&quot;new&quot;&gt;&quot;I think if I was 90 and told that I had Stage 4 Cancer ( there is no Stage 5, it&#39;s already spread outside the primary cancer site) I would do that. But I&#39;m not. I&#39;m 40, with two young children and I need more time.&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in Internet Land, we all know there be ‘Trolls’, I’m not completely naive, but I didn’t expect, what I thought to be an innocuous comment, would receive some of the attention it did.  But I learned the hard way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headline of the article was “91-year-old who inspired thousands by skipping chemotherapy to go on end of life road trip dies”.  It’s slightly misleading.  She didn’t refuse chemo alone,  she refused all treatment options.  So my response wasn’t just based on a refusal of chemo, it was all treatments: biological; hormonal; chemo; radio; surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t expect anyone to even look at the comment, never mind give me their opinion on it. The majority of the comments were positive, encouraging ones: “I wish you well with your treatment.”, “You’re in my prayers.”, “All the best.”, etc.  Thank you people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good.  And then this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IndyComment1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comment 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hold on… what?  Chemo gives you cancer?  I need to find out what “caused” my cancer and cut it out? Kill off the elderly?  Holy Moly! This was something else!! I have learned over the years I’ve been on Facebook that sometimes it’s not about retaliating, it’s about just leaving things alone.  Except, how can I leave it alone?  This person has just jumped to huge conclusions about me and my treatment and decided to tell me how I should be living my life.  Erm…no.  I think not.  I had to acknowledge the comment as it was so preposterous and I think I was rather restrained in my reply!
FYI, when she is talking about MIM, she is referring to a directory that medics can refer to when they are prescribing drugs.  As ‘Normal Folk’, we won’t have access to it, or generally know what it is, but this lady is “Educated” so she knows what she’s talking about. (Sit down at the back…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IndyComment2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comment 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My original comment has been like over 300 times.  Most people get where I’m coming from.  And yet, this person comes back again.  Really?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IndyComment3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crazy comment&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 48%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IndyComment4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crazy comment etc&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 48%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;

I know I&#39;m going back on what I said about not commenting further by writing this blog post, but I&#39;m still astounded that someone would say something like that.  Keyboard Warriors, Trolls, whatever you want to call them hide behind a keyboard, spew their bile and vitriol, tell other people how to live their lives and what?  Expect to be thanked for it?  &lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m so sorry that this woman&#39;s mother died from cancer.  It is an unforgiving and nondiscriminating disease.  But millions of pounds are being poured into research to find a cure.  There is no conspiracy.  The drugs companies are not hiding the cure.  They *are* researching cannabis (but it&#39;s not a silver bullet).  The management of these companies are as affected by cancer as anyone else.  They will have friends and/or family that are diagnosed with it.  They gain nothing by sitting by and watching people die.  Five to ten years ago, without Herceptin, my prognosis would have been bleak.  I may not even have been here to write this blog post.  Where did Herceptin come from?  A big drugs company that ran proper clinical trials, and now it is a standard treatment for certain cancers.  More trials are being run as I type, so that treatments and maybe a cure are found.  My role in *my* Cancer Story has not been that of a sheep.  I have grilled my Oncologist at length about the treatments I have had and currently having.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One in two people will receive a cancer diagnosis at some point in their life. But!  We have more screenings available, more treatments are available and as a result more people are surviving the diagnosis and go on to live full and healthy lives.  The statistics tell us that people are living longer, but everyone has to die at some point.  No one is immortal.  It&#39;s one of the two givens in life.  That and taxes. Life expectancy was &quot;three score years and ten&quot; or 70.  I&#39;m 30 years away from that age, and the odds of me getting there are slim.  But, I&#39;m here for the foreseeable.  The treatments are doing their job and we are more positive about things.  Long may the treatment continue to work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And as the Queen song goes, &quot;Who wants to live forever...when love must die?&quot;  
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Jx
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/my-way&quot;&gt;I'll Do It My Way&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 30, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turning 40]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/turning-40" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/turning-40</id>
  <published>2017-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I made it!!!&lt;p&gt;There’s the “Life begins at 40” Crew, and then there’s the “Forty is over the hill” Party.  I’m just delighted to have made it into another decade of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, I’ve had such a lovely birthday, and it hasn’t just been limited to one day.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the run up to the Big Day, we went up to the North East to visit my family.  My brother Max couldn’t join us as he’s a teacher in Manchester and our half term’s didn’t match up.  However, Grandma Julie organised the rest of the family so that we had a meal out complete with birthday cake and fizz with her and my Dad, my two other brothers, Callum and Regan, and their families.  It was a very nice evening, and I was spoilt with very lovely and generous gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also managed to meet up with Karen and Alison who I’ve known since we met at 6th Form College and did a fair amount of underaged drinking together.  With five kids between us now, we had a more sober celebration, but it was enjoyable nonetheless.  It’s funny how no matter how much time passes between the times we get together, it’s like we met last week.  It’s just nice to meet up and know we’ll have a laugh.  I left with a massive 40 balloon, a full stomach and sore cheeks from laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18th February 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days up there, we were back home so I could wake up in my own bed on my birthday itself.  Ross and the kids made me an amazing breakfast of American pancakes with fruit, maple syrup and cream.  Delicious.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was then presented with an huge pile of gifts.  I was absolutely stunned.  Ross had been squirreling away parcels and cards that had been arriving whilst I’d been in the house, none the wiser.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, friends dropped in for a cuppa and a slice of cake. It was a bit of an open house, so people could come and go, and so I didn’t feel so overwhelmed.  There was a steady stream of people and a lot of cake was consumed. This has lead Felix to tell people that he has had cake every day for a week.  That’s not a bad thing for an eight year old boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t help draw comparisons between this year and last year when I had to be signed out of the Hospice so that Ross and I could go out for an evening meal and I didn’t make it to dessert before I was asking to go back.  This year, we booked a taxi and went somewhere a bit special and had the most expensive meal we have ever had in our life together.  We splashed out on a bottle of Champagne.  It was magnificent!!  And I felt very lucky not only to be there enjoying it, but having Ross there with me to share it with me.  He’s been amazing and deserves it just as much as me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The days after were spent recovering as I’m still suffering from fatigue which means I have to plan when I can do things and when I need to take a nap and generally try not to overdo it.  I can mostly do what I want to, but it has to be planned with military precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the medical side of things, I have had my 4 weekly Zoladex injection and also had to catch up on Herceptin and Zometa treatments which had been delayed for a week so that I could go away at half term.&lt;br /&gt;
I have had a heart scan, which I have to have every 3 months to check the Herceptin isn’t damaging it, which can happen, but in my case it isn’t.  The cardiologist thinks that if I was going to have any heart damage, it would have happened by now, so I’m pleased about that.&lt;br /&gt;
My regular blood tests have showed that my platelets are a bit on the low side of normal, so I’m not clotting particularly well after I’m pricked with needles.  This has lead to a few bloody incidents, and also large bruises.  Fun fun fun!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Max came down for a flying visit, which was fantastic although it was too short.  I’m now looking forward to a few more events that we’ve got planned.  Everything, right now, is ok.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all,  I’m enjoying being 40.  So far, so good!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/fortycake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40th Birthday Cake&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 58%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cakeandballoon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;More 40th Birthday Cake&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 38%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/turning-40&quot;&gt;Turning 40&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 07, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Results Are In.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clear-scan" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clear-scan</id>
  <published>2017-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">My latest scan has revealed there is no new cancer activity anywhere in my body.&lt;p&gt;This is great news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I not on Cloud Nine?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why aren’t I celebrating?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why can’t I accept the good news and be happy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends and family are all offering good wishes and I am surrounded by love.  I am extremely lucky in more ways than one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be turning 40 next week, and doesn’t life begin there? I’ve got a few things lined up with friends and family to help me celebrate.  At one point I didn’t think I’d get to 40.  But here I am, 10 days to go, and the world should be my oyster. Except I don’t feel it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to get to the bottom of why I’m not feeling “Happy as Larry”.  (Whoever Larry is, I’d like to meet him and ask him his secret.)  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it comes down to the fact that I feel so fatigued still, and I can’t seem to get back to normal.  The doctors, who are involved in my medical wellbeing, are trying to find a reason for this fatigue are certain that it is not due to there being any cancer lurking anywhere. The scan proves this.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what else can it be?  What can it be that leaves me waking in the morning feeling like I need another 5 hours sleep?  That leaves me asleep in front of the tv after spending a 4 or 5 hours doing software development work?  That if I want to watch the kids partake in any event or fixture, I have to work out whether I can fit a nap in?  On Sunday’s, if I feel up to watching the bairns play rugby, I often have to choose which one I watch, because I can’t do both.  They both understand this, but I wish it wasn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should I have to plan my weeks, and my family’s activities, around my energy levels?  I feel like I’m cheating them out of their childhood.  The fun with me has to be rationed, or else it happens without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not asking for sympathy.  I’m not having a ‘Pity Party’, I just want to enjoy being cancer free, for as long I am.  I want to enjoy these times in between scans.  I want to give Ross and the kids a better version of me.  They deserve better than the current version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clear-scan&quot;&gt;The Results Are In.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 08, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Herceptin #18]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Herceptin-18" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Herceptin-18</id>
  <published>2017-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This is the magic number that usually hails the end of treatment.&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, on the 8th January 2015, I had my 18th and last dose of Herceptin.  Or so we thought.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
18 doses of Herceptin is the standard course for anyone who has Stage 2 or 3 breast cancer which is HER2+. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macmillan.org.uk/cancerinformation/cancertypes/breast/aboutbreastcancer/typesandrelatedconditions/her2%20positive.aspx&quot;&gt;There’s more info on HER2+ breast cancer here.&lt;/a&gt; 1 in 4 breast cancer diagnosis are HER2+.  It’s not a nice type of cancer.  It likes to travel and it spreads quickly.  Herceptin was regarded as a wonder drug when it was first developed.  As it targets a specific cell type, it isn’t as brutal as traditional chemo.  It still has side effects though, and I find it fatigues me.  Two years ago, as we drew to the end of the course of treatment, we were counting down, “3 to go”, “2 to go”, “1 to go”, “We’re done!!”.  Yippee!!!  Get out the banners and balloons! We’re done!!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today, I had Herceptin no.18, only this time we are not counting down, we are counting up.  I want to have as many doses of them as possible, as that means that it’s keeping the cancer under control and stopping any new tumours from growing.  And crucially, we can maintain some sort of semblance of normal family life.  Herceptin is the least brutal of the treatments that are on the table for me now.  Long may this treatment regime continue.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/herceptin18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Herceptin 18&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the 3 monthly scan next week which will tell us if the treatment is working.  Fingers crossed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Update…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I find Timehop does one of two thing:  Pops up with boring statuses about the weather, the kids annoying me or something, or, alternatively, it comes up with something relevant.  Today it popped up with a couple of photos I took on the day of my (second) first Herceptin last year.  I looked awful!  And the port had only just been put in surgically, so it was still healing hence the extra plasters.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/oneyearon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;One Year On&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 49%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/newportacath.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Portacath&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 49%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;

I&#39;m not sure which photo I look better in, this years or last years...
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Herceptin-18&quot;&gt;Herceptin #18&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 25, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memories - with Voices]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/memories" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/memories</id>
  <published>2017-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">As a family, we have an uncertain future.&lt;p&gt;We live our lives in 3 month periods.  There’s an MRI at the beginning, followed by an appointment with the Oncologist, if it’s not good, we deal with it, if it is, we wait until the next scan.  So in these 3 month periods of calm, (and long may they continue), the idea is that we set up as many fun and interesting experiences for the family, and me as an individual or with friends, as we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current chunk of ‘Well Time’ included Christmas and visits from Grandad Mike and Grandma Julie and Uncle Max, a New Year’s Eve party, and a New Year’s Day party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took the opportunity to get the stairs and Felix’s room decorated, and then a new carpet put down on the stairs.  Things we’ve had in mind for ages, but haven’t got round to.  Now they are done, and we only have Ross’s study left to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw The Son’s of Pitches in St. Albans, we went to see Star Wars: Rogue One, and also to the panto, Peter Pan, at the Gordon Craig in Stevenage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imy is in her school choir, and they performed in a few Christmas concerts in churches in Stevenage and Baldock, but the highlight for Imy and the choir was singing at The O2.  You heard me right, The O2!  The arena which has seen Rihanna, Prince, Bon Jovi, Plácido Doming, Beyoncé, One Direction, Monty Python, The Spice Girls, 2012 Olympic Artistic Gymnastics, and Olympic and Paralympic Basketball finals, AND… Hartsfield JMI as part of the Young Voices Choir.  Amazing!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young Voices is a big organisation which signs up loads of schools, gets them to learn the same songs, have a rehearsal in the afternoon, and then perform to a packed arena audience in the evening.  There were nearly eight thousand children in the choir, and they perform on the night with a band, and special guests including Natalie Williams, who is well known on the live music circuit, The Beat Box Collective, and a very funky street dance crew.  But the real stars, the kids, were amazing.  We had such a great time.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/youngvoices02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Young Voices at The O2&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 58%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/youngvoiceimy02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Young Voices - Imy&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 38%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The programme and the ticket will be put in our Family Memory Box, because that&#39;s one heck of a memory for us all, not least for our songbird, Imy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We are drawing to the end of our current three month period which means the anxiety of the impending scan is increasing.  However, we are still planning on making as many memories as a family as we can, and have a few already in the diary for 2017.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/memories&quot;&gt;Memories - with Voices&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 20, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>