<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2013-10-25T14:57:18+01:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The next day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/articles/the-next-day" />
  <id>/articles/the-next-day</id>
  <published>2013-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today has passed in a bit of a blur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 4am, and got up an hour later to send some work emails and put something live.  Funny what you think is important…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d inadvertently woken Ross up so we chatted eventually falling asleep not long before the children woke up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got them into bed with us, and read them a book called Mummy’s Lump.  It was a very high level book which discussed a bad lump, cutting it out, and strong medicine which would make my hair fall out.  They asked some questions, felt Big Lump, and what the operation would mean.  We told them my boob would be cut off.  Imogen was a bit upset, but Felix didn’t really understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this made us a bit late for school. Not by much but Felix wasn’t impressed.  We went to see Mrs Summerhayes as she would be able to ensure that things were put in place to ensure Imogen and Felix were given additional support as and when required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day has involved a trip to the doctors to get things signed, a trip to the supermarket, a walk round Radwell Meadows, an awkward conversation with my mother, ( who’s immediate reaction was to light a cigarette),  a light lunch, and a nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also told the Gin Club.  As expected the offers of help were overwhelming and also humbling.  They are a great group of friends, and were lucky to have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some beautiful flowers arrive from Dad and Julie with a card saying they were thinking if us. A conversation with my Dad followed, which was less emotionally fraught than yesterday’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross is flying solo at parents evening.  I can’t face it to be honest.  First parents evening I’ve missed.  But it needs to be focused on the kids.  I’m too much of a zombie and too leaky to make myself anything other than a nuisance right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross has been great and continues to be my rock, and to help me use our sense of humour to get us through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/the-next-day&quot;&gt;The next day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 24, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The day after]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/articles/the-day-after" />
  <id>/articles/the-day-after</id>
  <published>2013-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Julia is downstairs putting some code live, she can’t sleep and said she’d do it
yesterday when the world was normal.  If you can’t sleep its good to focus on
something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We told the kids before school, both Julia and I choked back tears when reading
“Mummy’s Lump” - a book about breast cancer given to us yesterday.  How did it
come to this?  I found it achingly difficult, so we went over it again.  We told
Imogen &amp;amp; Felix to make sure they don’t bottle it up. Imogen seems to understand but
Felix is a different matter, he wanted to know more about the lump and wanted to
feel it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took the kids in late to school and spoke to the head mistress.  She was great
and understanding of the situation.  The kids will get a card to hold up if they
ever need time out.  No questions will be asked they can go and sit with the head
mistress and chill.  This is an enormous comfort and its good to know the kids are
in safe hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call my mum up again are a text from dad, saying he’s thinking of us and
struggling to get his head round the news.  Its good talking to mum, she’s still
in shock but is being pragmatic and asking questions about the treatment. This time
I cry as I express my fears.  The biggest being I’m worried I won’t live up to
expectations and be strong enough for Julia.  Today has been a really leaky day
for my eyes!  And emotions are still so strong and raw - it’s a lot to take in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I email the gin club dads telling them about the news and
that I will need help, support, beers and sometimes to escape the insanity of the
family in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia has a nap and I head off to parents evening. Its good to focus on the kids
and they are both doing well.  Imogen is having her normal first half term of the
year issues - some alpha positioning thing with the teacher and class mates.  The
teacher loves her passion and there are a few things to work on but on the whole
shes settling in this year great.  I think the teacher was shocked when Imogen did
a “My Mums got Breast Cancer” talk for show and tell!  &lt;em&gt;Well we did say don’t
bottle it in!&lt;/em&gt;  Felix’s review was &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt;, he’s such a
lovely boy and the teachers are really impressed with him and his progress.
Julia and I are lucky to have such fantastic kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, I start to feel more lucid and actually myself.  Julia and I
chill watching rot on the TV and it feels closer to normal.  All our close
friends and family know and I plan on setting up a blog tomorrow to help get these
feelings out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rx&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/the-day-after&quot;&gt;The day after&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 24, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The longest day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/articles/the-longest-day" />
  <id>/articles/the-longest-day</id>
  <published>2013-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Julia immediately noticed we were seeing Mr rather than Dr and commented to the nurse, who gave a non committal reply. One quick examination then into a room with with two nurses and the consultant (this can’t be good news). It’s cancer and my fears of the last two weeks and last few months have been realised.  We are told quickly and honestly that it will involve operations, chemo and a mastectomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m holding Julia’s hand and notice it’s shaking, I squeeze tight. Desperately listening, trying to ensure I take it all in, but the news is too big to fit my head and to comprehend fully. After, we are taken to a quiet room and given a moment. We hug and cry, it’s shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurse comes in, Julia says its a bit shit, the nurse replies almost whispering its crap. We get the information again and can, this time digest it more.  We are given a library of books on cancer, I joke to Julia “you don’t have time to be ill as she has so much reading todo”. It’s not funny, but we’ll need our sense of humour in the coming months, so best start dusting it off now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We leave, I cry in the car, I’m so angry, upset and worried. I’m a man and it’s hard having a months / years worth of feelings in 5 minutes. Crying, as always makes me feel better, but I feel bad doing it in front of Julia as if I’m off loading onto her - she has one job now and that’s to get better and needs me to be strong.  I’m fully realising I need to create and use a support network to ensure I can get these feelings out and stay strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving home Julia starts phoning and telling her family.  I’m amazed by her strength on those calls - I’m still digesting the news and the content of the calls feels surreal. We get the kids, I drop them all off at home and head to the supermarket for cancer drugs and beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call Rich, he’s stunned and I seem to be broken with emotion. I can’t get my words out and repeatedly choke back tears. Richie is ace, says the right things.  He says Julia is a tough Geordie and we will get through this.  I think the nicest thing he says is that Julia and I “are love” as if we help define the word, I like the description. He offers to help out anyway he can and if we ever need him he’s only a couple of hours away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back home beers in hand. Felix reads a story to me, his reading is coming on and he’s starting to take pride in reading (when he’s not randomly guessing every other word). I phone my mum. It’s a hard call, she wasn’t expecting the news and is stunned. I somehow manage not to boo during this call, she asks lots of questions but I can tell she is stunned, quiet and I leave her crying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen senses things aren’t right, she’s been downstairs three times after bedtime.  The third time she’s been told to get back to bed. Weirdly, she picks now to start crying and talk about her own world ended and dying. Not sure where that came from but it seems school and Boudicca are to blame ?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drink beers, watch telly and discuss what’s happening and the future. It’s a lot to handle but the journey has started and we know where we need to get to.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/the-longest-day&quot;&gt;The longest day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 23, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Results day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/articles/results-day" />
  <id>/articles/results-day</id>
  <published>2013-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to be working today. And I did, to an extent. But I was very distracted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross and I got to the hospital 15 minutes early and got in to see the doctor at just after 5.  I saw the main man.  That made me worry.  And justifiably so as it turns out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have breast cancer.  I have it in more than one place.  The saving grace is that it’s only in one of my boobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is not the news I wanted.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in the next couple of weeks I need a CT scan to see if its spread anywhere else. I’ll see the consultant in two weeks to discuss the results and that dictates the big decisions.  I also need a small operation to see if there’s any cancer in the lymph nodes.  That’s on the 14th November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that its chemotherapy and a mastectomy.  I lose a boob and my hair.  I also have a course of herceptin, similar to chemo but more expensive and less side effects.  I started on tamoxifen today also which is supposed to stop the cancer in its tracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve told Dad, Julie, Callum, Regan and Max.  I’ve made them promise hugs.  A couple of close friends also know as they’ve been helping me through the wait for results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next task is to tell the bairns.  This isn’t going to be pleasant.  But Ross and I have a plan and we are going to do it together.  Once the kids know, it’ll become public knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so angry right now.  And being quite petulant with the “why me!” Attitude.  And tearful.  Meh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we are where we are.  There’s a journey to go on.  There’s a few way points, but we don’t know the route yet.  It’s going to be tough, but the troops have been mobilised and its going to be ok.  I’ve got a Race For Life to do in July, and I will do it.  Even if I have to walk…and I’ve never walked one!
Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/results-day&quot;&gt;Results day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 23, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mummy day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/articles/mummy-day" />
  <id>/articles/mummy-day</id>
  <published>2013-10-17T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been keeping busy at work which has meant I haven’t really had time to dwell to much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a bit of a problem when it comes to setting up new Life Insurance though.  We meant to get it sorted once we moved into the new house to cover the new mortgage, but because we’ve already some cover, and Ross has Death in Service cover, it wasn’t a top priority.  I’m now regretting that decision.  If anything happens to me, the majority of the mortgage will be paid off, but it will still mean that Ross has to work to cover the remaining mortgage.  That on top of child care costs isn’t going to be easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we know one way or the other we’ll be getting it sorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I keep getting cross about is why the scan in June didn’t pick up that the Big Lump wasn’t normal.  I need to stop dwelling on it, but I kept going back to the doctor and I feel like I’ve been fobbed off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we’re just waiting to see what next Wednesday brings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/mummy-day&quot;&gt;Mummy day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 17, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feeling more positive]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/articles/feeling-positive" />
  <id>/articles/feeling-positive</id>
  <published>2013-10-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We firstly took Merlin to the vets to get his first lot of jabs.  The vet was happy  he was a sociable cat, and gave plenty of advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was off to Little Ruggers and ballet.  A quick razz around Sainsburys and it was back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch was followed by the ironing, then sorting the under stairs cupboard and then a sit on the sofa watching Bondi Vet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to get a bit low during that, so after seeing some pictures, made our sloe gin and blackberry vodka.  Imogen and Felix helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dinner came soon after and them we watched Strictly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merlins been a bit lethargic today, but that’s down to the jabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross has managed to alter his schedule and he’s coming home tonight instead of Monday.  This makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/feeling-positive&quot;&gt;Feeling more positive&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 12, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A long wait]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/articles/a-long-wait" />
  <id>/articles/a-long-wait</id>
  <published>2013-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been 48 hours since I was at the QEII in Welwyn having a mammogram, scan and biopsy that will tell me what the increasing number of lumps in my left breast are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big lump has been around since the beginning if May. I did what I needed to and went to the GP straight away.  She didn’t seem worried and told me it was probably hormonal changes.  I wasn’t convinced, so told her I wanted to come back for her to have another look.  Again, she told me not to worry, but would refer me if I was worried.  Worried?  Of course I was worried!  I’ve breast fed both my kids for over a year each, and watched my boobs go through all sorted of weird changes.  This wasn’t normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got an appointment at the local breast unit for a scan at the beginning if June.  I was seen by the doctor, and then scanned.  I was quite sure that the area of my breast where the lump was, wasn’t scanned, but, I’m not the expert, so didn’t really push the point when I was told it was normal breast tissue.  The doctor said he would send me another appointment in 3 months so that we could discuss options.  Possibly an operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three months went by, the big lump got bigger and two more lumps developed.  The doctor scanned Big lump again and found fluid which either previously wasn’t there, or missed.  She decided I should have more scans as well as a biopsy, as if Big Lump was a cyst, it would be possible to drain it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that brings us to Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never had a mammogram before, and most women don’t until the screening programme kicks in at 50, it’s an uncomfortable experience with your boob manhandled into position by a radiographer and then squashed between two plates.  Not very pleasant, but no big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, then on to the ultrasound.  The radiologist had looked at my mammograms and decided there was an area he wanted to look at in more detail as well as Big Lump.  So he scanned very thoroughly, including areas that I hadn’t been previously worried about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the biopsy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t expected to sign a consent form, or to have local anaesthetic.  After seeing the size of the biopsy needle, and the fact they had to use a scalpel to break the skin to get it in, I realise why they were necessary.  They took 3-4 specimens from two different areas of my boob.  Given that Big Lump is still with us, I can only assume it wasn’t possible to drain it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they had finished and they had cleaned me up, I was told that the radiologist had found some calcium which can be an indicator of cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I first found this lump, the medical professionals have been telling me that Big Lump isn’t cancer and I shouldn’t be worried.  But I’ve now got multiple lumps, discharge and to top it off, Calcification.  Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I’ve been googling, and scaring myself.  But I’ve got to wait until the 23rd for the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is going to be a long two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross is away, but has cut his trip short so he’ll be back late tomorrow night.  He’s also cancelled his trip which was scheduled for when I get the results.  He is my rock.  Keeps me from going mental and is always pragmatic.  I realise this isn’t easy for him, but I just need him to be strong for us both for a little while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen has seen the plasters covering the biopsy wounds and asked about them.  I didn’t know what to say, so fobbed her off.  She asked again yesterday, so I told her that I’d had some tests as I had something in my booby that shouldn’t be there and the doctors needed to find out what it was.  She seemed happy with the explanation.   I haven’t mentioned the C word.  She knows what it is, as Grandad has had cancer.  We ran the Race For Life in July and I thought it important to explain why it was important to raise money for cancer research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix knows something is up but doesn’t really understand.  He’s been around Imogen when we’ve discussed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are.  In a strange limbo of trying to prepare for an unknown outcome.  I don’t know what it might be, but I have to prepare myself that I may be told I have breast cancer.  I’m hoping its not.  I really am.  Because that would suck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then if its not, what on earth is causing these lumps? And the discharge and the calcium?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if its not, then it’s two weeks of worrying for no reason.  And why I don’t want to tell the world,  “I’m waiting for results that will tell me if I have cancer or not.”  “Nope, I don’t…as you were”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, hoping for the best, preparing for the worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might drink some wine tonight.  And play with Merlin, our new kitten, who we got on the way home from the hospital on Wednesday.  He’s lovely.  The other two cats aren’t too impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/a-long-wait&quot;&gt;A long wait&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 11, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>