<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2016-03-04T16:21:59+00:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Garden House Hospice]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hospice" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hospice</id>
  <published>2016-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The word &#39;Hospice&#39; isn&#39;t really very user friendly.&lt;p&gt;Not for me anyway.  A Hospice is where people go to die.  So, when it was suggested to me by my Oncologist that I stay in a hospice, to say I wasn’t keen was an understatement!  However, my pain levels weren’t being managed and I needed something to happen to get back on track.  I had a conversation with Big Brother Callum on Wednesday, and I suggested that if the Hospice was called something else, I might be able to handle it a bit better.  So we coined the phrase ‘Igloo’.  You can leave an Igloo.  That’s fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is where Letchworth’s Garden House Hospice came in.  A small hospice, five minutes from my own home.  On the Thursday afternoon, I was admitted into my own little room, with a view of a lovely, cared for garden.  I met the nurses and a Doctor, and told them in no uncertain terms that I wouldn’t be staying for very long, maybe a day or two, and then I would be going home with my family.  Max was coming to see me on Saturday, and who would want to spend a day visiting someone in a Hospice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The staff nodded in agreement, went through my drugs list and I made myself comfortable.  The next day, Fiona and Michelle came to visit me in The Igloo.  Spirit’s were raised and I started to feel calmer about things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, Max assured me that he was fine to visit me in the Igloo, so when he arrived, complete with souvenir mug from Cats the Musical, I was really pleased. He’d had a late night the night before, and an early start that morning to be be able to get the train to visit me from Manchester, so at one point, the nurses came in to find him asleep on the armchair in my room, and me asleep in my bed.  They just left us to it.  They were great like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few days my opinion of the Igloo/Hospice changed substantially.  I hadn’t realised what other services they offer there.  We had support workers come in to us and offer counselling, not only to me, but to Ross and the kids.  They were given activity packs to keep them occupied as well as comfort quilts which were to be used as something that they would associate with a “safe place”.  There was a lounge next to my room so they didn’t have to spend all their time there looking at me feeling all sorry for myself.  Another massive thing that I hadn’t realised was that I wasn’t tied to the hospice.  I could come and go, as and when I wanted, as long as I was back in time for my medication.  This meant I was able to go to Rachel and Greg’s to watch the 6 Nation rugby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also able to greet Dad and Grandma Julie when they arrived at ours.  I had a little cry, and was taken back to what I had come to regard as my little oasis of calm, The Igloo.  As this was half term, we had planned on the kids going to stay up in the North East for a few days.  However, we decided that it would be best if Grandma and Grandad stayed at ours so the kids were able to visit me when they wanted, and they’d have some days out around me.  And crucially, get to see me on my birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had plenty of visitors to the Igloo, as well as support from the staff.  I was still adamant that I was going to be home for my birthday, but I after a week in the Igloo, I was still there, relinquishing control of things to the staff slowly but surely and starting to realise that BIG STUFF was happening and I couldn’t deal with it all on my own.  If I was still in the Igloo for my birthday, it didn’t matter.  I was, after all, Just Visiting, and Big Brother Callum made me a sign to make sure that I remembered that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/justvisiting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Just Visiting&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hospice&quot;&gt;Garden House Hospice&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 17, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberknife]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/cyberknife" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/cyberknife</id>
  <published>2016-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It sounds all very grand and space aged doesn&#39;t it?&lt;p&gt;Super high tech stuff which will hopefully help alleviate some of my pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning it was up and out to Mount Vernon Cancer Centre for the first of three Cyberknife treatments. The bairns were safely deposited at Fiona’s so she could take them to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traffic at that time in the morning on the A1 and M25 is horrid, and people are idiots. Luckily Ross did a super job of getting us there safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once there,  we had a quick chat with Dr Shah, my Oncologist, who told us that it could be 3-4 weeks before the pain in my back started to subside, and he was mindful that my painkiller meds aren’t quite doing the job.  He was going to speak to the Palliative nurse, Julia, who I’d seen on Monday,  with the intention of having a plan of action in place to best deal with my pain, by the time I’d finished the last treatment on Thursday.  All I want to be able to do is walk the kids to school in the morning.  Make their tea again.  Start to become a more useful member of Team Lawley!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyberknifebed1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyberknife Cradle&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have a great night’s sleep, so lying still, on a vacuum packed beanbag looking up at an artificial blue sky listening to music for an hour, whilst the scanner and robot do their stuff was quite appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyberknifeready.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyberknife Ready&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment didn’t hurt.  The robotic machine just moved around me and whirred, firing beams of radiation at me.  Nothing scary, nothing nasty, it just killed off bad cancer cells accurately.  All whilst I snoozed and listened to some music.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday was the same.  Kids dropped off at Caroline’s, and I had the second of the third treatments.  All calm, all fine.  Nothing of any concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as is standard, we Keep on, Keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/cyberknife&quot;&gt;Cyberknife&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 10, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charities]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/charities" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/charities</id>
  <published>2016-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Macmillan Support&lt;p&gt;My GP had referred me on to the Community Palliative Care Specialists in order that we could tap into the information and services they have available to them.  Being under a Palliative Care team feels like a double edge sword.  On one side it’s great, they can give me pointers in what we need to do in terms of getting me out and about more by applying for a Blue Badge and also the short term hire of a wheelchair.  The other side to the sword is that whichever way I look at it, I have a Terminal Illness, Stage 4 cancer, and there is nothing anyone can do for that.  All we can do is manage the Cancer.  I will never be free from it, and I will always be living under the shadow or it.  (Even at this point now, I’m still waiting for someone to tell me there’s been a terrible mistake, and it’s a slipped disk.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say that, Julia, the Palliative Care nurse was brilliant.  She was empathetic, and a great listener.  She gave us a hope that the pain I’m in will be short-term but the Cyberknife treatment can take 3-4 weeks to actually work.  She reviewed my current medication list, made some minor adjustments and gave us another prescription.  As I say, she’s a very knowledgeable person, another good one to have on my side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing she said to me was, and the thing I came away feeling most positive about was when she said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“You are living with Cancer, not dying from Cancer”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;race-for-life&quot;&gt;Race for Life&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Race For Life has been an event that I have enjoyed participating in for  years now.  I’ve done it 8 or 9 times, including last years Pretty Muddy spectacular.  It’s got a great atmosphere and people are very generous with their donations, it’s a good cause after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past two Race’s have happened around the time of Ross’s birthday, and have rather eclipsed it somewhat.  We had thought that this year we would miss the Race, or do a different one and concentrate on Ross and his birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we told Imy and Felix that my Cancer had come back, Imy immediately asked if she could do the Race again.  Felix was in agreement, and Ross selflessly agreed with the kids that doing the Race was an important, positive thing for them to do. I don’t know what state I’ll be in in July, I many be fully mobile, I may be in a wheelchair, I don’t know, so I said I’d make a call nearer the time.  Luckily,  members of The Gin Club had already signed up for the Race and Imy and Felix joined their team, and then they helped set up their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/ImyAndFelix/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Just Giving Page&lt;/a&gt;  If you feel inclined to sponsor them, please follow the link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/charities&quot;&gt;Charities&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 09, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gin of Human Kindness]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-kindness" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-kindness</id>
  <published>2016-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s my birthday next week. I&#39;ll be 39.&lt;p&gt;Back in November, when things were on an even keel, I had organised for myself and a small group of friends to go to a Gin Festival in London to celebrate my birthday as a treat for us all.  I don’t usually celebrate my birthdays in big ways.  They are usually sedate affairs involving Ross and the bairns and Tesco Club Card vouchers.  Organising an afternoon do in London felt quite an extravagance!  I hardly ever go into London these days, I spent years commuting from North Hertfordshire to the office on Regent Street, and if I’m honest, I don’t miss the Big Smoke too much.  I like living in our little country town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I found out that I’d gotten a bit poorly again, I had assumed that my friends would just go to the festival without me.  My friends like gin!  We’re not called the Gin Club for nothing!  But then I was being told that plans needed to change, the afternoon was not going to happen without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I’m not fit for much at the minute, in quite a lot of pain, and can’t walk very far, I decided that I’d like to have a few close friends round for a sophisticated afternoon tea, for a chat, and to help me deal with my new tea and cream scone obsession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then something strange happened.  I follow blog via Facebook called &lt;a href=&quot;http://hurrahforgin.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hurrah For Gin&lt;/a&gt;.  A Mum, called Katie,  who tells it how it is in her struggles with motherhood supported by gin.  She’s hilarious and strikes a chord with me.  Read her blog, buy Gin Bunny art.  She’s funny.  I think we’d get on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other night, I noticed Katie was running a competition to win a bottle of gin.  She was after a a funny story to give everyone a giggle. I decided to enter, thinking it would have been nice to give my friends who were missing out on the Gin Festival a cheeky tipple of gin during our afternoon tea.  My story wasn’t funny, it was quite maudlin, but it attracted a lot of attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t win the competition for said bottle of gin. Katie was after a funny story, not my doom and gloom one, and the lady who won it, definitely deserved it a whole lot more than me.  I can’t mix my medication with alcohol, so at least she’ll be able to drink it and enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it didn’t stop there.  It’s fair to say, things went a bit mental!  My original comment had been that my breast cancer had spread to my bones and was no longer curable and that I’d like to win the bottle of gin to thank my friends for being there for me during such a difficult time.  There were lots of nice comments and ‘likes’.  Facebook is good for things like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My comment was still getting a lot of attention, and Katie had shared it on her page.  By Sunday morning, I had to enlist the help of my good friend Fiona to liaise with various different people and companies who wanted to donate things to my Afternoon Birthday Tea and Gin Treat.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been totally overwhelmed by the warmth and generosity of strangers.  Little me, turning 39 next week, with a husband, two kids, 3 cats, a penchant for gin, wit and sarcasm, but now with the support of the wider Gin Community helping me thank those that are closest to me for making this whole shitty journey a bit more manageable.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cancer, you really do suck.  But you will not suck the joy out of my life.  Not a chance.  Not when there are people like Katie from Hurrah for Gin, and Fiona, and the rest of my support group who will drop everything to help me out if I need anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Facebook alerts have gone mad, but it’s in a good way, and it’s taking my mind off the pain and the cancer, and it feels wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who has taken time to keep the light shining.  You have no idea how overwhelmed, humbled and grateful I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-kindness&quot;&gt;Gin of Human Kindness&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brothers (Definitely not Grimm)]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/brothers-not-grimm" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/brothers-not-grimm</id>
  <published>2016-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I have three brothers, Callum is a year and a half older than me, Regan is 5 years younger, and Max is 14 years younger.&lt;p&gt;I think it’s fair to say that over the past 15 years, my brothers and I have drifted apart, and we are not as close as we once were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed a happy, if slightly unusual childhood, we all got on and all turned into reasonably well adjusted human beings.  But things change, I moved to London, and we don’t see each other as often as we want.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brothers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Brothers and Me&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This photo was taken when Regan married Lorna a few years ago.  It was a great day of laughing, celebrating and general silliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then something big happens.  Like getting told you have Cancer.  The first time round, in October 2013, everyone thought that it was just a lump (no pun intended) in the road.  A small hiccup.  Pick yourself up, dust yourself down, crack back on.   Nothing to worry about.  Modern medicine is great.  That’s what was supposed to happen. The statistics are on my side. We had all the time in the world to see each other.  During one of our visits, I was chatting to Callum asking what he was planning for his 40th birthday. I’d joked that I’d just like to be alive on my 40th.  I didn’t actually mean it, I thought I would be around for decades.  These things happen to “other people”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last week, unbeknownst to me, Ross had been in cahoots with Callum and Regan, and at 10am on Friday morning after driving for over 200 miles, they arrived on my doorstep.  They had come for the day to see me, because now it’s important.  Now we don’t have the luxury of time on our hands.  They were armed with meals, care packages, and stuff for the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chatted about this and that for a little while and then got on to the Big Stuff.  Callum had a look at my MRI images, trying to see what the doctors had decided was suspicious, he may have been able to see something, but it gave him something solid to focus on.   It was so hard telling them that this disease, that was supposed to be a minor glitch, was going to get the better of me, and there was nothing I could do about it.  That was tough.  Very tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you do after that?  Well you go to the pub next door, get sausage baguettes, get a hug off the land lord, and laugh about what we got up to as kids.  Remind ourselves that we had years of shared, happy, history, that needs to be passed on to our kids.  My kids might live ‘Down South’ but they still needs to have connections to their cousins ‘Up North’.  Callum and Regan need to make sure that this happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short while later, the school run is done and Imy and Felix are excited to see their Uncles and it’s not long before Top Trumps is being played, sweets are being eaten and the cheekiness starts.  At this point, I start to snooze, but as everything seems to be under control, there is no issue and Callum tells me to carry on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before long, it’s time for them to say goodbye, so more hugs, and we wave them off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was great to see them.  We talked more on that day than we had in years.  It was good, I enjoyed it.  I do love my brothers, I need them to know that.  I’ll be looking forward to squeezing Max when I see him next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully once we’ve got some of the pain under control, I’ll be able to go on a visit to see them.  Create some more shared, happy memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/brothers-not-grimm&quot;&gt;Brothers (Definitely not Grimm)&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 05, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[World Cancer Day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/world-cancer-day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/world-cancer-day</id>
  <published>2016-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today is World Cancer Day.&lt;p&gt;And what better way to spend it than at The Mount Vernon Cancer Centre, the East and North Hertfordshire NHS Trust specialised cancer centre.  It takes ages to get there, and as I’m not sleeping well at night, I use the opportunity to catch up on some zzzzz’s.  I feel bad about this as Ross is also sleeping badly, but he’s the one who can drive so he gets the short straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we’ve registered for our appointment, and filled in the relevant paperwork we wait to see the consultant to discuss the next phase of treatment.  Except today we don’t see my consultant.  We see someone else.  This isn’t a problem at all, he’s an expert in Cyberknife.  He knows what he’s talking about and answers our questions thoroughly.  He talks more to Ross than me, as I appear to be on another planet, and I’m not really taking things in.  This is why having Ross with me at these appointments is so important.  Goodness knows what I’d bring out from the meetings…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cyberknife technology is extremely accurate.  They are only interested in frying the bad cells.  We get shown where the treatment is going to be done, what the machine looks like, and it’s explained that during the sessions, a CT scanner will be constantly used, and the rays adjusted to ensure maximum damage to the cancer, minimal damage to me and my important nerves.  Each treatment will last about an hour, there will be one session a day and I will have 3 sessions.  My first session is in Tuesday, 9th February, and I will be finished on Thursday 11th.  I’m grateful that these sessions only take days, not weeks, like the radiotherapy for breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyberkniferoom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyberknife Room&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/world-cancer-day&quot;&gt;World Cancer Day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 04, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quirky Hospital]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/quirky-hospitals" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/quirky-hospitals</id>
  <published>2016-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Tuesday morning starts at 3am.&lt;p&gt;Ross and I wake early and chat about what is to happen today.  I’m booked into the Royal National Orthopaedic Hospital in Stanmore, North London in order that they can give me a bone biopsy of the naughty vertebrae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was due to be there for 7am, so at 6am we were on our way down the A1.  That road at that time is horrible.  There are idiots around at that time.  It is very dark, and everyone seems to need to be very close to the car in front.  Talk about making a stressful situation more stressful than in needs to be!  I’m so glad I don’t have to do that journey often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross dropped me off at the main doors, and went off to find a parking space. This hospital is very quirky.  All corridors seem to be off a very sloped corridor.  It’s just odd.  Also, because of the nature of the hospital, everyone has mobility problems, which means everyone thinks they have priority over everyone else.  This makes for some hilarious stand offs.  Who goes first?  The patient in the bed, the one in the wheelchair, the one on crutches or the one with one leg.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten minutes later, we were on the ward which I had been instructed to go to only to be told that there was no record of me on their list for that day.  More letters were produced, I turned my humour up a notch (it was either that or cry), and the relevant information was found and I was taken to another ward where my name was on the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had thought that the bone biopsy was to be done under local anaesthetic and that we would be out of the hospital quite quickly.  As it turns out, after a discussion with a very nice Anaesthetist, it is revealed that it was all to be done under a General. This means they have to go through my medical history and current medication list. This takes some time, but it gives me a chance to explain that I don’t tolerate GA’s very well and this gives her enough information to make sure that she gives me plenty anti-sickness drugs.  Once all this is done, the porter is ready to take me down to the imaging unit.  The biopsy that they are doing is being done using a CT scanner so they can have maximum accuracy when taking samples out with needles.  No one really wants to guess when you are dealing with the spine and nerves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross accompanies me down to the imaging unit, helps me change into a gown, and after a chat with the doctor who is doing the procedure, it’s not long before he’s despatched back to our ward and I’m in lying down having cannula’s inserted and the drugs are administered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What feels like five seconds later, I’m awake and before long I’m back on the ward with Ross.  I’m anxious to get my painkillers back on the go, and thanks to a wonderful nurse, we are given the permissions we need and I’m feeling more at ease with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey home happens in a whirl.  Helen, one of the wonderful ladies I met online through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breastcancercare.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Breast Cancer Care &lt;/a&gt; November Newbie 2013 support forums, organised for a charity &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/blanketssentwithlove/&quot;&gt;Sent With Love&lt;/a&gt; to send me a beautiful handmade blanket.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sent-with-love.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comfort Blanket&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blanket is the perfect size for me to take with me to hospital, to remind me of home.  The children had been given instructions to have the blanket around them whenever they can so they can get their smell on it.  (The nice after bath, clean smells, not the slightly cabbagy school smell).  This blanket is rolled up and used as a pillow and before long, Ross has got me home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so tired, Dad gives me my tea early, and off I go to bed.  The drugs alarms are all set, so I don’t have to worry about forgetting anything and that’s that.  Night night.  Off to sleep and a new day tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/quirky-hospitals&quot;&gt;Quirky Hospital&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 03, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monday was a good day.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/quiet-days" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/quiet-days</id>
  <published>2016-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Monday was a Greek Day!&lt;p&gt;Imy’s school year were taking part in an Ancient Greek Day, so she had to go in dressed in appropriate clothing.  We spent an hour on Sunday evening curling her hair with the stylers she received for Christmas and then she slept with her hair in a turban in order to keep it looking in tip top condition.  On Monday morning, the rest of the costume was assembled which included a fleece blanket (it’s February, it’s cold, I don’t want her to wear a white sheet),  tied in place with safety pins, broaches, cords and scarves.  She’s delighted and skips off to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/greek-imy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ancient Greek Imy&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day is relatively quiet, and quiet days are good.  Michelle came round to drink tea from china cups, which was lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to be getting a visit from the community Macmillan nurses, but due to illness and cover issues, it’s had to be rearranged.  We’ll meet them eventually and we’ll be able to see what services we can tap into, and utilize.  I’m keen to get some sort of support in place for Imy and Felix as they have a lot of things that they need to process and I am aware that I’m not the best person to be able to help them to do it.  There are experts out there,  (which in itself is something that is hard to comprehend), and if that helps my bairns try and process the situation that we are in, then all the better.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/quiet-days&quot;&gt;Monday was a good day.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 01, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relinquishing Control]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Relinquishing-Control" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Relinquishing-Control</id>
  <published>2016-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I have my own ways of doing things.  &lt;p&gt;Whether that be the order the laundry goes on, where the beans are kept in the cupboard, what to buy for the Bairn’s friends birthday presents etc, or which is the best toothpaste, meal planning.  I decide.  It’s all worked well.  Everyone knows what to expect as “if Mamma’s happy, everybody’s happy”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I’m having to give up on that control bit by bit.  Yesterday on the way back from Felix’s swimming lesson, Ross, my Dad and Felix were told to get a birthday present for Imy’s friend, Iris, and I had asked Ross to get me some sort of receptacle to store the things that I needed on my bedside table.&lt;br /&gt;
I’m not sure exactly what went on, but the outcome was a success.  Asking Felix to choose something a girl a year older than him caused him some confusion, my Dad just left the shop unwilling to take any responsibility for the decisions being made, but Ross rose to the challenge and surpassed himself.  He’s amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’d organised my bedside table with said new receptacle, I spoke to Max and he suggested I try one of the fancy candles he’d sent me in his Care Package.  Unfortunately the stupid cat decided at that moment she needed to be on the windowsill exactly where the candle was.  Candle tipped up, freaked out cat, wax everywhere.  Me in tears, Imy in tears, but no real harm done.  Imy went off to get a more substantial candle jar to put it in and with the help from some huggles and some Oramorph, things settled down again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Care Packages have been great fully received.  They are all very different, thoughtful, and put together with love, kindness and generosity.  Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also thank you for the hugs and messages of support.  I appreciate getting messages or texts (so don’t start the message off by saying, “I hope you don’t mind…”),  as I can read and respond to them as and when I am ready.  I’m a bit funny when it comes to actually talking on the phone though.  So, if you do ring and I don’t answer, leave a message.  I’m probably hiding behind a cushion what the drama is call about!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Relinquishing-Control&quot;&gt;Relinquishing Control&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 31, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tea, Crafts, Drugs and Class Assembly]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/teas-crafts" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/teas-crafts</id>
  <published>2016-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Anyone who knows me, knows I drink coffee.&lt;p&gt;I drink proper, dripped, strong coffee - I don’t drink tea.  Coffee that is strong enough to stand your spoon up in it.   Don’t talk to me until I’ve had at least one cup in the morning.  It’s not worth it.  Come 1pm, I’m coffee’d out and will switch to squash.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except something strange has happened.  I will have a cup of coffee with breakfast, but after that, I will have a cup of fruit tea.  From a bone china cup and saucer. (Specifically an MG cup and saucer I won in a school raffle about 6 years ago.)  Or, if it’s bedtime, a cup of camomile tea in by bone china  Kate and William Royal Wedding mug (I love twee).  It’s all a bit bizarre!  I don’t know what has changed, but I can’t drink coffee the way I used to!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep my mind off the recent craziness, on Thursday, Pinky came round to show me how to crochet.  We drank fruit tea from china cups, chatted about nothing and everything, and managed to make a start with a hook and wool.  She’ll have to come back so we can do it again.  I’m determined to be able to crochet a Granny Square, and maybe even a Remembrance Day Poppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst all this tea is being drunk, arrangements are being made for me to have samples taken from my spine next week.  This is to check that the treatment plan they have lined up to use is the best one for me.  I had received a letter that tells me I have to be nil by mouth from midnight the night before the procedure.  This worries me, if my pain levels aren’t under control, I won’t be able to get to the hospital in the first place, never mind have samples taken.  Fortunately, I speak to a very knowledgeable and understanding pre-op nurse who guides me through what I can and can’t take on the morning of the procedure and I feel calmer.  We can do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday morning, Tash popped in for a quick cup of fruit tea in a china cup, and after a quick nap, I decided that I felt well enough to go and watch Felix’s Jungle Class Assembly with Ross and my Dad.  The school have been brilliant and said we can park within the grounds when we need to, which makes things so much easier.  It was still a long walk to the school hall, and I had sweat dripping off me throughout the assembly, but the kids were great.  Lots of singing, information and funky dancing.   My walking stick seemed to cause a bit of cause stir with the kids.  “Why’s your Mum got a stick, Felix?”.  He turns, shrugs, “Cancer’s spread”.  Heartbreaking.  He shouldn’t have to say words like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke to as few School Mum’s who I hadn’t seen in a while.  It’s good to catch up on other people’s news, remind myself that there are other things going on.  Good things are going on.  Happy things are going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The busy day that I had, took it’s toll on me, and I was in bed by 5:30pm.  Luckily I have alarms set to wake me up to take my medication.  I’d be in all sorts trouble if I missed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so it continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/teas-crafts&quot;&gt;Tea, Crafts, Drugs and Class Assembly&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 29, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's 4am]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/4am" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/4am</id>
  <published>2016-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Here I am, awake and waiting for the painkillers to kick in.  It&#39;s all getting very tiresome.&lt;p&gt;Sunday and Monday ended up as quiet days, and they were good days.  I like quiet, calm days.  Imy needed some persuasion to get to school, but she’d had a good chat with a key worker and seemed happier on her return home.  We are finding her more emotional than normal, but all we can do is make sure she knows she is loved and supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday arrived, and we were up and at ‘em early to get the kids dropped off at school and then us off to the hospital to get my port reinserted.  I had been hoped they’d knock me out for it, but due to the cocktail of drugs I’m already taking, they just gave me a little bit of sedation, local anesthetic, and 30 minutes later, I was back in my room watching the end of Bargain Hunt with Ross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I’d been in theatre, Ross had spoken to my GP to get my pain meds tweaked.  The levels just weren’t quite right and I was finding it difficult to keep under control.  Between them, they came up with a plan, and I’ll be able to function with some level of normality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit later on I got a message that my Dad had arrived at ours, so the kids would be collected from school with no fuss or drama.  Tea was made for them, and they were taken to after school activities once their homework had been completed.  I think my Dad was a bit shocked in the difference between me since the last saw me at Christmas. A month ago, I was just normal little me.  Getting on with life.  Now I’m discussing adapting my way of living to make things easier for me and those around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I need to look into quickly though is getting a Blue Badge.  I can’t walk far, I’m using a stick and trying to do normal stuff is becoming more problematic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m getting my first dose of Herceptin today, as well as a bone strengthener.  A long dull day in hospital but a positive step to giving this horrible disease its marching orders again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Just a little note to say thank you to everyone who has sent a care package.  Large or small, edible or not, even the messages, emails, texts and calls.  They are all appreciated and make me feel like I’ve got an army of supporters helping me walk along the road I need to travel.  It’s not too much fun at the minute, but it won’t all be doom and gloom either.  I can’t live like that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/4am&quot;&gt;It's 4am&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 26, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Pain!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the%20pain" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the pain</id>
  <published>2016-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Things are starting to get harder for me.&lt;p&gt;I’m finding it harder to walk any great distance.  School runs are out.  I can’t drive due to the meds and keeping comfortable for any length of time is a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday night, I’d woken up as usual at 5am in discomfort.  By the time I’d been to the loo, things had reached a peak and I was crying and screaming in pain.  It took 10 minutes to get the level 10 pain down to a still very Hurty 8 pain.  Unfortunately I’d woken Imy up and she got rather distressed with the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross took the kids to rugby to allow them some normality, and Charli came round to keep me company and make sure the pain remained under control.  It was very much appreciated and kept me occupied enough to get through the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Ross came back, he went to Tesco for some supplies.  These included a shower chair, a coccyx cushion, a wall handle for the bathroom and a walking stick.  This has really upset me as walking sticks are for old people. I’m only 38.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to get some much needed relief by lying on the floor in the front room. Obviously it’s a bit of a pain for the rest of the family, but they’ll have to get used to it.  Imy has asked if it’s likely that I’ll wake up crying in the night again.  I hope not.  It’s not pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the%20pain&quot;&gt;The Pain!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 25, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Singing through the pain]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-through-the%20pain" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-through-the pain</id>
  <published>2016-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The phone has been ringing a lot at our house recently.&lt;p&gt;It’ll be the doctor, the chemo ward, the insurance company. All giving me information, updates and appointments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To distract myself, on Wednesday, Tash drove me to choir so I could sing. I’m so glad she did. When I got my primary diagnosis I promised myself I’d start to do things I had been putting off. The first one of those things was to join a choir. Luckily, one had started up a month or so before locally in Baldock, so I put my big girl pants on, and went along. I’ve loved it all. I’ve met some truly lovely people and learned to have confidence in my singing again. (I lost all confidence in my ability in my late teens and it was just something I would do in the shower. ) I’ve since sung at Christmas concerts, collaborative concerts, an open mike session and even in a group at someone’s wedding. A few people at choir already knew what was occuring thanks to the power of social media, so I got some lovely hugs and much appreciated words of encouragement. As long as I can sing, I’ll be there, with the Naughty Alto’s, having fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-organised&quot;&gt;Getting Organised&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve started to gather together paperwork so that all my financial stuff is in one place. Pensions, bank accounts, and I also set up a funeral insurance plan. Not the happiest of jobs, but I don’t want Ross to have to worry about how he’ll cope with it all. One phone call, one direct debit set up, and it was all done. We must get round to sorting our Will out too. It won’t be complicated, Ross get’s everything, and there’s not even that much of that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-looking-cancer-patient-in-hertfordshire&quot;&gt;Best Looking Cancer Patient in Hertfordshire&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to not allow standards to slip, I went to see my lovely hairdresser Isabel yesterday to get my hair cut and coloured. As it’s not been decided if I’ll be having a chemo treatment which will cause my hair to fall out or not yet, I thought I might as well start the process off looking a million dollars. If it falls out later, so be it, but for now, I’m delighted. It’s great to be able to have such trust in a hairdresser to be able to say, I want it cut and coloured - you decide what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;another-scan&quot;&gt;Another Scan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I can start treatment, I had to get a last minute appointment see a cardiologist to check my heart was well enough to withstand it. Herceptin has been shown to damage some people’s hearts to the extent where treatment has to be stopped. Luckily, my heart is in tip top condition so there’s no issue with moving onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;treatment-begins&quot;&gt;Treatment Begins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week the fun really begins. I’m having a port reinserted on Tuesday to allow for easy administration of infusions. Herceptin, the targeted treatment will start on Wednesday and I’ll also get an infusion of Zometa which will help plug the holes in my damaged vertebrae. These treatments will be every 3 weeks for as long as they continue to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad will be coming down to look after the kids for a bit whilst this is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the meantime, the flowers, gifts, chocolates and messages of support continue to come in and lift our spirits. We’re in a really tough place, but knowing we have a legion behind us, is keeping us going. Ross had to take Felix to his swimming lesson this morning, but my pain has gone up a notch, and I’m finding it hard to get comfortable. Ross wasn’t going to take Felix, but rather stay with me. He changed his mind when I told him that if anything changed, I would put a shout out and that I was confident someone would be able to come round and keep me company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;all-cancers-are-different&quot;&gt;All cancers are different&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word Cancer is an umbrella term for a wide range of diseases.  For every cell in the human body, their can be one or more associated, renegade cancer cells. There is not a “One Size Fits All” cancer diagnosis. There are also different stages and grades. Grade 1 is slow growing, Grade 3 is fast growing. Stage 1 is contained in a small place, Stage 4 for travelled. You can’t compare different cancers, it’s like comparing apples to pears.  Both fruit, both different. You can’t compare Stage 4, Grade 3 Invasive Ductal Carcinoma with Stage 3 Liver cancer. They all have different treatments, and prognosis. Everyone will also have different treatment plans too, even if they do happen to have the same diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-cure&quot;&gt;No Cure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the tough things to try and explain is that now that the cancer has come back, there is no cure. Yes, we got on top of it once, and I “beat it”, but that can’t be done this time. No amount of positive thinking, tumeric, cannabis oil or fairy dust is going to get rid of this blasted disease. It’s decided I’m a nice place to stay. (I’m not flattered about this.) The best we can hope for is that the treatment keeps it under control for a long time to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still not a fan of the battle/warrior/fighter/brave analogies. This isn’t a fight that I’ll win. It doesn’t mean I didn’t try hard enough, it means that Cancer is a horrific, destructive and merciless disease that takes no prisoners. I hate it, because it’s robbing my family of our future together. My babies deserve so much better. My husband had hoped to be married to me for a long time yet. My parents shouldn’t have to be having the conversations they are having. My brother’s shouldn’t have to face up to the loss of a sibling (even if I am the annoying, shouty, loud one). My friends may have to have some very scary conversations with their children that sometimes there is nothing you can do about an altogether horrible situation, and all you can do is offer a friendly ear, hug or word of compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-babies&quot;&gt;My Babies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side point, can I ask that my friends who know Imogen and Felix and want their children to be there for them, that they allow Imy and Felix to talk abut things on their own terms?  They don’t need to be bombarded with questions or statistics or be told how long I’m going to live for.  Can I ask that you talk to them and ask them to be compassionate and kind.  The future is very uncertain for Imy and Felix and they don’t need to have any extra or unnecessary hurt caused by someone’s lack of empathy or thinking.  When I was their age it wouldn’t even been on my radar that I could lose a parent, and it breaks my heart for them, to think that this is in their future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enough&quot;&gt;Enough!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But enough wallowing! Because at this very moment we’ve got time. For now I’ll take the hugs, and the love and support. I’ll keep on smiling, I’ll probably keep on swearing and making very inappropriate jokes. I’ll be offering hugs to people who find it frightening and scary. I’ll be the one saying “ Everything will be OK”. Because that’s me. That’s who I am. And that’s not going to change just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-through-the%20pain&quot;&gt;Singing through the pain&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 23, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Support]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/super-support" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/super-support</id>
  <published>2016-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">There&#39;s no right or wrong way to deal with life changing news, there&#39;s no rule book.&lt;p&gt;There may be some self help books, but &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; reads them just in case?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mixed-bag&quot;&gt;Mixed Bag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now the news is public, I’m not going to rehash it but in short it’s a mixed bag. Good news is it’s only in one place, so much more containable. Bad news we’re not talking cure but containment. We’re hoping for a record breaking amount of time containing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My emotions have been up and down, the metaphor I used in my head was swimming in stormy seas. Waves of grief for a future that won’t happen, sadness and worry for Julia, being scared of being alone all crashing into me. It was a rawness I’ve never felt before and I’ve glimpsed a chasm of despair that is so alien to me and my personality. It’s a worrying time to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;telling-the-world&quot;&gt;Telling the world&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had told the kids the basics in the morning, Imogen was brave and worried, Felix seemed unsure. It felt good to let them know it’s not their fault Mum and Dad have been fraught over the weekend. We have to keep them talking and let them express any worries over the coming months / years. I plan to be proactive about it but I can see it’s going to be a fine line between asking and over asking. I’ll have to stay attuned and am planning at some point making sure that they (we?) get counselling to ensure that they become the well adjusted and wonderful children that Julia and I know they will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke to the teachers at school - through sobs and asked them to look after the kids today. It was just so hard to speak about it and acknowledge it publicly. I was a mess and the teachers were kind but probably more than a little bemused and concerned. Whilst leaving the playground, I happened to bump into Rachel and then Adam and needed hugs from them both so I could compose myself - thanks you two it was much needed and much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia and I headed off to the Doctors for better meds, tears filled my eyes more than once and I realised I best to speak to one soon as well. We got more meds, a bagful, the lady at the pharmacy was kind and efficient and we headed back home. The extra meds have helped Julia get more comfortable and reach a lower number of the pain scale. It breaks my heart that even with all these meds she is still on the pain scale but I can but hope future treatment will sort that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We publish our blog posts and let the world know, Facebook is a marvelous thing at times. Julia announced the news and support, love and kind words flood in raising our spirits. I had a meltdown in the kitchen and posted my own post to facebook. The amount of support was humbling and helped my sea of anxiety soften. I took strength from the comments, encouragement and love that came through. Support has flooded in from best friends, old friends, internet wierdy friends (Julia’s terminology!) and even people we have never met or spoken to. It’s been amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hard-times-ahead&quot;&gt;Hard times ahead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of Felix’s, told him that if Julia’s cancer has comeback then she’ll be dead in five years. It’s shocking and I don’t know where a 7 year old would get that from but I can’t be angry at Felix’s friend, he’s a child just like Felix. Anyway, Felix told me he doesn’t believe it and we talked about it with Imogen on the way home from school. I couldn’t lie and tell them it definitely won’t be the case but rather, I stuck to the positives, no one knows the future and the doctors are working their hardest to do their best to contain it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Julia and I don’t know the implications of the reoccurrence of cancer, then how can the kids? We have to keep to the positives and ask the kids to be the best they can be and make sure they talk if they need to and get space when they need as well. Felix, holds his feelings closer than Imy and that night for the first time in an age he has a bed wetting accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fog-clearing&quot;&gt;Fog clearing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to see the Doctor myself yesterday, I had been feeling better or rather more on an even keel. I bumped into Pinky and that facade crumbled but it all helps - thanks for the hugs. I spoke to doctor, talked myself out of any medication but I know that they are there should they be needed. That in itself has been a big relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rawness of the initial shock seems to be leaving and I feel more positive. The insurance company are on board, which is a relief and we are starting treatment next week. I even managed to tell my colleagues at work without booing - a big improvement. The house seems to be running smoothly, chief laundry master Lawley has stepped up to the plate! Being proactive always helps me and I’m glad to say my wobbles have been further apart. I’m sure they’ll be back but with such awesome support from friends and family I know we’ll stay afloat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/super-support&quot;&gt;Super Support&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 21, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scans and Results]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scans-and-results" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scans-and-results</id>
  <published>2016-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Yesterday, we went for the final scan.&lt;p&gt;This one was to last an hour an a half, and when I came out I was a bit annoyed when they radiologist told me the results would be through in 3 days.  I had a bit of a strop and told them I was seeing the consultant that evening and he needed to report by then.  There was lots of huffing and puffing on their part and I left them to it.  In the car park on the way out, I phoned my consultant’s secretarial team and told them they might need to put some pressure on them to get the results.  These ladies are brilliant and whatever they did, it worked.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 7pm I was in the consultants office and he told me that it was indeed cancer in the vertebrae, but by some miracle that’s the only place it was.  He’s currently deciding on a treatment plan, which is likely to include a bone biopsy, cemented the vertebrae to sure it up a bit and try and avoid it collapsing, radiotherapy, possible changes to me Hormone therapy, and the likely restarting of Herceptin, which means I’ll be having a port reinserted.  The Herceptin will be every 3 weeks for the rest of my life.  There may be chemotherapy involved but that’s not definite yet.  Things are going to move quickly, I’ve just got to be ready to go where I’m told, when I’m told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this all being an awful lot to take on, we’ve got to look at the positives.  The consultant is talking in terms of years, not weeks or months.  The fact it’s only in one vertebrae is also on my side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I phoned my brothers to let them know the news.  And felt better for them to know.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been to the GP’s this morning to get some more painkillers, and more drugs to deal with the side effects of the said painkillers.  I’m also being referred to a Macmillan nurse who will help me deal with things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kids have been told, and the school is aware so that they can help them through this.  Imogen can be a delicate flower, and will no doubt need a lot of help from her friends, and adult key workers.  Felix is a very different fish, we just need to make sure he doesn’t bottle things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, once again, here we are, keeping on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scans-and-results&quot;&gt;Scans and Results&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 19, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[An unwelcome surprise]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/an-unwelcome-surprise" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/an-unwelcome-surprise</id>
  <published>2016-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s been a year since I last wrote, I was starting to believe I would only to come back to the blog as a visitor.&lt;p&gt;You’ve should have read Julia’s post so you have an idea of whats occurring, if not catch up there first. I write in this blog to help me process and connect with my feelings. It’s also been a great conduit for me and Julia to communicate our inner thoughts in a way thats less burdening than a conversation would be.
I digress…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-pain-in-the-back&quot;&gt;A pain in the back&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Julia’s had back pain and its been worse than normal. Deep down Julia knows this and calls the oncologist to discuss it. I think she’s being a drama queen and tell her off for not going to the GP first! A few of our friends also agree but Dr Shah plays it safe and orders an MRI. On &lt;em&gt;Tuesday&lt;/em&gt; we make the journey to Spire Harpenden and I can’t help be nostalgic, the journey may have been a pain in the bum but I enjoyed the time Julia and I had when she was on treatment. It was our time, it bought us closer and helped make me feel useful whilst she had her treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MRI goes swimmingly and we are a little anxious as we await the results. They gave us a dvd with the images on, how cool is that? Julia looks at it and Googles. “Is that a bulging disk?” That’ll explain it. I look through, Google MRI spine and learn about disks, vertebrae and the like. It all looks good to my untrained eye, which is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-hate-the-qe2&quot;&gt;I hate the QE2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head to the QE2 on &lt;em&gt;Wednesday&lt;/em&gt;, its been such a long time since we were last there. In fact the old hospital seems to have fallen down and a new smaller hospital sits in its shadow. Julia and I like the new QE2 it’s shiny. We potter round to the yellow zone in search of Dr Shah. Julia’s nervous, I can tell, shouldn’t I be nervous? No, it’s just muscular back pain, Julia is being a drama queen and Dr Shah moved the appointment because it was more convenient for him as he has 2 hospitals and a university to lecture at today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get called into see Dr Shah, comment on how nice the hospital is. Dr Shah cuts to the chase - he doesn’t have the images but has been told it’s cancer. My mind is slow to react, it’s like I’m watching myself, looking out of my eyes. I can’t comprehend what he just said. He’s still explaining and I see Julia shaking. How did this happen? Treatment went so well we weren’t even having scans to check. We hand over the images to Dr Shah and Julia walks him getting the program started - “it’s IT it’s what &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; do” says Julia. One vertebrae is the wrong shade of grey. Dr Shah explains that theres a 90% chance it’s cancer and tells us not to hold out for the 10%. He says we need blood tests, a CT Scan and full spinal MRI to confirm and see if its spread. He’ll sort this out and we should see him Monday evening. He says we should be prepared for a hard meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He offers the NHS’s drug cabinet to Julia and writes a big prescription. Julia’s painkiller of choice is liquid Morphine. I’m stunned and in a daze, we’re leaving his office and the news is hitting home. Its so hard and unfair, Julia is white as a sheet and shaking.  We head to the pharmacist and are told there’s a 40 minute wait as the Morphine is a controlled drug. We have a coffee and cry in the coffee shop. Julia is much better than me, more prepared and more composed. I’ve been sideswiped, I must have lied to myself as I hadn’t entertained the thought. We’ve been through so much and we were supposed to be out the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prepare-for-the-worst&quot;&gt;Prepare for the worst&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie, the next few days were hard. The hardest I’ve ever been through. My stupid imagination is relentlessly cruel and feelings hit me like waves. I’m working hard to stay afloat in this maelstrom but at times I break. Weirdly, its at odd times, a glib comment by Julia or when doing things with the kids whilst Julia rests, I ask is this how it will be in the future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia shames me with her composure, I guess the drugs are numbing her feelings also and is in a world of sadness of her own. I also know that I have to work hard get past my feelings. I’m not a strong person but I know bottling the tears is not the way, anyway I seem to have developed my own personal spring, so I can’t. Crying is sadness leaving the body and I have to prepare for the worst, just in case it comes, because if it does I have to be strong for Julia and the kids. It’s an indulgence or necessity now that I can’t take later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friends have been great in helping and offering to pick up kids and sending good wishes. We haven’t told everyone yet - we still don’t know what the answer will be. The kids are having to deal with, what must appear to them as a pair of emotionally disfunctional parents! However, they help keep spirits high with their energy and their laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insomnia&quot;&gt;Insomnia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve fallen into the habit of waking up early and not being able to go back to sleep as our minds are racing. Julia’s pain wakes her and I wake as she gets up and takes more drugs to dampen it down. Even with all the drugs she’s taking I’m concerned that she still feels pain from her back, it might fade to the background but its still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My head is not in the right place to do any coding, so I tell work whats happening and that I will report in on Tuesday when we have the answers about her back. Work again have been brilliant, allowing me to take time and wishing us the best. I’m so grateful to be working for them, in so many ways they’ve been brilliant through this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weekend&quot;&gt;Weekend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday, comes and its CT Scan day, but first some of Julia’s friends are keen to see her in person and Julia invites them round for coffee after the school drop off. We bump into Neil and its good to see him up and about after a rather nasty chest infection. Neil, asks what folks are doing and I invite him for coffee. We chat, he asks after Julia and I mention her back and then choke. For a few moments I can’t speak and tears well. Eventually, I get the words out and he’s shocked by the news. Rather than join the Julia and the ladies for coffee we head off to the coffee shop and that coffee was great. Just talking about it for a few moments and then talking about normal things lifts helps lift a burden and raise spirits. Thanks Neil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we head back to the Spire and it’s done quick enough. The journey to and from the hospital gives us time to reflect and chat. In the past week we’ve had so &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; hard conversations. Ones that I couldn’t imagined having just the week before. We are preparing for the worst and Julia is getting her stuff together. We’ve talked about wills, funerals, the kids, life, the future. It might seem morbid and in away it is, but Julia would hate for me to get it wrong - or more correctly she’d hate for me to worry that I’d got stuff wrong. And yes we know there is hope, that it might be muscular and not sinister at all but it’d be foolish to delude ourselves totally. Anyway, doing this and organising things is what Julia is good at. It keeps her busy and is the most proactive thing to do in the circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beers&quot;&gt;Beers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday, I ferry Felix to the pool for his lesson and take time out to read whilst he swims. I bump into the Strongs at the pool and there’s talk of a beer in the evening with Adam - sounds good to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep ourselves busy, Julia and I planned a trip to the IMAX to see Star Wars again. It’s pretty “in your face” cool with the 3D visuals and super sound. I notice Julia looks to be in pain at times during the film, so once its over we ditch the dinner plans and opt for takeaway instead. After dinner and painkillers Julia zones out, whilst the kids cheer for the latest round of contestants in Ninja Warrior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I head out the pub and its nice to have a few beers. I probably had more than I had planned but Dan, Adam and Marcus are good company. By the time we leave the pub its snowing. Theres always a touch of magic walking through the first flakes of snow. Dan and I have a chat about Julia whilst heading home and for the first time since the news, I feel at peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunday-feeling&quot;&gt;Sunday feeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always think the downside to having beers, is you pay for the previous nights happiness with todays. As if happiness is some kind of limited resource. The hangover wasn’t great and I have a touch of the blues. I make a mental note I can’t be having too many, too often as it has a high happiness cost!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rugby was cancelled, so Imogen decides to make cheesecake. A brilliant plan! I walk them to the supermarket whilst Julia takes it easy. We grab snow from the tops of walls and throw snowballs there and back. I become Imogen’s sous chef - man she’s demanding! Later on I watch the rugby on tv and generally chill. The kids get a little cabin fevered - note to self I need to exercise them more when rugby is off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sunday feeling is hard to bare, there’s some dread about what tomorrow may bring. Finding sleep is hard and moods are low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monday-monday&quot;&gt;Monday, Monday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, this is the worst Monday of the year, the newspapers say so, so it must be true. We’re on board with that, but we also are hoping for sciatica. That’s in our script, so lets hope it becomes so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased that Julia was up for the school run today. It’s even better that she has the chance to head to the community centre for coffee with friends after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia is currently having an mammoth MRI scan an hour and half (we know how to get the most out of our insurance). I’m in the waiting room, drinking coffee and, well, waiting. There’s an odd bunch in today. I’m not a fan of the man whose been listening to loud music, farting and burping as he has to down a litre of water for some scan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way I’m glad today’s come even though it’s ominous at least we’ll know what’s what. We’ll be able to talk about it with clarity. The kids can finally know why we’ve been so weird and we can be open with all our friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it is what it is and tonight we find out, here’s hoping for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/an-unwelcome-surprise&quot;&gt;An unwelcome surprise&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 18, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long Weekend]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-long-weekend" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-long-weekend</id>
  <published>2016-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Saturday started early again, with the usual pain waking me up.&lt;p&gt;After a few hours the kids came in and were despatched to play on the Playstation or read.  Next thing I know, it’s time for Ross to take Felix to his swimming lesson and Imogen was instructed to get her homework done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we’d had lunch it was time to see Star Wars again.  This time at the IMAX.  It was brilliant.  We really enjoyed it.  It was quite uncomfortable for me to sit for over two hours and I was glad to get home to top up the painkillers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A curry was ordered in for tea, and Ross went out for a couple of beers.  I went to bed when the kids did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday we were praying that rugby training would be cancelled due to it being so cold and a covering of snow.  Luckily it was, so despite my early waking, I had Breakfast in bed and was back asleep by 10am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was quiet, but with the anticipation building for tomorrow’s final scan and the results we’ll get, to say I’m a bit anxious is an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-long-weekend&quot;&gt;The Long Weekend&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 17, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Day, Another Scan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-day-another-scan" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-day-another-scan</id>
  <published>2016-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;ve been waking up in the night by the pain in my back.&lt;p&gt;I usually take some morphine and some diazepam to try and relieve it before going back to sleep.  Unfortunately, sleep tends to be illusive, and by the time I’ve huffed and puffed a bit, Ross has woken up.  We chat for a while, maybe read, maybe chat to the other insomniacs on social media, and if we’re lucky get back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I had some visitors, which was nice.  Some of the Gin Club came round after the morning school with biscuits and made their own tea and coffee. (They are good like that.)  It’s good to have news from the outside world.  Something that doesn’t involve me, pain, cancer or hospitals.  I appreciate it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was due a CT with contrast today and was nil by mouth from 9am.  This included painkillers.  The imaging department at the hospital was very efficient, I was given water, changed into a robe, had a cannula fitted and was led into the CT suite.  By this point I was in agony.  20 minutes later, I was all done, the radiographers helped me up out of the scanner as I can’t get from lying to sitting on my own, and sent on my way, but not before I dosed up on morphine and other painkillers, and snuck in a cup of coffee and some jammy dodgers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once home I tried to keep busy.  Felix was out at a friends and Imy got on with her music practice.  We haven’t said anything to the bairns yet about any of this.  They know I have a bad back, and that I’ve been having scans and seeing doctors. I don’t think Cancer is even on their radar.  They don’t know you can get cancer in your back or bones.  Why would they?  They are children.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, I have another MRI, and then in the evening, after we’ve seen the Oncologist and find out what we are dealing with, we’ll decide what to tell them and how best to do it.  I don’t expect it’ll be an easy conversation.  But - it still could be a trapped nerve…there’s a 10% chance it’s not cancer.  Please let that be the case.  Please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-day-another-scan&quot;&gt;Another Day, Another Scan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 15, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bad Back, Bad News]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/bad-back-bad-news" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/bad-back-bad-news</id>
  <published>2016-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">After the upbeat nature of my last post, I&#39;m afraid to say things aren&#39;t going to plan.&lt;p&gt;I had said I wanted to have no medical interventions I didn’t choose myself.  Nope - I’ve failed at that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, after the kids went back to school, I started to get a pain in my back.  Back pain is not unusual for me, so I ignored it for a bit.  But it got progressively worse.  I became permanently attached to a hot water bottle, even taking it into the office with me.  I started talking painkillers but the paracetamol and ibuprofen weren’t cutting it, so I broke into my stash of Tramadol.  This was a mistake as it sends me a bit doo-lally.  It didn’t make the pain much better either, so I went back to the paracetamol and ibuprofen.  Walking was becoming laboured, bending and twisting was agony and I couldn’t sleep properly as the pain was waking me up.  I like to think I have quite a high pain threshold, but this was something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross suggested I do some stretches and use his roller for easing muscular pain.  For a quiet life I gave them a go, but nothing helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time Monday morning rolled around, I’d had enough.  Ross suggested seeing the GP for painkillers, but instead I emailed my Oncologist’s secretary to see if he could fit me in for a quick telephone chat.  I wanted him to tell me to “Man up and get on with things”.  I even told him this when we spoke later that evening on the phone.  I explained my symptoms, and he thought it sounded like a slipped disk.  Oh! I haven’t had one of them before!  Then he said given my history, that I should go for an MRI and he’d get his secretary to organise it quickly for me.  He also told me to go to the GP for the painkillers.  He gave me a list of what to ask for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, I go to the GP’s and come back with a good haul of painkillers, including anti-inflamitories and valium.  ( :-o )  He tells me if I don’t get an MRI through quickly via my consultant, then I was to go back and let them know and they would organise one for me.  This is a bit odd.  People are taking me seriously!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At lunchtime I get a call telling me to go for a scan at 4:30 that afternoon, and that the Oncologist will catch up with me the following Monday to discuss the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the scan is done, I get all my images on disk.  This is quite exciting, considering all the scans I’ve had, I’ve never actually seen any!  But I’ve got my own disk!  To keep!  Obviously Ross and I have a look at them, but can’t make head or tail of them so put it back in it’s envelope and wait to see the Oncologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The appointment comes through quicker than we anticipated.  His secretary contacted me the next day to tell me that he wanted to see me as soon as possible and could I get to the hospital for lunchtime.  Oh.  Ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the hospital we are sat down and Dr Shah makes no bones about the fact (no pun intended) that he is 90% sure my pain is caused by cancer in the vertebrae which is causing it to bulge and press on my spinal cord.  Obviously this is bad news.  Very bad news.  It means the breast cancer has metastasized and gone traveling.  If it is the 90%, then I’ll be classed as Stage 4 or terminal.  There is no cure for this, only management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing he wants to do is get my pain under control.  In addition to the painkillers given to me by the GP, he has given me steroids and oral morphine, as well as a couple of drugs to counteract the side effects of these.  He’s said if the pain can’t be controlled by this method, he’ll get me admitted so it can be done in a more controlled environment.  Obviously, I don’t want to go into hospital, I want to be with me family.  I want to watch Imy and Felix play rugby on Sunday.  I want to see Star Wars again on Saturday, but this time at the IMAX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To confirm the diagnosis, I need the have a couple more scans.  A CT is booked in for Friday, and another MRI for Monday.  The idea is they confirm that the suspect vertebrae is in fact Cancer (although there’s still a 10% chance it’s not), and also see if it’s managed to go anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment plan would involve radiotherapy and “therapy” but he wasn’t clear on whether that would be chemotherapy or targeted therapy like Herceptin or it’s sisters.  He said there was no point having a big long discussion about it now, as until he’s got all the facts, he won’t have a plan of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question “How long have I got?” was also evaded.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then went to the chemo ward to have some bloods taken.  It was bizarre to be back there, seeing the lovely chemo nurses.  They gave me big hugs, and I told them as much as it was nice to see them, I hadn’t really wanted to go back there.  They completely understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are, back playing the Waiting Game.  Thankfully we won’t have to wait long.  I’ll be seeing him again on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/bad-back-bad-news&quot;&gt;Bad Back, Bad News&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 14, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another New Year]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year</id>
  <published>2015-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Three years ago, we were thinking to ourselves that 2012 had been a pretty good year, and looking forward to another good one in 2013.&lt;p&gt;As it transpired, it was a good year.  We moved into a new house, we had a couple of great holidays, as a family, things were fantastic, everyone was happy but it was also the year where things changed for me forever.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gone over what it feels like to have the rug pulled out from under you before, I’m not going to rake over old ground. I’m here 2 years on, feeling very grateful I’ve got to another New Year, still not dead.  But it’s going to take me a long time yet to get over it mentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen has requested that as a New Year’s resolution, I try not to shout as much.  I’ll give it a go, but I’m also going to try and not have any medical interventions that I don’t choose myself. (Ha, like I have any say in that!)  In 2015, I finished Herceptin, and had two lots of surgery and still more scans, and consultant appointments.  I’m tired of hospitals.  Tired of doctors. Tired of tests. And just generally tired.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the latest round of tests, I’ve been told that my health is pretty perfect, which is obviously great news!  I’m just experiencing the after effects of 2 years of medical interventions.  Just.  Ok, great.  Thanks.  I’ve had Cancer, can I just move on now?  No!  I need to build up my stamina again, but it’s proving tricky.  I can swim 40 lengths in half an hour, do a pilates class, walk the kids to and from school, but every morning I wake up feeling like I could sleep for a week. I can’t even do a full day at work without having to take two days to recover! It’s just annoying.  I want to be able to do everything that I want to do, everything that I used to be able to do, and I can’t and it’s really frustrating me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are my New Year Resolutions?  It may sound dramatic, but I’d like to stay alive.  I’d like to get to my 40th birthday in Feb 2017.  The type of cancer I had, before the days of Herceptin, it would have been game over.  Grade 3, HER2+ breast cancer is not good news, it spreads fast and wide.  Luckily, I’ve had the Herceptin, hopefully it’s got rid of all the baddies that were lingering that the surgery didn’t get, and we can carry on. I’ve been signed up for a Macmillan Hope course in January which will hopefully help me deal with The Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the second one and to be fair, I think I’ll stop there.  That’s enough to be going on with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all my friends and family who have been with me on the journey so far, I thank you.  I’m sorry to be a Cancer bore.  I can rely on you all to keep my spirits up, and tell me how it is.  In fact, I think Rachel said “God, Julia, just because you’ve had cancer doesn’t mean you get special treatment!”.  Keeping it real!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year&quot;&gt;Another New Year&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>