<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2013-11-21T08:39:32+00:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The chemo starts]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/z-the-chemo-starts" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/z-the-chemo-starts</id>
  <published>2013-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Luckily, granny and grandad were on hand to get the bairns organised and to breakfast club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There had been an accident on the A1, so the trusty sat nav sent us different way to the hospital.  We get stuck in a bit of traffic around Hitchin, which makes us nervous, but we arrive in time and are soon settled into our room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurses are very efficient and before long I’m hooked up to a drip, being pumped with saline, anti sickness drugs, and then the main feature, the chemo drugs.  Note to self, go to the loo before being hooked up to the machine.  It’s a Faff otherwise.  A few hours later, I’m detached, and sent on my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way home we pop to Argos and pick up a few Christmas presents.  It’s good to feel like we’re doing something positive for Christmas.  The timing of the treatments suck, but needs must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home, we have lunch and then I try for a nap to catch up on some sleep.  I manage about 45 mins but then the bairns come in from school and want to check I’m ok after my treatment.  I’ve still got a line attached to my port as I’m back to the hospital tomorrow to start my Herceptin treatment, so they were interested in having a look at it.  I’m looking forward to having it taken out tomorrow and also the steri strips removed and dressing changed so that I can have a proper shower and bath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be having an early night tonight and trying to actually sleep through most of it.  Last night was no fun.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/z-the-chemo-starts&quot;&gt;The chemo starts&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 20, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who needs sleep?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/who-needs-sleep" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/who-needs-sleep</id>
  <published>2013-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;He was fully awake by this point, so he watched last nights episode of Hebburn with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then talked about how grossly unfair this all was.  I can’t understand why the Cancer decided to have a go at me.  I realise I’m in danger of wallowing in self pity or worse slipping into depression, but I can’t help thinking ‘why me?’  What did I do to deserve this?  I also know that it’s just an unfortunate situation that is a result of chance and bad luck. Unfortunately the former is winning over the latter at the moment despite my stoicism and pragmatism, and until I learn to accept it, I will struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross managed to go back to sleep.  He needs as much sleep as he can get too.  Luckily as Ross’s parents are here, they are able to pick up the slack with things like cooking and looking after the bairns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen has told me she’s a little bit worried about my first chemo treatment and she is going to tell her teacher so they can offer her some support. I’m so glad she’s confident enough to do that, she is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix asked if my hair would fall out straight away.  I think he was disappointed when I said no.  Felix doesn’t really understand what’s going on, so he focuses on the bits he does understand.  Bald heads he can relate to.  Ross has one after all!  If he sees tangible evidence like dressings, or scars, he can relate to that. He’s had and got those himself!  He’s asked to feel the Big Lump and the implanted port catheter, they are real and physical, but he doesn’t understand the implications of them all.  To be honest, no 5 year old, or 7 year old for that matter, should have to watch a parent fight this battle.  It’s not fair on them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On hair loss related news, I had a wig delivered.  I don’t like it.  I’m going to have to go to a wig shop and try some on.  The problem I have is, I have quite a small head, small forehead and a widow’s peak.  So to get a wig that sits right will prove tricky.  My wonderful hairdresser is going to see if there’s anything she can do with the internet wig, so at least I have a backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to try for another hour of sleep now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shall return.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/who-needs-sleep&quot;&gt;Who needs sleep?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 20, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perfect Heart]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/perfect-heart" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/perfect-heart</id>
  <published>2013-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Woot.  In fact, despite having cancer, all the various health checks I’ve had recently tell me I’m actually in pretty good shape.  This is good news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it’s all go for the chemo and herceptin on Wednesday and Thursday.  I’m feeling quite calm about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was driving to work this this morning, David Guetta’s Titanium came on.  “Shoot me down, but I won’t fall, I am Titanium”.  That’s me!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/perfect-heart&quot;&gt;Perfect Heart&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 18, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Busy, busy, busy]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/busy-busy-busy" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/busy-busy-busy</id>
  <published>2013-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up and at ‘em after a terrible nights sleep on the lovely new matress.  Julia
was worried she would fall out and took over two thirds of the bed and no
amount of snoring would get her to move!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix bounded out of bed as it’s Children In Need and pyjama day at school.
Imogen was less excited about the idea of the early rising. Michelle was a star
and took the kids at 6:30am as we dashed down the A1 and onto the M25 for the
9am appointment in Rickmansworth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The staff were great and we soon found out about Julia’s operation.  No general
anethestic needed so Julia was happy. I had some coding to do, so spent the
waiting period working and watching lectures for the online course I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short time after Julia is wheeled out, she’s back and still chilled out
from the sedatives.  She looks a million times better than she did after the
general and is keen for food and drink so they can discharge her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once free we have to take some bloods to Harpenden so Julia can be signed fit
for chemotherapy.  At the hospital Julia gets to meet the chemotherapy nurses
and they talk us through the process.  This answers some questions and wierdly
it all now feels more “normal” now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get home and Julia rests up. I get the kids from school but by 8:30pm I
can’t stay awake and head up the wooden hills to Bedfordshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;saturday&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia seemed less scared about falling off the bed and we both manage to get a
good nights sleep.  It’s my parents 45th wedding anniversary today, I didn’t
think we’d make it but Julia is feeling well enough to go.  So we head off
to Newbury.  The M25 is a nightmare and we park for 30mins, I’m just glad it was
easy running the day before.  Once that wrinkle is out the way, we cruise to
Newbury and surprise my parents by phoning from outside their flat.  We have
a great lunch, it’s brilliant to see the family and to see Julia looking so great
and enjoying some fizzy wine! We head back in the early evening tired and
happy.  Julia is sore from Fridays operation and plans to have a well deserved
lie-in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sunday&quot;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I let Julia rest and take the kids to their swimming lessons.  We swim for an
hour and then after a cuppa it’s time to head home and do the chores.  I head
to the tip, do the laundry, go shopping, do the tidying and the cooking.  We
are now eating more vegetables and I’m not a fan of raw veg but it’s time to get
over that.  Felix is less enthusiastic initially but the kids barter between
themselves - some of the pepper slices for cucumber and peace is restored.  I
even smile whilst showing Felix I now like raw tomatos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon I play some Lego Star Wars with the kids then I bully Julia
into an afternoon walk.  The doctors have said that exercise will help…
Its a grey old day, but the kids chase me kicking the rugby ball round Ivel
Springs.  We head home via the Orange Tree for a cheeky pint. Good day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monday&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents arrive at lunchtime they are over for the week to help out.  I take
them on the school run to pick up the kids and meet the teachers so they know
where to get them later in the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening Julia has her ECG the whole thing was funny, the Doctor was great,
slightly disorganised but the tells Julia she has a perfect heart.  We are
good to go for Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/busy-busy-busy&quot;&gt;Busy, busy, busy&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 18, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[More surgery]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/more-surgery" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/more-surgery</id>
  <published>2013-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since my last post, there’s been a lot going on.  The Chemotherapy starts on Wednesday and in preparation, I’ve had a port fitted in my chest which all drugs will be dispensed through.  It’ll also be used for blood tests and will save the veins in my right arm.  I can’t have any blood tests, injections, or even blood pressure taken on my left arm ever again, as I’ve had so many lymph nodes taken out, so everything would have to be done on the right arm.  The port just saves it for the length of my treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The procedure involved dropping the bairns off at Michelle’s at 6:30 on Friday morning (thank you), and then a trip to a hospital in North London.  A few hours, a local anaesthetic, light sedation, blood tests and some extra bits being fitted to me later, we’re off to another hospital to meet the Chemotherapy team.  My first Chemo treatment will be given on Wednesday, and the Herceptin will be given on Thursday.  They were all very nice, the rooms look nice, and we were sent on my way with some fairly hefty steroids which I start taking taking on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also got to have a heart scan on Monday as the Herceptin treatment can affect it and they need to get a base line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, it’s not all been crazy cancer stuff.  It was Ross’s parents 45th Wedding Anniversary and before things went mental we were planning on spending the weekend with them and the rest of the family.  Early Saturday morning Ross asked me how I was feeling and we decided that we’d make the effort and go and visit them for the day.  I’m glad we did.  It was great to see everyone.  The bairns played nicely with their cousins and it was good to see Ross with his two brothers.  We travelled back and got home for early evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning comes and I’m tired, so Ross takes the bairns to their new swimming lessons.  I then have a fairly lazy day, but did go for a walk round Ivel Springs followed by a cheeky drink in the Orange Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a visit from Anna.  She brings gifts from the Gin Club.  They are such an amazing bunch of ladies who know me very well.  It consisted of a blanket, socks, smellies, chocolate, fizzy wine, nail varnish and an iTunes voucher.  I’m blessed and touched that they took the time to do this for me.  They’ve also given me a photo album filled with photos taken at various Gin Club events. My challenge is to name and date the event.  The idea is I do it when I’m having my treatment to keep me occupied.  So thoughtful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m back to the office tomorrow.  That’s going to be odd.  I haven’t been in since before Halloween.  Yikes!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/more-surgery&quot;&gt;More surgery&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 17, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrations]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/frustrations" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/frustrations</id>
  <published>2013-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The good bit is that our new mattress has been delivered.  Greg and Rachel came round with Joni too.  Greg helped Ross sort the cat flap out, so that’s all working now.  Cats won’t go through it though…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the not so good bits…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started when I went to the doctors to pick up a prescription.  They told me it had been processed, but they couldn’t find it.  So I waited for half an hour whilst they searched for it, I even went to chemist to see if it had it, but to no avail.  I’m sorry to say I put on a sad face, and told them it was &lt;em&gt;whispers&lt;/em&gt; Cancer medication.  They then printed out a new prescription and got the doctor to sign it.  All that and then I was required to go and actually get the drugs from the pharmacy.  More waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get home, crack on with some work, and get a phone call from a hospital in North London asking me to confirm my appointment for tomorrow morning to insert a Portacath. What? Where? How?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some frantic phone calls, which Ross deals with, as I’m unable to take in any information, things start to become clearer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m having the Portacath inserted tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On Monday I’m having a heart scan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On Wednesday I start my chemotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to some great family and friends we have the kids covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scary times ahead though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/frustrations&quot;&gt;Frustrations&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 14, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drills, saws and holes]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/drills-saws-holes" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/drills-saws-holes</id>
  <published>2013-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the morning we head off to see the clinical oncologist in Welwyn.
We arrive early and no sooner had I got the iPad out the doctor is there to see us.
The doctor is really nice and reassuring about chemotherapy, it might not be all
that bad, it depends and there’s lots they can do to help.  The aim of the
treatment is to cure Julia - that’s the destination and he’s keen to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s practical reasons to do chemotherapy first, it will kill the cancer quickly
and make the operation later easier as the tumor will have shrunk.  He explains
that he wants to get moving as soon as possible.  We had wanted to get the chemo
done locally but he explains some differences about NHS versus private and it’s a no
brainer. To get moving quickly and give Julia the best care it means staying in
private sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early evening, I decide it’s a good time to fit the cat flap.  I don’t
know why it was suddenly important but it was. I got all the kit (and some more)
out of the garage, measured twice, cut once and it still wouldn’t fit as expected.
I had to cut some bolts and the nuts wouldn’t then go back on.  I picked up the
kids, went to Wickes asked for help and they only had electricians screws. Turns
out the nuts wouldn’t fit them either.  Shit.  I make tea, find some nuts that do
kind of fit and then cut the bolts too short.  Shit, Shit, Shit.  I give up and
have to walk away. My pride is wounded and it matters - of course it does, in
the grand scheme of things it’s inconsequential but that night it really mattered.
I retreat to the sofa in a huff as the cats skip merrily through the new hole in
the door.  A facebook SOS and Greg volunteers himself to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have nothing on today, no doctors, hospitals or waiting rooms Woot! I head
to the gym after dropping off the kids. The knee feels better than last week
and it’s good to de-stress.  I do notice I’m not as switched on as normal. I used
a couple of machines on the wrong settings and wondered why they felt odd, only
to notice I hadn’t moved the leg rest etc… I blame the lack of coffee but it
really is because I have become scatter brained. I have more and more things
taking up that limited resource up at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia annoys me when I get home because she is working but hasn’t had any breakfast
or coffee.  I tell her if she’s well enough to work, she’s well enough to make
herself breaky and it’s so crucial she eats, stays strong and looks after herself.
There’s been a few occassions recently where I’ve raised my eyebrows because
I’m carrying the can for her where she could so easily. I feel like that sounds
heartless and I’m whinging but I am stepping up and I’m happy to do so.
I won’t deny it’s tiring but also there are small things she can and has to do
for herself.  I remind her we are a team - TeamRJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new mattress arrives, the old one dragged into the garage waiting for the day
I have the time to get it to the tip. Greg, Rachel and Joni arrive and
Greg tells me how to file down cut bolts that don’t take a nut - 2 seconds of
rubbing the bolt on a brick and bingo.  Top tip that one! The next one is that
electricians pliers have threaded holes for cutting bolts (found that nugget out
on youtube yesterday).  Greg sorts the cat flap out in no time and I now owe him a beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In between all this and work, there’s been lots of phone calls sorting out Julia.
Tomorrow we are off to London for the portacath operation. Then monday its ECG,
Tuesday I’m off to have my jaw looked at.  Then wednesday and thursday Julia
is having chemotherapy and herceptin.  It’s going to be a busy week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theres some panic / concern when the insurance folks call about refusing a
certain drug - as its on a trial.  We hadn’t discussed this with the doctor but
it seems it was a punt on his behalf and he wasn’t hopeful so didn’t discuss it.
I’m chasing this one up to make sure and to double check it’s all tickety boo
for next week.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/drills-saws-holes&quot;&gt;Drills, saws and holes&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 14, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scores on the Doors]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scores-on-the-doors" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scores-on-the-doors</id>
  <published>2013-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We now know I have Stage 2 Grade 3 Cancer.  We also know the TMN score.  This is T3 N2 M0.  Basically it means, there’s more than two lumps or tumours, it’s spread to 2 nodes, but it’s nowhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Doctor today reiterated what the surgeon said, which is that they are treating me with a view to curing me.  Completely destroying or removing any and all cancer that may be lurking in my body.  This is good to know that everyone is on the same page as me.  I won’t be beaten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the next step is getting the chemotherapy underway.  This could start as early as Friday.  (Private health insurance comes up trumps again).  I’ll be having a Portocath fitted which will mean the drugs go straight into a vein in my chest rather than a needle in my arms.  To be honest, I don’t care.  I just want to get cracking and get rid of this horrible disease which has turned my life upside down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still having pain in my arm and shoulder which is getting annoying now.  Wish it would give it a rest.  I’m feeling like an invalid.  And quite fragile which is increasingly annoying me.  It’s something I’m going to have to get used to as it’s going to get worse before it gets better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as Pinky told me when I bumped into her in Tesco, we need to stay positive.  I’m continuing to receive cards and messages of support, as well as hugs in supermarkets and school yards, and every single one is very much appreciated.
The phone calls to my Dad and Julie are also enormously helpful.  Talking to them helps put things in focus as it can get very blurry here at times.  Not least because I’m looking through tear filled eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scores-on-the-doors&quot;&gt;Scores on the Doors&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 13, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swear It Again]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/swear-it-again" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/swear-it-again</id>
  <published>2013-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I also quite like Westlife, which I realise makes me a sad human being, but I don’t actually care.  They had a hit with a song called “Swear it Again”.  Well I’ve been swearing again, and again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been to the hospital today to get the results of my Lymph Node Biopsy.  It’s not the result we wanted.  The surgeon took out 3 initial nodes, and decided to take out 5 more whilst he was there.  Two of the initial three turned out to be cancerous.  The other five were clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now we know what the next step is.  I see a Oncologist tomorrow to discuss the best way to get the chemotherapy started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll return to the surgeon in March for the mastectomy and further lymph node surgery.  Then it’ll be the Herceptin treatment, maybe radiotherapy, and after that it’ll be the reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m swearing…alot.  It wasn’t supposed to have spread.  It wasn’t supposed to be me, and I’m really, really angry.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/swear-it-again&quot;&gt;Swear It Again&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 12, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The next path]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-long-day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-long-day</id>
  <published>2013-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I hate the wait, I like to be proactive, so today the results are in and I
want to know what we are facing. I want it to be good news and I want to get
started.  It didn’t work out as planned but we are another step on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today has had highlights, its not all maudlin and dolldrums for Julia and myself.
We’ve both been working from the kitchen table and that’s nice.  We’ve got lots
done and get insights about each others working day.  YouTube yielded some great
retro soul and old skool hip hop tunes, and we chair dance too.  We also took
Merlin for a walk around the garden in his kitten harness during one coffee break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon its time to go and we head off to the hospital.  I have my questions and
we’ll get answers.  We get there and we wait, standard hospital stuff. I’m
nervous as hell, so god knows how Julia felt as we waited.  We get called in to the Consultant and
there’s no messing. It’s spread. Shit.  But as soon as that’s said there’s good news
too.  He took 3 nodes and 2 looked “wrong”, so he sent them off and then took
a further 5 and sent them off seperately.  No wonder she’s been in pain.  The maximum they told us they’d take out was 5.  The two that looked wrong had cancer
but all the others were clear.  Thank f*ck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it changed much in terms of the treatment but we learnt more about
timelines and the future.  Chemo will start soon, we are seeing the clinical
onthologist tomorrow, so we’ll learn more about that.  One thing I’ve
realised is it will probably take time, there’s probably more to it than
just getting an appointment and rocking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, thats the next path we’ll go down, its time to go give Julia another hug.
Lord knows she needs them. Lots of them.  And I can do that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-long-day&quot;&gt;The next path&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 12, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Names]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/names" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/names</id>
  <published>2013-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I received a letter today confirming in writing that I have Invasive Ductal Carcinoma in two different places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously we’ve known I have cancer, but this is the type of cancer it is.  It gives it a name.  The good news is that it’s the most common sort of breast cancer, so they should know how to treat it.  The next thing we need to know us the stage and grade.  We may find that out tomorrow when we go to the see the Consultant, but I have a feeling they won’t know the whole sorry story until after I’ve had my mastectomy and they get a chance to examine it fully in a lab somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news I went to the doctors to sort out a repeat prescription for the anti-cancer drugs I’ll be talking for the next 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also ordered a new mattress.  The one we have is 11 years old and very lumpy.  So we decided that as I’m probably going to be spending quite a while in bed over the next few months, I might as well be comfy.  It gets delivered on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A kindly neighbour dropped round with some apple cake too.  It seems word is getting round in the street we’ve been living in for 2 and half months. She was very kind and said all the right things.  We are lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/names&quot;&gt;Names&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 11, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharks and Mermaids]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sharks-and-mermaids" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sharks-and-mermaids</id>
  <published>2013-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The arm on the side I had the operation on is still giving me significant pain.  This is in no small part due to sleeping on it on Friday night. I woke up on Saturday morning in tears as it was on fire.  I dosed up on my full contingent of painkillers, and stayed in bed for the majority of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was our very good friends, Adam and Heather’s, wedding party at the pub round the cornering in the evening.  We’d waited so long to go to it, that I was determined to show my face, even for a short time.  I’m glad I did.  Everyone was very complimentary about my new short hair, and I got lots of Gin Club Dad hugs when I tried to slope of early.  (I’m usually one of the last ones standing, so it was very odd to be the first of our group to leave!) Ross walked me home and but went back to join the matrimonial celebrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning arrives, and it’s clear Ross had enjoyed himself. (Read raging hangover).
So, I rally the troops, bite the bullet and drive the bairns to their swimming lessons leaving Ross in bed. I haven’t driven since the operation and needed to do a short drive to check whether a 30 minute drive to work was feasible.  It’s not.  I’ll be working from home tomorrow and Tuesday at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix enjoys his swimming lessons very much and always works hard.  There were only three in his class today, and obviously I’m biased but he was so much better than the other two.  The teacher was in agreement as when the lesson finished he was given a slip of paper to move up to the next class.  He’d only been in stage 3 lessons for 6 weeks.  So proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two minutes silence were observed at the swimming pool at the end of their lessons and when Imogen finished her lesson, she produced a slip.  She’s moved up to Stage 6.  I’m so proud of her too.  She’s worked very hard to get her breast stroke right so she can move up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the proud owner of a Shark and a Mermaid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I come back home to find Ross has got up and is resembling a human being. A quick chat, and I return to bed.  I nap most of the afternoon.  I’m wondering if the sleeping that I’m doing is a coping mechanism, a reaction to the anaesthetic, a symptom of the cancer or something else.  I just know I need a lot of it at the minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it’s back to work tomorrow, albeit at home, and an appointment with the consultant on Tuesday afternoon.  This is the appointment when I find out just how and when they are going to take me apart before they put me back together again.  I’d be lying if I said I wasn’t scared.  My life is dependent of them getting this right.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sharks-and-mermaids&quot;&gt;Sharks and Mermaids&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 10, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A well earned hangover]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-well-earned-hangover" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-well-earned-hangover</id>
  <published>2013-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I rub Julia’s shoulder but it seems that she’s done herself a mischief whilst
asleep and pulled the stitches.  It’s painkillers and bed for her this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen helps by coming with me to take Merlin to the vet, a jab and microchip
later and he’s nearly ready to go outside.  The vet reckons to give a week and
praises Merlin for being a rounded cat, the needle for the chip was massive and
he just gave a miaow as it happend.  The vet also thinks 7 year old girls are
the best thing for cats to make them domesticated.  Luckily, we have one of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get home and Julia is in the bath, she’s in tears because she’s reading
“The Cancer Journey” its about staying postive, conquering fear and staying
healthy.  The prospect of chemotherapy is shit scary and Julia has been so
brave for the last few weeks it briefly becomes overwhelming.  I hug her and
tell her I’m there every step of the way and we’ll get through it together.
When things become massive and overwhelming we have to take things one day at a
time.  The big picture can be soo frightening its incomprehensable.
The conversation crashes like a stormy sea around my head all day - advice is
easy to give and hard to take it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask Imogen to keep and eye on Mummy and give her hugs if needed and I take
Felix to little ruggers.  Felix loves little ruggers and I spent the time talking
geek to another dad.  In the afternoon, I notice the garage roof is more banjaxed
than previously thought. Water is leaking into the garage and down the brick work
outside. I phone and book some builders to come round and give us quotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening it’s Adam and Heathers wedding celebration, Julia and I have been
looking forward to this for ages!  The baby sitter arrives and Julia and I
practically skip to the pub.  Its a great night, Julia enjoyed it but left early,
I walked her home and then headed back. I drank a lot and probably was
dismal, self-absorbed company, hopefully not too much.  Adam and Heather - thank you
for letting me bend your ears at the end of the night, it was good therapy and sorry
for doing so at your wedding celebration (timing is not my strong point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning arrives all too quickly and I’ve won myself an epic hangover.
It’s painkillers and bed for me this morning.  Julia is determined that Felix
and Imogen go to swimming, so gets up and drives them. I’m pleased she does
as my two fishes both move up a level!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not at my best and take the morning off and then swap with Julia for the
afternoon and she goes to bed.  I pump up a rugby ball and take the kids out.  We pass the ball in
line and do some kicks.  The weather is good, sunny and fresh and the autumn
leaves look especially good this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its been a heck of a few weeks and all eyes are now on Tuesday, to some extent
we’ll be treading water until we see the consultant.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-well-earned-hangover&quot;&gt;A well earned hangover&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 10, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fairly normal day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fairly-normal" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fairly-normal</id>
  <published>2013-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After sorting the laundry ready so that we could get a load on as soon as the new washing machine was installed, I walked the bairns to school.  It took us a bit longer than normal, as I wasn’t able to move fast, and despite leaving 5 minutes earlier we still only just made it when the bell rang.  But we made it, and after quick (and hard fought from Boy Child) kisses, they were in and ready to learn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met up with the Gin Club at Michelle’s which was great.  It’s the first time I’ve had a chance to discuss things fully with them, and it was just the tonic I needed.  It was also lovely to see the two smiley babies, and the brand new Joni!  In all the mental ness that has enveloped the Lawley’s in the past few weeks, it’s good to remember that life goes on around us, and others have their own battles to fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left early as I was tired and came home to find the washing machine being installed.  Great news.  Once it was in, Ross and I had a cursory look at the instructions, loaded it up and started as we meant to go on.  I then took myself off to bed as I was tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I woke up it was time to got to the hairdressers. I’d decided with everything going on, I might as well get my hair cut short so it’s one less thing to worry about.  Izzy, my hairdresser, was great.  There were a few tears but I reiterated that this Cancer will not beat me, and it’s just a chapter in my life.  And I now have new hair!  It’s lush.  Thanks Iz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, at school pickup time, it was tipping it down.  Ross collected Imogen and I waited for Felix.  As I was waited, Imogen came towards me with her classmate Norah who handed me a gift bag.  I thanked her for it, I was so touched and surprised that she would want to give me something.  I got home and opened it, and it was bubble bath and a card.  It said she had chosen and bought it herself and that she hoped it would help me through my treatment.  Tears. Fat tears.  What an amazing little girl.  So compassionate.  I’m getting tearful just writing about it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way out of the school yard, Imogen asked if I’d like to talk to her teacher.  I wasn’t sure why she hadn’t asked Ross to do this, but as she was keen, I went.  I was told that I should be proud and pleased with Imogen this week.  She’d been really engaged, keen and hard-working.  I am proud of her.  She’s taken a pretty rubbish situation and turned it to around into something positive.  She’s awesome, and I’m lucky that I’m her Mummy.  Something I keep reminding both her and Felix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got home and dry we just sat, watched tv and relaxed.  The kids kept cuddling me, with Felix making sure he knew which was my sore arm so he could cuddle the other side so as not to hurt me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before long it was off to Imogen’s gymnastics with the promise of fish and chips or curry afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fairly-normal&quot;&gt;A fairly normal day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 08, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A clean sheet]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clean-sheet" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clean-sheet</id>
  <published>2013-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve slept well the last few days so can’t complain.  This stress does wierd
things - for one I’ve lost my thirst for beer at home.
For the past two nights I really wanted a beer, yet could only manage 1/2 a pint
and had to throw the rest down the drain - weird and worrying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lie in bed wondering why I’m awake and I realise that
I feel bad about the ear bashing that we had given John Lewis Customer Services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to make good I decided I’d turn it round and I started drafting an email
in my head and I decided to get up and write it down before I forgot it.  Being
the procrastinator that I am, I started drafting this blog post first! Well
I read this post first: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rats-funnybone.com/25-funny-auto-correct-fails/&quot;&gt;25 auto correct fails&lt;/a&gt; I saw it on facebook and it brightened my morning considerably!  Here’s
my email to John Lewis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hi Aimée,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thank you so much for getting the
washing machine and tumble dryer delivered. You have single handedly restored
our faith in John Lewis.  Our thanks also
go out to those others in the background who made this happen.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Julia and I are both 36 and we have two children Imogen, 7 and Felix, 5.  Three
weeks ago after 5 months of back and forth with the NHS Julia was diagnosed
with breast cancer. These have been the most stressful and emotionally turbulent
3 weeks of our lives. In preparation for the hard times to come Julia put me in
charge of the laundry, the day after we ordered the washing machine our own
washing machine took umbrage and broke down completely.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've been thinking (I awoke at 4:30am thinking about this) and would like, if
possible to ask two things from John Lewis:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
1. Julia dropped quite a bombshell on your colleague in the call center (I think
her name was Karen). It can't have made her day to have someone crying on the
phone whilst describing our situation, and although she couldn't help us
speed things up, she was kind and tried to help.  Please make sure she is ok.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
2. Compensation.  We don't want any, we have a working washing machine and would
much rather John Lewis donate any compensation you would have given to us to
charity.  Julia has run 7 Race For Life's and never thought she would be running
her own personal race this year. She is determined to get round the Race For Life
next year. If you could donate the money to a cancer charity, I'm sure they
would be grateful - as would we.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As part of our journey and as some form of therapy we are blogging our journey
at http://teamrj.co.uk and I'd like your permission to post any response there.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yours sincerely,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The Lawleys
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I got a fantastic response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hi Ross,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thank you for your email and your kind words, your thanks are truly appreciated by myself and the others who have assisted me. It really has been a pleasure getting this issue resolved, you have been patient and courteous in allowing me time to get things done.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think it is a beautiful gesture and would be happy to offer a donation to a charity of your choice. I would like to offer £100 which I know your chosen charity will put to great use. ...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I honestly can't imagine the stress you and your family have been under lately and I am genuinely sorry that John Lewis has contributed to this. I would like to offer my best wishes to you all and I hope that you succeed in your new role as the chief laundry man.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You may share your experience in your blog, you have my absolute permission. This is a wonderful idea and as you say a great form of therapy. I hope Julia enjoys the Race for Life, I'm sure she will do herself and everyone proud.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Kind regards,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Aimée
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So John Lewis have made good, the washing machine has arrived, been installed and
is working nicely. Whats more the tumble dryer has been installed in the
conservatory - a revelation!  Glad thats all sorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At lunchtime, I took Julia to have her hair cut and now it’s short, quite like
it was when we first met - she looks gorgeous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen sees my old award (if you can call it that) in the study. It’s a picture of
me when I was 8, I had just been gunged by the Hash House Harriers in Riyadh.
It’s titled “Ross Lawley the biggest little shit” - Imogen struggles with the
last word, then repeats it 5 times “shit, shit, shit, shit, shit”.
Oh brother.  Julia is not going to be happy with me!  I have to tell Imogen
she’s not allowed to used that word as it’s a swear word and I tell her it means
“poo”.  Imogen runs downstairs to tell mummy, “daddy &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; the biggest little poo
you know”.  What can you do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This evening, its been Imogen’s gymnastics and then a curry - all good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signing off for now - Chief Laundry Man&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clean-sheet&quot;&gt;A clean sheet&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 08, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Scans]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/more-scans" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/more-scans</id>
  <published>2013-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to be having a new washing machine delivered between 2pm and 9pm.  It was getting quite desperate as Felix had wet the bed, and anyone with a family knows, it just keeps multiplying!  So I rang then at about 5:30pm for an eta only to find they had no record of the delivery. It had been arranged for Monday, but as I had my operation, I had rung to reschedule.  Only half that happened.  They cancelled Monday but didn’t rebook.  I was told they’d ring me from the distribution centre to rearrange.  We didn’t expect to hear anything that evening so carried on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday morning, I needed to go back to Harpenden for a MRI scan.  We got there a bit early, so took the opportunity to ring them again and find out what was going on.  I let Ross take over.  I couldn’t deal with that as well.  After a while of going backwards and forwards they said they needed to speak to me as I’d placed the order.  They then told me the next available delivery was the 15th Nov.  I’m afraid I lost it.  I said something along the lines of “no, I need it sooner than that.  I have breast cancer, I have a 5 year old son who is wetting the bed with worry, and I have washing mounting up.  This needs to be sorted.”  I might have cried a bit too.  She then said she’d get back to me to which I responded “you’ll have to talk to my husband as I have an MRI Scan”.  I wasn’t very kind, and feel a bit bad about it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while later, I was attached to a drip and lying face down in a very, very noisy tunnel.  There was supposed to be music to take the edge off, but I couldn’t hear it for the horrid buzzing.  I don’t know how long I was in there, but it seemed forever.  I felt faint and dizzy when I came out so they gave me coffee and biscuits to give me a boost before they let me go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came home, had lunch and a quick nap, and then it was off to my Asthma review and to get my flu jab.  The idea is to have me on top form healthwise with everything else for when the big things start kicking in.  That all done, it was back home, and into bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave Ross to update on the washing machine.  I’m too tired.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/more-scans&quot;&gt;More Scans&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 07, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A bucket full of washing]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-bucket-full-of-washing" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-bucket-full-of-washing</id>
  <published>2013-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m quite knackered at the moment, so in the morning I watched a video about
a new way to abstract code in Scala, fascinating stuff for me but probably not for you.
I also did the walk of shame and finally went to the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the gym they punish you for absence by deactivating your gym machine key
and then making you explain yourself to the personal trainer.  Promises of better
attendance did the trick and I chucked some weights about for forty minutes.
The knee I knackered doing the One True Grit challenge is considerably weaker
than its counterpart and could only manage 7kg leg extensions, compared to
22.5kg - so some work to do there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon it was more coding and video hangout meetings with colleagues.
At 5:30pm Julia comes into the study (mid meeting) to tell me the washing machine
isn’t coming. The washing has been steadily breeding and what was a small pile
is now a mountain.  She’s not happy, I’m not happy and seemingly John Lewis isn’t
happy but as the depot centre is having technical problems they can’t reschedule
at the moment. We chose John Lewis because we didn’t want to be dicked about -
we could have gone to Currys for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s another scan day, so we drive back to Spire Harpenden for 9:30am.  We arrive early, so
Julia suggests we chill in the car for a bit. I call John Lewis to ask about
the whereabouts of the washing machine. I make
it clear I’m not happy and they go away and find out what’s what.  Then they can’t
speak to me about the new delivery date as Julia ordered it - data protection
and all that. They tell Julia the next they can deliver is in 8 days time, Julia
responds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Thats just not good enough, I have breast cancer, a 5 year old son who is
so worried he has started wetting the bed and &lt;strong&gt;no washing machine&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s had enough of them and tells them to speak to me as she has to go into the
hospital for her scan. It’s a bit of a bombshell to drop on the customer service
lady and she promises to do her best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They call back telling me that 8 days time is the quickest they can deliver. I
flip and even offer to pick up a machine from a local store:
&lt;strong&gt;I just need an f’ing washing machine&lt;/strong&gt;. She says she’ll callback.
Well this is getting us nowhere fast - time to publicly shame them and use twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appalled by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johnlewisretail&quot;&gt;@johnlewisretail&lt;/a&gt; now without a washing machine. wife has cancer, son wetting bed with worry and the best new delivery is 8 days&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ross Lawley (@RossC0) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RossC0/statuses/398385647305887744&quot;&gt;November 7, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask my colleagues to retweet and I get a response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RossC0&quot;&gt;@RossC0&lt;/a&gt; Extremely concerned to read your tweet. Please: email_us@johnlewis.co.uk with your details and I will assist. Thank you, Aimee.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; John Lewis (@JLcustserv) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JLcustserv/statuses/398387106839408640&quot;&gt;November 7, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a call from the customer service lady saying there is no stock locally, so
they can’t deliver the washing machine and tumble dryer until the 15th November
and that she is very sorry but theres nothing else she can do.
I’m so pissed off I can’t agree to that, so I emailed Aimee and she promised to
sort it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few calls and emails later and the
washing machine and tumble dryer will be delivered and installed at 10am tomorrow
morning. &lt;strong&gt;Result!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the f*ck I had to call them to find out how they were
going to sort it and why someone inside John Lewis cancelled
yesterdays delivery for no reason and why I had to resort to naming and shaming
them in publicly, I don’t know.  But I do know that twitter is &lt;strong&gt;the
best way&lt;/strong&gt; to get action from complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aimee is even sending Felix a parcel as good will gesture and once its installed
they’ll look to compensate Julia for the stress caused. So lets hope it all
arrives nicely tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time for a beer, cheers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-bucket-full-of-washing&quot;&gt;A bucket full of washing&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 07, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spires and Surgery]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/spires-and-surgery" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/spires-and-surgery</id>
  <published>2013-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s Monday and I’m back at work for the first time since finding out. I have
questions about this: would I be able to do &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; work? Has my concentration
gone? I needn’t have worried as I’m one of those lucky souls who loves his job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start with the usual Monday morning meeting, which for me is a video hangout with the
rest of the EMEA drivers team.  We’re a diverse bunch, based across Europe
and its good to catch up and get some normality back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was going to be sitting in a hospital for a long time, I needed some offline
work to get on with.  Happily, it was the start of a
new programming course I’d signed up for on &lt;a href=&quot;http://coursera.org/&quot;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; (
if you haven’t checked out Coursera do – there’s awesome free online courses on all
manner of subjects).  So I downloaded this weeks lectures and assignments to keep me
busy at the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drive is nice, although annoyingly there’s a love of speed bumps on hills near
Harpenden.  The Spire hospital is really nice, staff friendly
and as in common with all hospitals time moves at a different pace. We arrive
on time for 12pm but Julia’s surgery didn’t take place until after 3pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I manage to grab some crisps and chocolate for lunch, Julia is annoyed
because she is nil by mouth.  She gets her own back later by having dinner post
op, something I missed out on. In fact she practically rubs my nose in it by
making me see it twice - bleurgh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia’s operation goes well but she comes out looking green gilled. So much so
one doctor practically panics when he sees her and has to be “shooed” out the room by
a nurse.  A quick red cell count and blood pressure check determines her fit,
although nauseous from the anesthetic and operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes some time to persuade them to discharge her, they would have
preferred her to stay in but there’s no place like home and as the anesthetist joked
you can just as easily feel nauseous there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clair was great looking after the kids - thank you and we finally made it
home for 10pm.  Julia celebrates by being sick again and I get her to bed.
She has nothing to worry about tomorrow and can stay in bed resting all day.
All of which doesn’t explain why she woke me up at 4:30am by trying to read her iPad
under the covers! I may have swore but this is how things are now,
suddenly you go from fast asleep to wide awake for no apparent reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed they don’t find anything - we’ll find out next Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/spires-and-surgery&quot;&gt;Spires and Surgery&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 05, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fireworks]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fireworks" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fireworks</id>
  <published>2013-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I had my Sentinel Node Biopsy.  It was to check whether the cancer has spread to my lymph nodes.  Scans suggest that it hasn’t, but they needed to do this to be sure.   The operation involved having a dye injected and then any lymph nodes dyed blue removed through an insertion into my armpit.  All done under general anaesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yesterday morning, the bairns went back to school after their half term break,  whilst I got things ready here.  I made a quick dash for new pj’s, dressing gown and slippers, drop the house key off to Clairs, and then we were off to the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This operation was done  using Ross’s health insurance, so we had to go to Harpenden, a bit of a trek, but we had private room.  This meant Ross was able to crack on and get some work done.  Odd, you might think, but it’s his way of keeping busy, and relaxed.  And he was right beside me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After waiting a couple of hours, I was whisked off to theatre, wearing full length surgical stockings, hospital knickers and gown.  I looked a treat!  Two hours later I was coming round in recovery with a lot of pain in my arm pit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m eventually wheeled back round to my room, where Ross is waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to do three things before they will let me leave.  Drink, eat, and wee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First one was fine.  Drink.  Done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I was presented with soup, a sarnie, ice cream and juice.  Unfortunately I was feeling very woosey, clammy and a bit sick.  So, I dozed.  The soup went cold, the ice cream melted.  The nurse came in and I asked for something to help me stop feeling sick.  She agreed, although a doctor came in and was a bit shocked at my pallor.  Apparently it was akin to corpse or vampire.  He wanted to do blood tests, but the nurse ushered him out and said she’d do it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were starting to mention keeping me in over night.  Time was marching on but I didn’t want that to happen.  I wanted to be back in my own bed with my family there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sickness drug worked, I ate the sarnie, and I was gearing up for a wee.  This had to be supervised by a nurse as I was still hooked up to a drip and they needed to check I was ok getting up after the anaesthetic.  So, buzzer pressed for wee supervision, I feel sick again.  And throw up all the painkillers, sarnie, water etc, I’d been so desperately trying to keep down.  On a side point, the blue dye they had used earlier had turned my sick a greeny, blue colour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurse comes in again, and suggests strongly I stay in over night.  I’m determined not to, so oblige with a (blue) wee, and after taking my blood count (12.1), she relents and signs the papers to let me go.  Yay!  A quick trip in a wheelchair to the car and we are homeward bound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clair had brought the bairns home, done homework with them, played disney infinity and then put them to bed.  This was a relief to Ross and I to know they were safe and well cared for, and am very thankful to her.  I snuck in to give my babies kisses whilst they sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sick again before I went to bed, but at least I was in my own bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen and Felix gave me hugs this morning and I showed them what I’d had one and why we needed to be careful with my left arm.  Imogen gave me a card she’d made with her head teacher, Mrs Summerhayes.  Apparently, Imogen had been feeling a bit anxious around lunchtime when she knew I’d be off to the hospital and had asked her teacher for time out with Mrs Summerhayes.  It’s nice to know the school are being understanding and empathetic to her.  She needs it, she’s a delicate flower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m staying in bed today.  I’ll get up for nourishment, but I’m still feeling sick and in pain.  I must make sure I do my arm exercises to make sure the wound doesn’t heal and scar tight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a long line of operations and treatments, but it’s done.  One down, plenty more to go.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fireworks&quot;&gt;Fireworks&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 05, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trick or Treat]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/trick-or-treat" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/trick-or-treat</id>
  <published>2013-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the
alarm goes off at 5.10 I have no idea where I am or who I am - but its time to
load the car. Once we’re nearly ready I wake Imogen, who jumps out of bed saying
“Finally, I’ve been waiting all night!” - Felix was less pleased to be woken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We flew up the A1 only hindered by Lorries playing the overtaking game. The one
where they swing out into the fast lane and then try to overtake the Lorry in
front as slowly as possible. We get to the grandparents, help set up a Halloween
party and I have a beer.  Grandma Julie has been looking forward to Halloween
and made it really special for the kids - thank you Grandma!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family come round for the party. I’ve noticed Julia is taking on a role
of being strong when friends / family cry.  This warms me as it is a sign of Julia’s
inner strength and character that I’m so in love with.  There’s lots of
“I’m not dead you know”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uncle Callums pumpkins are amazing, people even had their photo taken with them
when trick or treating us.  Imogen &amp;amp; Felix &lt;strong&gt;loved&lt;/strong&gt; trick or treating. After a nervous start Felix
really got into it, I think he would have happily knocked on every door in
Cullercoats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning Grandma Julie, the kids and I walked Uncle Regans and Grandma
Lindas dogs - that sounds way more complicated that it was. Apart from missing
a massive sign saying park closed - we enjoyed the walk in the park, funnily enough
it was nice and quiet. Julia stayed home and slept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we head to see Grandma Ursula. When talking in the car, we tell
Imogen to help with the “I’m not dead” line and she practices. Felix reacts to it, he
was in a mood anyhow but grunts when she says it. Its becoming obvious that he will
need some help to communicate his feelings - he’s very young and it is impacting
him more than we initially thought. We’ll have to work on being extra understanding
with Felix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia sleeps a lot today, the fatigue worries me but its also a way for her to
charge batteries and prepare for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we have an epic roast and beers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;saturday&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off into town to see Newcastle play Chelsea! Granddad Mikie and myself get to go
to the match whilst the other (better?) halves and kids go shopping.  We got the
best deal!  Before the match we all head into Krispy Kremes for doughnuts and coffee.
Group wide chronic indecision about what people want to order hits, its too painful
I had to escape and take Felix to the loo.  There is such a thing as too
much choice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The match was awesome, the first half pretty dull and the crowd was nervous.  But
it the second half Newcastle were attacking the Gallowgate End and the crowd lifted
the team and practically willed the ball into the back of the next. I jumped and
cheered like a loon when the first goal went in.  We went expecting defeat and
came out winners - a brilliant way to spend an afternoon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the match we swung by Regan &amp;amp; Lornas new house, not sure I could have
taken on such a massive project but they’ll get a home exactly as they want it.
The house has been gutted and there’s still a mountain of work to do but from now
on it’ll come together and its going to look fantastic once done.  Looking forward
to seeing it done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sunday&quot;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pop by Julia’s brothers before heading home.  The drive is long and moods
are low when we get home.  Imogen and Felix got bored in the car and fought
over the no mans land of the middle seat.  No one helps get anything in from
the car and I get grumpy. That evening Felix is extremely rude again to
mummy. I’m really not happy with about it and react.  Once
tempers have cooled and we’ve discussed the whys and how we should have dwelt
with it, we hug and Felix and I become friends again. I think the nerves about
tomorrows operation and cancer in general are leaking out and we must come
closer as a family to get through it and remember &lt;strong&gt;we are a team&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/trick-or-treat&quot;&gt;Trick or Treat&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 03, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>