<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2016-01-31T11:48:12+00:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relinquishing Control]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Relinquishing-Control" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Relinquishing-Control</id>
  <published>2016-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I have my own ways of doing things.  &lt;p&gt;Whether that be the order the laundry goes on, where the beans are kept in the cupboard, what to buy for the Bairn’s friends birthday presents etc, or which is the best toothpaste, meal planning.  I decide.  It’s all worked well.  Everyone knows what to expect as “if Mamma’s happy, everybody’s happy”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I’m having to give up on that control bit by bit.  Yesterday on the way back from Felix’s swimming lesson, Ross, my Dad and Felix were told to get a birthday present for Imy’s friend, Iris, and I had asked Ross to get me some sort of receptacle to store the things that I needed on my bedside table.&lt;br /&gt;
I’m not sure exactly what went on, but the outcome was a success.  Asking Felix to choose something a girl a year older than him caused him some confusion, my Dad just left the shop unwilling to take any responsibility for the decisions being made, but Ross rose to the challenge and surpassed himself.  He’s amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’d organised my bedside table with said new receptacle, I spoke to Max and he suggested I try one of the fancy candles he’d sent me in his Care Package.  Unfortunately the stupid cat decided at that moment she needed to be on the windowsill exactly where the candle was.  Candle tipped up, freaked out cat, wax everywhere.  Me in tears, Imy in tears, but no real harm done.  Imy went off to get a more substantial candle jar to put it in and with the help from some huggles and some Oramorph, things settled down again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Care Packages have been great fully received.  They are all very different, thoughtful, and put together with love, kindness and generosity.  Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also thank you for the hugs and messages of support.  I appreciate getting messages or texts (so don’t start the message off by saying, “I hope you don’t mind…”),  as I can read and respond to them as and when I am ready.  I’m a bit funny when it comes to actually talking on the phone though.  So, if you do ring and I don’t answer, leave a message.  I’m probably hiding behind a cushion what the drama is call about!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Relinquishing-Control&quot;&gt;Relinquishing Control&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 31, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tea, Crafts, Drugs and Class Assembly]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/teas-crafts" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/teas-crafts</id>
  <published>2016-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Anyone who knows me, knows I drink coffee.&lt;p&gt;I drink proper, dripped, strong coffee - I don’t drink tea.  Coffee that is strong enough to stand your spoon up in it.   Don’t talk to me until I’ve had at least one cup in the morning.  It’s not worth it.  Come 1pm, I’m coffee’d out and will switch to squash.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except something strange has happened.  I will have a cup of coffee with breakfast, but after that, I will have a cup of fruit tea.  From a bone china cup and saucer. (Specifically an MG cup and saucer I won in a school raffle about 6 years ago.)  Or, if it’s bedtime, a cup of camomile tea in by bone china  Kate and William Royal Wedding mug (I love twee).  It’s all a bit bizarre!  I don’t know what has changed, but I can’t drink coffee the way I used to!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep my mind off the recent craziness, on Thursday, Pinky came round to show me how to crochet.  We drank fruit tea from china cups, chatted about nothing and everything, and managed to make a start with a hook and wool.  She’ll have to come back so we can do it again.  I’m determined to be able to crochet a Granny Square, and maybe even a Remembrance Day Poppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst all this tea is being drunk, arrangements are being made for me to have samples taken from my spine next week.  This is to check that the treatment plan they have lined up to use is the best one for me.  I had received a letter that tells me I have to be nil by mouth from midnight the night before the procedure.  This worries me, if my pain levels aren’t under control, I won’t be able to get to the hospital in the first place, never mind have samples taken.  Fortunately, I speak to a very knowledgeable and understanding pre-op nurse who guides me through what I can and can’t take on the morning of the procedure and I feel calmer.  We can do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday morning, Tash popped in for a quick cup of fruit tea in a china cup, and after a quick nap, I decided that I felt well enough to go and watch Felix’s Jungle Class Assembly with Ross and my Dad.  The school have been brilliant and said we can park within the grounds when we need to, which makes things so much easier.  It was still a long walk to the school hall, and I had sweat dripping off me throughout the assembly, but the kids were great.  Lots of singing, information and funky dancing.   My walking stick seemed to cause a bit of cause stir with the kids.  “Why’s your Mum got a stick, Felix?”.  He turns, shrugs, “Cancer’s spread”.  Heartbreaking.  He shouldn’t have to say words like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke to as few School Mum’s who I hadn’t seen in a while.  It’s good to catch up on other people’s news, remind myself that there are other things going on.  Good things are going on.  Happy things are going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The busy day had taken it’s toll on me, and I was in bed by 5:30pm.  Luckily I have alarms set to wake me up to take my medication.  I’d be in all sorts trouble if I missed therm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so it continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/teas-crafts&quot;&gt;Tea, Crafts, Drugs and Class Assembly&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 29, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's 4am]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/4am" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/4am</id>
  <published>2016-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Here I am, awake and waiting for the painkillers to kick in.  It&#39;s all getting very tiresome.&lt;p&gt;Sunday and Monday ended up as quiet days, and they were good days.  I like quiet, calm days.  Imy needed some persuasion to get to school, but she’d had a good chat with a key worker and seemed happier on her return home.  We are finding her more emotional than normal, but all we can do is make sure she knows she is loved and supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday arrived, and we were up and at ‘em early to get the kids dropped off at school and then us off to the hospital to get my port reinserted.  I had been hoped they’d knock me out for it, but due to the cocktail of drugs I’m already taking, they just gave me a little bit of sedation, local anesthetic, and 30 minutes later, I was back in my room watching the end of Bargain Hunt with Ross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I’d been in theatre, Ross had spoken to my GP to get my pain meds tweaked.  The levels just weren’t quite right and I was finding it difficult to keep under control.  Between them, they came up with a plan, and I’ll be able to function with some level of normality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit later on I got a message that my Dad had arrived at ours, so the kids would be collected from school with no fuss or drama.  Tea was made for them, and they were taken to after school activities once their homework had been completed.  I think my Dad was a bit shocked in the difference between me since the last saw me at Christmas. A month ago, I was just normal little me.  Getting on with life.  Now I’m discussing adapting my way of living to make things easier for me and those around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I need to look into quickly though is getting a Blue Badge.  I can’t walk far, I’m using a stick and trying to do normal stuff is becoming more problematic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m getting my first dose of Herceptin today, as well as a bone strengthener.  A long dull day in hospital but a positive step to giving this horrible disease its marching orders again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Just a little note to say thank you to everyone who has sent a care package.  Large or small, edible or not, even the messages, emails, texts and calls.  They are all appreciated and make me feel like I’ve got an army of supporters helping me walk along the road I need to travel.  It’s not too much fun at the minute, but it won’t all be doom and gloom either.  I can’t live like that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/4am&quot;&gt;It's 4am&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 26, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Pain!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the%20pain" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the pain</id>
  <published>2016-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Things are starting to get harder for me.&lt;p&gt;I’m finding it harder to walk any great distance.  School runs are out.  I can’t drive due to the meds and keeping comfortable for any length of time is a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday night, I’d woken up as usual at 5am in discomfort.  By the time I’d been to the loo, things had reached a peak and I was crying and screaming in pain.  It took 10 minutes to get the level 10 pain down to a still very Hurty 8 pain.  Unfortunately I’d woken Imy up and she got rather distressed with the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross took the kids to rugby to allow them some normality, and Charli came round to keep me company and make sure the pain remained under control.  It was very much appreciated and kept me occupied enough to get through the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Ross came back, he went to Tesco for some supplies.  These included a shower chair, a coccyx cushion, a wall handle for the bathroom and a walking stick.  This has really upset me as walking sticks are for old people. I’m only 38.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to get some much needed relief by lying on the floor in the front room. Obviously it’s a bit of a pain for the rest of the family, but they’ll have to get used to it.  Imy has asked if it’s likely that I’ll wake up crying in the night again.  I hope not.  It’s not pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the%20pain&quot;&gt;The Pain!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 25, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Singing through the pain]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-through-the%20pain" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-through-the pain</id>
  <published>2016-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The phone has been ringing a lot at our house recently.&lt;p&gt;It’ll be the doctor, the chemo ward, the insurance company. All giving me information, updates and appointments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To distract myself, on Wednesday, Tash drove me to choir so I could sing. I’m so glad she did. When I got my primary diagnosis I promised myself I’d start to do things I had been putting off. The first one of those things was to join a choir. Luckily, one had started up a month or so before locally in Baldock, so I put my big girl pants on, and went along. I’ve loved it all. I’ve met some truly lovely people and learned to have confidence in my singing again. (I lost all confidence in my ability in my late teens and it was just something I would do in the shower. ) I’ve since sung at Christmas concerts, collaborative concerts, an open mike session and even in a group at someone’s wedding. A few people at choir already knew what was occuring thanks to the power of social media, so I got some lovely hugs and much appreciated words of encouragement. As long as I can sing, I’ll be there, with the Naughty Alto’s, having fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-organised&quot;&gt;Getting Organised&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve started to gather together paperwork so that all my financial stuff is in one place. Pensions, bank accounts, and I also set up a funeral insurance plan. Not the happiest of jobs, but I don’t want Ross to have to worry about how he’ll cope with it all. One phone call, one direct debit set up, and it was all done. We must get round to sorting our Will out too. It won’t be complicated, Ross get’s everything, and there’s not even that much of that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-looking-cancer-patient-in-hertfordshire&quot;&gt;Best Looking Cancer Patient in Hertfordshire&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to not allow standards to slip, I went to see my lovely hairdresser Isabel yesterday to get my hair cut and coloured. As it’s not been decided if I’ll be having a chemo treatment which will cause my hair to fall out or not yet, I thought I might as well start the process off looking a million dollars. If it falls out later, so be it, but for now, I’m delighted. It’s great to be able to have such trust in a hairdresser to be able to say, I want it cut and coloured - you decide what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;another-scan&quot;&gt;Another Scan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I can start treatment, I had to get a last minute appointment see a cardiologist to check my heart was well enough to withstand it. Herceptin has been shown to damage some people’s hearts to the extent where treatment has to be stopped. Luckily, my heart is in tip top condition so there’s no issue with moving onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;treatment-begins&quot;&gt;Treatment Begins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week the fun really begins. I’m having a port reinserted on Tuesday to allow for easy administration of infusions. Herceptin, the targeted treatment will start on Wednesday and I’ll also get an infusion of Zometa which will help plug the holes in my damaged vertebrae. These treatments will be every 3 weeks for as long as they continue to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad will be coming down to look after the kids for a bit whilst this is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the meantime, the flowers, gifts, chocolates and messages of support continue to come in and lift our spirits. We’re in a really tough place, but knowing we have a legion behind us, is keeping us going. Ross had to take Felix to his swimming lesson this morning, but my pain has gone up a notch, and I’m finding it hard to get comfortable. Ross wasn’t going to take Felix, but rather stay with me. He changed his mind when I told him that if anything changed, I would put a shout out and that I was confident someone would be able to come round and keep me company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;all-cancers-are-different&quot;&gt;All cancers are different&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word Cancer is an umbrella term for a wide range of diseases.  For every cell in the human body, their can be one or more associated, renegade cancer cells. There is not a “One Size Fits All” cancer diagnosis. There are also different stages and grades. Grade 1 is slow growing, Grade 3 is fast growing. Stage 1 is contained in a small place, Stage 4 for travelled. You can’t compare different cancers, it’s like comparing apples to pears.  Both fruit, both different. You can’t compare Stage 4, Grade 3 Invasive Ductal Carcinoma with Stage 3 Liver cancer. They all have different treatments, and prognosis. Everyone will also have different treatment plans too, even if they do happen to have the same diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-cure&quot;&gt;No Cure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the tough things to try and explain is that now that the cancer has come back, there is no cure. Yes, we got on top of it once, and I “beat it”, but that can’t be done this time. No amount of positive thinking, tumeric, cannabis oil or fairy dust is going to get rid of this blasted disease. It’s decided I’m a nice place to stay. (I’m not flattered about this.) The best we can hope for is that the treatment keeps it under control for a long time to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still not a fan of the battle/warrior/fighter/brave analogies. This isn’t a fight that I’ll win. It doesn’t mean I didn’t try hard enough, it means that Cancer is a horrific, destructive and merciless disease that takes no prisoners. I hate it, because it’s robbing my family of our future together. My babies deserve so much better. My husband had hoped to be married to me for a long time yet. My parents shouldn’t have to be having the conversations they are having. My brother’s shouldn’t have to face up to the loss of a sibling (even if I am the annoying, shouty, loud one). My friends may have to have some very scary conversations with their children that sometimes there is nothing you can do about an altogether horrible situation, and all you can do is offer a friendly ear, hug or word of compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-babies&quot;&gt;My Babies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side point, can I ask that my friends who know Imogen and Felix and want their children to be there for them, that they allow Imy and Felix to talk abut things on their own terms?  They don’t need to be bombarded with questions or statistics or be told how long I’m going to live for.  Can I ask that you talk to them and ask them to be compassionate and kind.  The future is very uncertain for Imy and Felix and they don’t need to have any extra or unnecessary hurt caused by someone’s lack of empathy or thinking.  When I was their age it wouldn’t even been on my radar that I could lose a parent, and it breaks my heart for them, to think that this is in their future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enough&quot;&gt;Enough!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But enough wallowing! Because at this very moment we’ve got time. For now I’ll take the hugs, and the love and support. I’ll keep on smiling, I’ll probably keep on swearing and making very inappropriate jokes. I’ll be offering hugs to people who find it frightening and scary. I’ll be the one saying “ Everything will be OK”. Because that’s me. That’s who I am. And that’s not going to change just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-through-the%20pain&quot;&gt;Singing through the pain&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 23, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Support]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/super-support" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/super-support</id>
  <published>2016-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">There&#39;s no right or wrong way to deal with life changing news, there&#39;s no rule book.&lt;p&gt;There may be some self help books, but &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; reads them just in case?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mixed-bag&quot;&gt;Mixed Bag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now the news is public, I’m not going to rehash it but in short it’s a mixed bag. Good news is it’s only in one place, so much more containable. Bad news we’re not talking cure but containment. We’re hoping for a record breaking amount of time containing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My emotions have been up and down, the metaphor I used in my head was swimming in stormy seas. Waves of grief for a future that won’t happen, sadness and worry for Julia, being scared of being alone all crashing into me. It was a rawness I’ve never felt before and I’ve glimpsed a chasm of despair that is so alien to me and my personality. It’s a worrying time to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;telling-the-world&quot;&gt;Telling the world&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had told the kids the basics in the morning, Imogen was brave and worried, Felix seemed unsure. It felt good to let them know it’s not their fault Mum and Dad have been fraught over the weekend. We have to keep them talking and let them express any worries over the coming months / years. I plan to be proactive about it but I can see it’s going to be a fine line between asking and over asking. I’ll have to stay attuned and am planning at some point making sure that they (we?) get counselling to ensure that they become the well adjusted and wonderful children that Julia and I know they will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke to the teachers at school - through sobs and asked them to look after the kids today. It was just so hard to speak about it and acknowledge it publicly. I was a mess and the teachers were kind but probably more than a little bemused and concerned. Whilst leaving the playground, I happened to bump into Rachel and then Adam and needed hugs from them both so I could compose myself - thanks you two it was much needed and much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia and I headed off to the Doctors for better meds, tears filled my eyes more than once and I realised I best to speak to one soon as well. We got more meds, a bagful, the lady at the pharmacy was kind and efficient and we headed back home. The extra meds have helped Julia get more comfortable and reach a lower number of the pain scale. It breaks my heart that even with all these meds she is still on the pain scale but I can but hope future treatment will sort that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We publish our blog posts and let the world know, Facebook is a marvelous thing at times. Julia announced the news and support, love and kind words flood in raising our spirits. I had a meltdown in the kitchen and posted my own post to facebook. The amount of support was humbling and helped my sea of anxiety soften. I took strength from the comments, encouragement and love that came through. Support has flooded in from best friends, old friends, internet wierdy friends (Julia’s terminology!) and even people we have never met or spoken to. It’s been amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hard-times-ahead&quot;&gt;Hard times ahead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of Felix’s, told him that if Julia’s cancer has comeback then she’ll be dead in five years. It’s shocking and I don’t know where a 7 year old would get that from but I can’t be angry at Felix’s friend, he’s a child just like Felix. Anyway, Felix told me he doesn’t believe it and we talked about it with Imogen on the way home from school. I couldn’t lie and tell them it definitely won’t be the case but rather, I stuck to the positives, no one knows the future and the doctors are working their hardest to do their best to contain it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Julia and I don’t know the implications of the reoccurrence of cancer, then how can the kids? We have to keep to the positives and ask the kids to be the best they can be and make sure they talk if they need to and get space when they need as well. Felix, holds his feelings closer than Imy and that night for the first time in an age he has a bed wetting accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fog-clearing&quot;&gt;Fog clearing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to see the Doctor myself yesterday, I had been feeling better or rather more on an even keel. I bumped into Pinky and that facade crumbled but it all helps - thanks for the hugs. I spoke to doctor, talked myself out of any medication but I know that they are there should they be needed. That in itself has been a big relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rawness of the initial shock seems to be leaving and I feel more positive. The insurance company are on board, which is a relief and we are starting treatment next week. I even managed to tell my colleagues at work without booing - a big improvement. The house seems to be running smoothly, chief laundry master Lawley has stepped up to the plate! Being proactive always helps me and I’m glad to say my wobbles have been further apart. I’m sure they’ll be back but with such awesome support from friends and family I know we’ll stay afloat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/super-support&quot;&gt;Super Support&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 21, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scans and Results]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scans-and-results" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scans-and-results</id>
  <published>2016-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Yesterday, we went for the final scan.&lt;p&gt;This one was to last an hour an a half, and when I came out I was a bit annoyed when they radiologist told me the results would be through in 3 days.  I had a bit of a strop and told them I was seeing the consultant that evening and he needed to report by then.  There was lots of huffing and puffing on their part and I left them to it.  In the car park on the way out, I phoned my consultant’s secretarial team and told them they might need to put some pressure on them to get the results.  These ladies are brilliant and whatever they did, it worked.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 7pm I was in the consultants office and he told me that it was indeed cancer in the vertebrae, but by some miracle that’s the only place it was.  He’s currently deciding on a treatment plan, which is likely to include a bone biopsy, cemented the vertebrae to sure it up a bit and try and avoid it collapsing, radiotherapy, possible changes to me Hormone therapy, and the likely restarting of Herceptin, which means I’ll be having a port reinserted.  The Herceptin will be every 3 weeks for the rest of my life.  There may be chemotherapy involved but that’s not definite yet.  Things are going to move quickly, I’ve just got to be ready to go where I’m told, when I’m told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this all being an awful lot to take on, we’ve got to look at the positives.  The consultant is talking in terms of years, not weeks or months.  The fact it’s only in one vertebrae is also on my side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I phoned my brothers to let them know the news.  And felt better for them to know.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been to the GP’s this morning to get some more painkillers, and more drugs to deal with the side effects of the said painkillers.  I’m also being referred to a Macmillan nurse who will help me deal with things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kids have been told, and the school is aware so that they can help them through this.  Imogen can be a delicate flower, and will no doubt need a lot of help from her friends, and adult key workers.  Felix is a very different fish, we just need to make sure he doesn’t bottle things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, once again, here we are, keeping on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scans-and-results&quot;&gt;Scans and Results&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 19, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[An unwelcome surprise]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/an-unwelcome-surprise" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/an-unwelcome-surprise</id>
  <published>2016-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s been a year since I last wrote, I was starting to believe I would only to come back to the blog as a visitor.&lt;p&gt;You’ve should have read Julia’s post so you have an idea of whats occurring, if not catch up there first. I write in this blog to help me process and connect with my feelings. It’s also been a great conduit for me and Julia to communicate our inner thoughts in a way thats less burdening than a conversation would be.
I digress…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-pain-in-the-back&quot;&gt;A pain in the back&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Julia’s had back pain and its been worse than normal. Deep down Julia knows this and calls the oncologist to discuss it. I think she’s being a drama queen and tell her off for not going to the GP first! A few of our friends also agree but Dr Shah plays it safe and orders an MRI. On &lt;em&gt;Tuesday&lt;/em&gt; we make the journey to Spire Harpenden and I can’t help be nostalgic, the journey may have been a pain in the bum but I enjoyed the time Julia and I had when she was on treatment. It was our time, it bought us closer and helped make me feel useful whilst she had her treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MRI goes swimmingly and we are a little anxious as we await the results. They gave us a dvd with the images on, how cool is that? Julia looks at it and Googles. “Is that a bulging disk?” That’ll explain it. I look through, Google MRI spine and learn about disks, vertebrae and the like. It all looks good to my untrained eye, which is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-hate-the-qe2&quot;&gt;I hate the QE2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head to the QE2 on &lt;em&gt;Wednesday&lt;/em&gt;, its been such a long time since we were last there. In fact the old hospital seems to have fallen down and a new smaller hospital sits in its shadow. Julia and I like the new QE2 it’s shiny. We potter round to the yellow zone in search of Dr Shah. Julia’s nervous, I can tell, shouldn’t I be nervous? No, it’s just muscular back pain, Julia is being a drama queen and Dr Shah moved the appointment because it was more convenient for him as he has 2 hospitals and a university to lecture at today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get called into see Dr Shah, comment on how nice the hospital is. Dr Shah cuts to the chase - he doesn’t have the images but has been told it’s cancer. My mind is slow to react, it’s like I’m watching myself, looking out of my eyes. I can’t comprehend what he just said. He’s still explaining and I see Julia shaking. How did this happen? Treatment went so well we weren’t even having scans to check. We hand over the images to Dr Shah and Julia walks him getting the program started - “it’s IT it’s what &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; do” says Julia. One vertebrae is the wrong shade of grey. Dr Shah explains that theres a 90% chance it’s cancer and tells us not to hold out for the 10%. He says we need blood tests, a CT Scan and full spinal MRI to confirm and see if its spread. He’ll sort this out and we should see him Monday evening. He says we should be prepared for a hard meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He offers the NHS’s drug cabinet to Julia and writes a big prescription. Julia’s painkiller of choice is liquid Morphine. I’m stunned and in a daze, we’re leaving his office and the news is hitting home. Its so hard and unfair, Julia is white as a sheet and shaking.  We head to the pharmacist and are told there’s a 40 minute wait as the Morphine is a controlled drug. We have a coffee and cry in the coffee shop. Julia is much better than me, more prepared and more composed. I’ve been sideswiped, I must have lied to myself as I hadn’t entertained the thought. We’ve been through so much and we were supposed to be out the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prepare-for-the-worst&quot;&gt;Prepare for the worst&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie, the next few days were hard. The hardest I’ve ever been through. My stupid imagination is relentlessly cruel and feelings hit me like waves. I’m working hard to stay afloat in this maelstrom but at times I break. Weirdly, its at odd times, a glib comment by Julia or when doing things with the kids whilst Julia rests, I ask is this how it will be in the future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia shames me with her composure, I guess the drugs are numbing her feelings also and is in a world of sadness of her own. I also know that I have to work hard get past my feelings. I’m not a strong person but I know bottling the tears is not the way, anyway I seem to have developed my own personal spring, so I can’t. Crying is sadness leaving the body and I have to prepare for the worst, just in case it comes, because if it does I have to be strong for Julia and the kids. It’s an indulgence or necessity now that I can’t take later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friends have been great in helping and offering to pick up kids and sending good wishes. We haven’t told everyone yet - we still don’t know what the answer will be. The kids are having to deal with, what must appear to them as a pair of emotionally disfunctional parents! However, they help keep spirits high with their energy and their laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insomnia&quot;&gt;Insomnia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve fallen into the habit of waking up early and not being able to go back to sleep as our minds are racing. Julia’s pain wakes her and I wake as she gets up and takes more drugs to dampen it down. Even with all the drugs she’s taking I’m concerned that she still feels pain from her back, it might fade to the background but its still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My head is not in the right place to do any coding, so I tell work whats happening and that I will report in on Tuesday when we have the answers about her back. Work again have been brilliant, allowing me to take time and wishing us the best. I’m so grateful to be working for them, in so many ways they’ve been brilliant through this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weekend&quot;&gt;Weekend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday, comes and its CT Scan day, but first some of Julia’s friends are keen to see her in person and Julia invites them round for coffee after the school drop off. We bump into Neil and its good to see him up and about after a rather nasty chest infection. Neil, asks what folks are doing and I invite him for coffee. We chat, he asks after Julia and I mention her back and then choke. For a few moments I can’t speak and tears well. Eventually, I get the words out and he’s shocked by the news. Rather than join the Julia and the ladies for coffee we head off to the coffee shop and that coffee was great. Just talking about it for a few moments and then talking about normal things lifts helps lift a burden and raise spirits. Thanks Neil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we head back to the Spire and it’s done quick enough. The journey to and from the hospital gives us time to reflect and chat. In the past week we’ve had so &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; hard conversations. Ones that I couldn’t imagined having just the week before. We are preparing for the worst and Julia is getting her stuff together. We’ve talked about wills, funerals, the kids, life, the future. It might seem morbid and in away it is, but Julia would hate for me to get it wrong - or more correctly she’d hate for me to worry that I’d got stuff wrong. And yes we know there is hope, that it might be muscular and not sinister at all but it’d be foolish to delude ourselves totally. Anyway, doing this and organising things is what Julia is good at. It keeps her busy and is the most proactive thing to do in the circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beers&quot;&gt;Beers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday, I ferry Felix to the pool for his lesson and take time out to read whilst he swims. I bump into the Strongs at the pool and there’s talk of a beer in the evening with Adam - sounds good to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep ourselves busy, Julia and I planned a trip to the IMAX to see Star Wars again. It’s pretty “in your face” cool with the 3D visuals and super sound. I notice Julia looks to be in pain at times during the film, so once its over we ditch the dinner plans and opt for takeaway instead. After dinner and painkillers Julia zones out, whilst the kids cheer for the latest round of contestants in Ninja Warrior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I head out the pub and its nice to have a few beers. I probably had more than I had planned but Dan, Adam and Marcus are good company. By the time we leave the pub its snowing. Theres always a touch of magic walking through the first flakes of snow. Dan and I have a chat about Julia whilst heading home and for the first time since the news, I feel at peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunday-feeling&quot;&gt;Sunday feeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always think the downside to having beers, is you pay for the previous nights happiness with todays. As if happiness is some kind of limited resource. The hangover wasn’t great and I have a touch of the blues. I make a mental note I can’t be having too many, too often as it has a high happiness cost!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rugby was cancelled, so Imogen decides to make cheesecake. A brilliant plan! I walk them to the supermarket whilst Julia takes it easy. We grab snow from the tops of walls and throw snowballs there and back. I become Imogen’s sous chef - man she’s demanding! Later on I watch the rugby on tv and generally chill. The kids get a little cabin fevered - note to self I need to exercise them more when rugby is off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sunday feeling is hard to bare, there’s some dread about what tomorrow may bring. Finding sleep is hard and moods are low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monday-monday&quot;&gt;Monday, Monday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, this is the worst Monday of the year, the newspapers say so, so it must be true. We’re on board with that, but we also are hoping for sciatica. That’s in our script, so lets hope it becomes so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased that Julia was up for the school run today. It’s even better that she has the chance to head to the community centre for coffee with friends after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia is currently having an mammoth MRI scan an hour and half (we know how to get the most out of our insurance). I’m in the waiting room, drinking coffee and, well, waiting. There’s an odd bunch in today. I’m not a fan of the man whose been listening to loud music, farting and burping as he has to down a litre of water for some scan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way I’m glad today’s come even though it’s ominous at least we’ll know what’s what. We’ll be able to talk about it with clarity. The kids can finally know why we’ve been so weird and we can be open with all our friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it is what it is and tonight we find out, here’s hoping for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/an-unwelcome-surprise&quot;&gt;An unwelcome surprise&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 18, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long Weekend]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-long-weekend" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-long-weekend</id>
  <published>2016-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Saturday started early again, with the usual pain waking me up.&lt;p&gt;After a few hours the kids came in and were despatched to play on the Playstation or read.  Next thing I know, it’s time for Ross to take Felix to his swimming lesson and Imogen was instructed to get her homework done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we’d had lunch it was time to see Star Wars again.  This time at the IMAX.  It was brilliant.  We really enjoyed it.  It was quite uncomfortable for me to sit for over two hours and I was glad to get home to top up the painkillers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A curry was ordered in for tea, and Ross went out for a couple of beers.  I went to bed when the kids did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday we were praying that rugby training would be cancelled due to it being so cold and a covering of snow.  Luckily it was, so despite my early waking, I had Breakfast in bed and was back asleep by 10am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was quiet, but with the anticipation building for tomorrow’s final scan and the results we’ll get, to say I’m a bit anxious is an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-long-weekend&quot;&gt;The Long Weekend&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 17, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Day, Another Scan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-day-another-scan" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-day-another-scan</id>
  <published>2016-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;ve been waking up in the night by the pain in my back.&lt;p&gt;I usually take some morphine and some diazepam to try and relieve it before going back to sleep.  Unfortunately, sleep tends to be illusive, and by the time I’ve huffed and puffed a bit, Ross has woken up.  We chat for a while, maybe read, maybe chat to the other insomniacs on social media, and if we’re lucky get back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I had some visitors, which was nice.  Some of the Gin Club came round after the morning school with biscuits and made their own tea and coffee. (They are good like that.)  It’s good to have news from the outside world.  Something that doesn’t involve me, pain, cancer or hospitals.  I appreciate it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was due a CT with contrast today and was nil by mouth from 9am.  This included painkillers.  The imaging department at the hospital was very efficient, I was given water, changed into a robe, had a cannula fitted and was led into the CT suite.  By this point I was in agony.  20 minutes later, I was all done, the radiographers helped me up out of the scanner as I can’t get from lying to sitting on my own, and sent on my way, but not before I dosed up on morphine and other painkillers, and snuck in a cup of coffee and some jammy dodgers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once home I tried to keep busy.  Felix was out at a friends and Imy got on with her music practice.  We haven’t said anything to the bairns yet about any of this.  They know I have a bad back, and that I’ve been having scans and seeing doctors. I don’t think Cancer is even on their radar.  They don’t know you can get cancer in your back or bones.  Why would they?  They are children.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, I have another MRI, and then in the evening, after we’ve seen the Oncologist and find out what we are dealing with, we’ll decide what to tell them and how best to do it.  I don’t expect it’ll be an easy conversation.  But - it still could be a trapped nerve…there’s a 10% chance it’s not cancer.  Please let that be the case.  Please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-day-another-scan&quot;&gt;Another Day, Another Scan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 15, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bad Back, Bad News]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/bad-back-bad-news" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/bad-back-bad-news</id>
  <published>2016-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">After the upbeat nature of my last post, I&#39;m afraid to say things aren&#39;t going to plan.&lt;p&gt;I had said I wanted to have no medical interventions I didn’t choose myself.  Nope - I’ve failed at that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, after the kids went back to school, I started to get a pain in my back.  Back pain is not unusual for me, so I ignored it for a bit.  But it got progressively worse.  I became permanently attached to a hot water bottle, even taking it into the office with me.  I started talking painkillers but the paracetamol and ibuprofen weren’t cutting it, so I broke into my stash of Tramadol.  This was a mistake as it sends me a bit doo-lally.  It didn’t make the pain much better either, so I went back to the paracetamol and ibuprofen.  Walking was becoming laboured, bending and twisting was agony and I couldn’t sleep properly as the pain was waking me up.  I like to think I have quite a high pain threshold, but this was something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross suggested I do some stretches and use his roller for easing muscular pain.  For a quiet life I gave them a go, but nothing helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time Monday morning rolled around, I’d had enough.  Ross suggested seeing the GP for painkillers, but instead I emailed my Oncologist’s secretary to see if he could fit me in for a quick telephone chat.  I wanted him to tell me to “Man up and get on with things”.  I even told him this when we spoke later that evening on the phone.  I explained my symptoms, and he thought it sounded like a slipped disk.  Oh! I haven’t had one of them before!  Then he said given my history, that I should go for an MRI and he’d get his secretary to organise it quickly for me.  He also told me to go to the GP for the painkillers.  He gave me a list of what to ask for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, I go to the GP’s and come back with a good haul of painkillers, including anti-inflamitories and valium.  ( :-o )  He tells me if I don’t get an MRI through quickly via my consultant, then I was to go back and let them know and they would organise one for me.  This is a bit odd.  People are taking me seriously!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At lunchtime I get a call telling me to go for a scan at 4:30 that afternoon, and that the Oncologist will catch up with me the following Monday to discuss the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the scan is done, I get all my images on disk.  This is quite exciting, considering all the scans I’ve had, I’ve never actually seen any!  But I’ve got my own disk!  To keep!  Obviously Ross and I have a look at them, but can’t make head or tail of them so put it back in it’s envelope and wait to see the Oncologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The appointment comes through quicker than we anticipated.  His secretary contacted me the next day to tell me that he wanted to see me as soon as possible and could I get to the hospital for lunchtime.  Oh.  Ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the hospital we are sat down and Dr Shah makes no bones about the fact (no pun intended) that he is 90% sure my pain is caused by cancer in the vertebrae which is causing it to bulge and press on my spinal cord.  Obviously this is bad news.  Very bad news.  It means the breast cancer has metastasized and gone traveling.  If it is the 90%, then I’ll be classed as Stage 4 or terminal.  There is no cure for this, only management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing he wants to do is get my pain under control.  In addition to the painkillers given to me by the GP, he has given me steroids and oral morphine, as well as a couple of drugs to counteract the side effects of these.  He’s said if the pain can’t be controlled by this method, he’ll get me admitted so it can be done in a more controlled environment.  Obviously, I don’t want to go into hospital, I want to be with me family.  I want to watch Imy and Felix play rugby on Sunday.  I want to see Star Wars again on Saturday, but this time at the IMAX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To confirm the diagnosis, I need the have a couple more scans.  A CT is booked in for Friday, and another MRI for Monday.  The idea is they confirm that the suspect vertebrae is in fact Cancer (although there’s still a 10% chance it’s not), and also see if it’s managed to go anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment plan would involve radiotherapy and “therapy” but he wasn’t clear on whether that would be chemotherapy or targeted therapy like Herceptin or it’s sisters.  He said there was no point having a big long discussion about it now, as until he’s got all the facts, he won’t have a plan of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question “How long have I got?” was also evaded.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then went to the chemo ward to have some bloods taken.  It was bizarre to be back there, seeing the lovely chemo nurses.  They gave me big hugs, and I told them as much as it was nice to see them, I hadn’t really wanted to go back there.  They completely understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are, back playing the Waiting Game.  Thankfully we won’t have to wait long.  I’ll be seeing him again on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/bad-back-bad-news&quot;&gt;Bad Back, Bad News&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 14, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another New Year]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year</id>
  <published>2015-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Three years ago, we were thinking to ourselves that 2012 had been a pretty good year, and looking forward to another good one in 2013.&lt;p&gt;As it transpired, it was a good year.  We moved into a new house, we had a couple of great holidays, as a family, things were fantastic, everyone was happy but it was also the year where things changed for me forever.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gone over what it feels like to have the rug pulled out from under you before, I’m not going to rake over old ground. I’m here 2 years on, feeling very grateful I’ve got to another New Year, still not dead.  But it’s going to take me a long time yet to get over it mentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen has requested that as a New Year’s resolution, I try not to shout as much.  I’ll give it a go, but I’m also going to try and not have any medical interventions that I don’t choose myself. (Ha, like I have any say in that!)  In 2015, I finished Herceptin, and had two lots of surgery and still more scans, and consultant appointments.  I’m tired of hospitals.  Tired of doctors. Tired of tests. And just generally tired.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the latest round of tests, I’ve been told that my health is pretty perfect, which is obviously great news!  I’m just experiencing the after effects of 2 years of medical interventions.  Just.  Ok, great.  Thanks.  I’ve had Cancer, can I just move on now?  No!  I need to build up my stamina again, but it’s proving tricky.  I can swim 40 lengths in half an hour, do a pilates class, walk the kids to and from school, but every morning I wake up feeling like I could sleep for a week. I can’t even do a full day at work without having to take two days to recover! It’s just annoying.  I want to be able to do everything that I want to do, everything that I used to be able to do, and I can’t and it’s really frustrating me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are my New Year Resolutions?  It may sound dramatic, but I’d like to stay alive.  I’d like to get to my 40th birthday in Feb 2017.  The type of cancer I had, before the days of Herceptin, it would have been game over.  Grade 3, HER2+ breast cancer is not good news, it spreads fast and wide.  Luckily, I’ve had the Herceptin, hopefully it’s got rid of all the baddies that were lingering that the surgery didn’t get, and we can carry on. I’ve been signed up for a Macmillan Hope course in January which will hopefully help me deal with The Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the second one and to be fair, I think I’ll stop there.  That’s enough to be going on with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all my friends and family who have been with me on the journey so far, I thank you.  I’m sorry to be a Cancer bore.  I can rely on you all to keep my spirits up, and tell me how it is.  In fact, I think Rachel said “God, Julia, just because you’ve had cancer doesn’t mean you get special treatment!”.  Keeping it real!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year&quot;&gt;Another New Year&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[2nd Cancerversary]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/2nd-Cancerversary" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/2nd-Cancerversary</id>
  <published>2015-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today is my Cancerversary.&lt;p&gt;It’s two years since Ross and I were ushered into a room and told I had breast cancer. I can’t remember the exact words that were used. All I know is that a bomb went off that day and we’ve been feeling the effects of that explosion since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite hard having my Cancerversary in Breast Cancer Awareness Month, as it’s everywhere. I’m constantly being reminded of how devastating it is. But…without that awareness how many more women will die from the disease?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will reiterate a point I’ve made before, breast cancer is not pink, nor fluffy, nor is it one of the “best ones” to get. It kills. Even the “lucky” ones don’t come out unscathed. The treatments that are life saving, are also life changing. Many of us have to deal with fatigue which is more than just feeling a bit tired. It’s waking in the morning after 8 hours sleep and feeling like you could roll over and sleep for a week. It’s the constant feeling of having to pull against the crushing force of gravity just to get off the sofa. It’s the feeling that you’d love to do something, make plans, but when it comes to it, just wanting a nap instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there’s the medication which interferes with your hormones. I’ve got 8 more years of hot flushes and mood swings to contend with. Poor Ross will wake up in the night, in the dead of winter, and find the bedroom windows wide open just so I can sleep comfortably, whilst having night sweats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you’ve got the scars. Whereas once I just had a few stretch marks from being pregnant, I now have a wide array of scars in varying sizes, from 5mm to 30cm. I don’t look upon them as being ugly, but rather as way markers from the path I’ve walked to get me to where I am today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have I mentioned the memory loss? It’s very frustrating for someone that had the memory of an elephant to now not have the capacity to remember the 3 things I needed to get from the shop. It’s changed the way Ross remembers things too. He would just ask me where something was. That’s no longer reliable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m lucky, I’m Cancer free. I get to walk my kids to school everyday, help with their homework, watch them play rugby, all normal things that maybe once I took for granted. But everyday I have the cloud hanging over me that it’ll return. I have to deal with a vast array of “what if’s” that are, quite frankly, terrifying. I’ve even discussed my funeral with Ross. Not something you normally think about in your 30s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is my point after all this rambling on? Check your boobs. If you think something isn’t right, go to your GP. Get thinks checked by the professionals. If you think you are being fobbed off, ask for a referral to the breast clinic. Don’t just do nothing. It’s important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Ross? He’s amazing. He’s had to run Team Lawley on his own on more than one occasion, and has done a magnificent job. ❤&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/2nd-Cancerversary&quot;&gt;2nd Cancerversary&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 23, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Boob Day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/New-Boob-Day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/New-Boob-Day</id>
  <published>2015-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">September 17th will from now on be known as &#39;New Boob Day&#39;&lt;p&gt;On the 17th I was admitted into hospital for my reconstruction surgery. The surgery is DIEP Flap reconstruction.  It involves taking a large piece of skin and fat from my stomach, (luckily there was plenty), and then replumbing it in to create me two new boobs.  It’s very long, fiddly surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the run up to surgery, I’d caught Imogen’s cold, and I was concerned that it may be postponed.  Thankfully, it wasn’t and after nearly 11 hours of surgery, I was in recovery, chucking my guts up which I had told everyone involved would happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first night and next day on the ward are a bit hazy.  I remember being very rude to a nurse who brought me a cup of tea.  (I’m mortified about this.)  Ross came to visit in the afternoon and I was pleased to see him.  He decided to bring the kids in to visit, as they’d been missing me, and me them.  Imogen proudly showed me her certificate she’d been presented in Golden Assembly for passing her Grade 1 Flute exam.  She’d also got Star of The Week for great maths.  Such was the anesthetic haze, I couldn’t remember any of this until Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I was encouraged to get up, have a wash, and eventually had the drains and other tubes removed.  I was also taken off the morphine pump, but as I wasn’t really using it, this wasn’t too much of a drama.  Every so often someone would come in and ask to “check my flaps”.  This invariably caused me much amusement, but laughing about it with Ross hurt my stomach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday morning rolled around, and the doctor told me I could go home if the Consultant agreed.  Luckily he did, so after 11 hours of surgery, 4 nights in hospital, armed with a packet of paracetamol and some replacement dressings, I was off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad had come down the day before surgery to look after the kids, and when I got home, Grandma Julie had arrived too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent most of the next week in bed, only getting up for mealtimes, and The Great British Bake Off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad returned home after 2 weeks.  It was brilliant having him stay, as it meant Ross could get on with work, and the kids could stay in their normal routine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gradually I’ve been getting better, and am no longer reliant on the painkillers. I’ve had all my dressings and stitches removed, and the wounds are healing well. I’m hoping over the next week to start getting out for walks again, and build up some stamina.  I had assumed that I would be still incapacitated at this stage, and I think I have surprised everyone, including the Consultant, with how well I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw the Consultant on Wednesday, he told me to “keep doing whatever you are doing as it’s obviously working”.  So that’s what I’m going to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/New-Boob-Day&quot;&gt;New Boob Day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 02, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long Time No See]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Long-time-no-see" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Long-time-no-see</id>
  <published>2015-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s been a long time since my last post.&lt;p&gt;It’s been five months since my last post, and a lot has happened but I’ll try to be brief!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of May, I had the key hole surgery to remove the cyst on my ovary.  It turns out that there was in fact two cysts, of different types, but both completely benign.  They were both removed successfully along with the offending ovary.  The surgeon was happy with the outcome and has decided he doesn’t need to see me again.  Good news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four weeks after this surgery, I completed the Pretty Muddy Race For Life with Allison, Caroline, Charli and Michelle.  It was great fun, and we were all suitably grubby when we’d finished.  The supporting squad were very much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July, a larger Gin Club contingent took part in the Stevenage Race for Life, followed by a post race fundraising BBQ at The Orange Tree.  Thanks Rob!  We managed to raise over £1000 for Cancer Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August brought us school holidays and our two week family break away.  The first week we went to the Peak District with my Dad ad Julie and had some great days out.  The second week we went to the Lake District and marched up and down hills most days, but also ventured over the Hardknott and Wrynose Pass which was an interesting drive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to school in September and the kids settled back into their new classes well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in January, I’d mentioned to my good friend Fiona, that I fancied doing a Trialthlon.  “I’ll do it with you” she said.  Well, she did do it, and I didn’t.  I didn’t know when the reconstruction surgery was going to be, so I thought it best not to commit to such a big thing.  I now owe her a triathlon.  She was amazing.  It was a hot day and a hard course, but she did it.  And with a smile on her face (not all the time, there might have been swearing at times, but we can forgive her that.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that brings us to New Boob Day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Long-time-no-see&quot;&gt;Long Time No See&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 01, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook Follow-up]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Facebook-Follow-up" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Facebook-Follow-up</id>
  <published>2015-05-04T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This post started off as a a Facebook Status update.&lt;p&gt;This weekend I’ve been called a Facebook Warrior, as I am quite active on Facebook whilst also dabbling in Twitter.  (Does that make me a Twitter Twerp?)  Anyway, when I was writing it, it became clear that I needed to write a proper blog post for it because there was a lot of information I wanted to get across and lots of links to other sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original post was prompted by Rio Ferdinand’s wife, Rebecca, dying on Friday from breast cancer.  Here is what I said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s easy to think that Breast Cancer is one thing of the “best” cancers to get. But we should not get complacent. Breast Cancer kills. It is ignorant and non discriminating, and it’s pot luck if those who are diagnosed live or die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rebecca Ferdinand had been given the all clear, but it returned and sadly she died on Friday, aged 35, leaving her 3 kids without a Mummy. Heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lisa Lynch, in The C Word, on tonight, was also given the all clear, only for the Cancer to return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cancer is a Bitch. I’ll always be wondering whether my luck will change and we’ll have the Bitch come back. In the meantime, I’ll be living my life, enjoying watching my bairns grow up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ll also be raising money for Cancer Research, because we need to stop ladies like Rebecca and Lisa dying.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being told you have Cancer is horrendous.  Your life flashes in front of your eyes and you are suddenly given a very harsh lesson in the limitations of your own mortality. Whilst the medical team try and assure you that they hope to rid your body of Cancer, you are acutely aware that this disease has the potential to end your life.  (Insert your own Bad Swear here.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.breakthrough.org.uk/research/secondary/what-secondary-breast-cancer&quot;&gt;Breast Cancer Campaign&lt;/a&gt;, nearly 1,000 women in the UK die from breast cancer each month. Most of these deaths are from where the original breast cancer has spread to other parts of the body like liver, brain or bones.  Every month, 1000 families are left devastated at the loss of a Wife, Mum, Grandma, Sister, Aunt, Daughter.  1000 families discover that Breast Cancer isn’t the ‘best’ type of cancer to get, that it’s not easy to treat and are left with a gaping hole that no amount of condolences will fill.  Families like those of Rebecca Ellison, Lisa Lynch, Lulu and Rachel.  The latter two being ladies I’ve come across on my own cancer journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must continue to raise awareness to get women (and men) to know what the signs of breast cancer are.  Get familiar with your breasts, find out what’s normal and see the doctor if something’s not right.  Early detection is key.  Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.breakthrough.org.uk/about-breast-cancer/touch-look-check&quot;&gt;Breakthrough Breast Cancer’s&lt;/a&gt; guide for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must also continue to raise funds for research into finding a cure for Cancer.  Whilst Cancer is not pink and fluffy, if a pink and fluffy event gets people raising money, then that’s got to be a good thing.  So, if I can do the Race for Life and the Pretty Muddy one, you can sponsor me.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/the-gin-club-2015/&quot;&gt;Sponsor the Gin Club at Race For Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t underestimate Cancer.  It sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/football/2015/may/02/rebecca-ellisson-wife-of-footballer-rio-ferdinand-dies&quot;&gt;Rebecca Ellison wife of Rio Ferdinand Dies - The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3066155/Rio-Ferdinand-s-sister-thanks-fans-friends-love-support-tributes-continue-pour-footballer-s-wife-Rebecca-Ellison-died-cancer.html&quot;&gt;Rio Ferdinand’s Wife Died from Cancer - The Daily Mail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alrighttit.blogspot.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Lisa Lynch’s Blog - Alright Tit &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Facebook-Follow-up&quot;&gt;Facebook Follow-up&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 04, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last Port]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-port" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-port</id>
  <published>2015-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">In November 2013, I had a Chemotherapy port fitted.&lt;p&gt;It’s about the size of a pound coin with a thin tube going into a vein and sits under the skin on my chest.  I can feel it, the kids can feel it, and on occasion if they hug me too fervently, it can hurt.  But, it’s done it’s job.  It has made for easy administration of 10 rounds of chemo, 18 rounds of Herceptin, 1 dye for a CT scan and at least 20 blood tests.  That’s all things that would normally have been done via a needle in my arm.  And so now, after a conversation with my Oncologist and the Radiologist, it’s coming out next Friday.  It was put in under sedation, and I was given the option of being sedated to have it taken out.  It’s the difference between being admitted as an inpatient and waiting around for hours, or rocking up, and 20 minutes later going home.  I don’t imagine that it’s going to be particularly pleasant as they pull the tube out from the vein, but I’ll put my Big Girl Pants on, and crack on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I saw the Cardiologist today for a final Echo scan.  Herceptin, the biological treatment which targets the HER2+ bit of the cancer and has worked so well for me, has been proven in clinical trials to increase the risk of damage to the heart.  So throughout the course of treatments, (18 doses over 15 months, 3 weeks apart with a break for surgery and radiotherapy), I have been having regular heart scans to check nothing sinister is going on.  It seems I’ve been lucky and the Cardiologist has said that he’s happy there’s been no damage and I don’t need to see him again.  Yippee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back from the hospital I was telling Ross how lucky I was.  He was a bit surprised I thought this, “Lucky for getting Cancer?”  Well, no, not lucky for getting Cancer, as to be honest, that’s been a bit rubbish, but lucky to have responded so well to treatment, with no major drama’s along the way and not to have any lasting side effects apart from the fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifteen months ago, I felt like I had a mountain to climb.  On reflection, I’m not sure how I’ve done it, but I appear to be on the other side.  I suppose I kept my head down, and put one foot in front of the other and just kept going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could say anything to someone who has found themselves in a similar situation to me, I would say “Trust the experts, take it one day at a time, and accept help when offered.  Cancer is scary, some people will surprise you, others will let you down but try not to dwell on it.  Keep on, keeping on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-port&quot;&gt;Last Port&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 22, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Goes On]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/life-goes-on" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/life-goes-on</id>
  <published>2015-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Winter is turning to Spring and all around us the buds of new beginnings are peaking up.&lt;p&gt;I love seeing the snowdrops, crocuses, daffodils and the blossom on the trees. Spring has always been my favourite time of year.  Full of possibilities, of opportunities, and lots of what can be’s. It’s a reminder that life goes on and it’s no different in the Lawley house.  We’ve got the usual round of school, music lessons, swimming lessons, rugby and dancing.  It’s almost as if we are a normal family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to add to the normality, I’ve started working again.  Its not much.  Only 10-15 hours a week, and I’m working at home, but it gets my brain working again.  It’s spent the last 8 months slowly turning to mush.  It’ll be good to get my teeth into something again.  Plus we need to refill the Lawley coffers that have taken a battering whilst I haven’t been working.  Boring, but necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also spending 2 hours a week in the local Library as their IT Champion.  I’m helping out the public who maybe aren’t so confident using computers.  It’s early days yet, and I haven’t had a massive uptake, but it’ll take time to get word out that I’m around.  In the meantime, I’m writing a blog post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I said I would do last year when I was being a little bit fatalistic was that I would stop putting things off, and do the things that I wanted to do.  So far I’ve joined a choir, and will be performing in a concert in May, I’ve run another Standalone 10km, and the latest thing is that I’ve signed up to do a Race For Life Pretty Muddy in June.  It’s not as hard core as the Tough Mudder/Beach Warrior/One True Grit, etc, but given that I’ll only be one month past keyhole surgery it’s probably not a bad thing.  I’ve got a few of the Gin Club ladies to sign up too, so it should be a good laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, life goes on, and we are planning this years camping trips and summer holidays.  Something that this time last year, and to an extent this year until we got the surgery date, we felt we weren’t able to do.  Ross and I have decided that we’ll delay reconstruction  until September time.  Then we can have the kids back at school and I can get the long recovery time I need without interfering in our family time too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as is standard, we’ll keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/life-goes-on&quot;&gt;Life Goes On&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 02, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fighting Fit!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fighting%20fit" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fighting fit</id>
  <published>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">My Oncologist is keen that I don&#39;t turn into a blimp.&lt;p&gt;He’s told me I’m not allowed to just sit on the sofa all day and watch daytime tv.  (Meanie).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve been using Ross’s Fitbit and trying to get 10,000 steps in a day. This works out at about 7km or 4.5 miles a day. Some days it’s fine, as I can pretty much do that by walking the kids to and from school.  Other days it’s a bit harder.  Like at the weekends.  I’ve come to realise that I don’t move very much at the weekends.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, a friend, (that’s you Fiona), has challenged me to a step race.  It’s basically who can get the most steps in Monday to Friday.  My competitive streak kicked in, and I managed to win last week.  I came last in the weekend challenge, (lol), but I’m on track this week and managed my 10,000 steps before 10:10am this morning after a brisk walk round Baldock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve just checked my stats for the past 7 days, and I’ve walked nearly 50km which is just over 31 miles.  That’s got to be doing something for my fitness levels surely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see me walking round Baldock purposefully, you know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fighting%20fit&quot;&gt;Fighting Fit!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 17, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another long wait]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-long-wait" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-long-wait</id>
  <published>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Back in October 2013, I wrote a blog post called A Long Wait.&lt;p&gt;It seems I’ve found myself in the midst of another long wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of the year, I’ve had two CT scans, two MRI scans and an ultrasound scan.  That’s quite a lot of scans.  The Multi-disciplinary team have discussed me three times and at last, this week I heard the decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s good news.  All the scans and blood tests indicate that this lump is benign.  Yay!  It still needs to be removed as it’s unlikely to go away by itself, and the ‘wait and see’ option isn’t really an option when I want to have reconstruction at some point this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m booked in to have surgery on the 11th of May.  It’ll involve at most one night in hospital, and I’ll be out of action for a week, but it is so good to be able to make plans around a date.  So many things were being put off, or only tentative plans made, but this is great.  I’m pleased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-long-wait&quot;&gt;Another long wait&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 17, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>