<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2015-04-22T17:06:49+01:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Goes On]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/life-goes-on" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/life-goes-on</id>
  <published>2015-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Winter is turning to Spring and all around us the buds of new beginnings are peaking up.&lt;p&gt;I love seeing the snowdrops, crocuses, daffodils and the blossom on the trees. Spring has always been my favourite time of year.  Full of possibilities, of opportunities, and lots of what can be’s. It’s a reminder that life goes on and it’s no different in the Lawley house.  We’ve got the usual round of school, music lessons, swimming lessons, rugby and dancing.  It’s almost as if we are a normal family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to add to the normality, I’ve started working again.  Its not much.  Only 10-15 hours a week, and I’m working at home, but it gets my brain working again.  It’s spent the last 8 months slowly turning to mush.  It’ll be good to get my teeth into something again.  Plus we need to refill the Lawley coffers that have taken a battering whilst I haven’t been working.  Boring, but necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also spending 2 hours a week in the local Library as their IT Champion.  I’m helping out the public who maybe aren’t so confident using computers.  It’s early days yet, and I haven’t had a massive uptake, but it’ll take time to get word out that I’m around.  In the meantime, I’m writing a blog post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I said I would do last year when I was being a little bit fatalistic was that I would stop putting things off, and do the things that I wanted to do.  So far I’ve joined a choir, and will be performing in a concert in May, I’ve run another Standalone 10km, and the latest thing is that I’ve signed up to do a Race For Life Pretty Muddy in June.  It’s not as hard core as the Tough Mudder/Beach Warrior/One True Grit, etc, but given that I’ll only be one month past keyhole surgery it’s probably not a bad thing.  I’ve got a few of the Gin Club ladies to sign up too, so it should be a good laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, life goes on, and we are planning this years camping trips and summer holidays.  Something that this time last year, and to an extent this year until we got the surgery date, we felt we weren’t able to do.  Ross and I have decided that we’ll delay reconstruction  until September time.  Then we can have the kids back at school and I can get the long recovery time I need without interfering in our family time too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as is standard, we’ll keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/life-goes-on&quot;&gt;Life Goes On&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 02, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fighting Fit!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fighting%20fit" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fighting fit</id>
  <published>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">My Oncologist is keen that I don&#39;t turn into a blimp.&lt;p&gt;He’s told me I’m not allowed to just sit on the sofa all day and watch daytime tv.  (Meanie).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve been using Ross’s Fitbit and trying to get 10,000 steps in a day. This works out at about 7km or 4.5 miles a day. Some days it’s fine, as I can pretty much do that by walking the kids to and from school.  Other days it’s a bit harder.  Like at the weekends.  I’ve come to realise that I don’t move very much at the weekends.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, a friend, (that’s you Fiona), has challenged me to a step race.  It’s basically who can get the most steps in Monday to Friday.  My competitive streak kicked in, and I managed to win last week.  I came last in the weekend challenge, (lol), but I’m on track this week and managed my 10,000 steps before 10:10am this morning after a brisk walk round Baldock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve just checked my stats for the past 7 days, and I’ve walked nearly 50km which is just over 31 miles.  That’s got to be doing something for my fitness levels surely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see me walking round Baldock purposefully, you know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fighting%20fit&quot;&gt;Fighting Fit!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 17, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another long wait]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-long-wait" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-long-wait</id>
  <published>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Back in October 2013, I wrote a blog post called A Long Wait.&lt;p&gt;It seems I’ve found myself in the midst of another long wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of the year, I’ve had two CT scans, two MRI scans and an ultrasound scan.  That’s quite a lot of scans.  The Multi-disciplinary team have discussed me three times and at last, this week I heard the decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s good news.  All the scans and blood tests indicate that this lump is benign.  Yay!  It still needs to be removed as it’s unlikely to go away by itself, and the ‘wait and see’ option isn’t really an option when I want to have reconstruction at some point this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m booked in to have surgery on the 11th of May.  It’ll involve at most one night in hospital, and I’ll be out of action for a week, but it is so good to be able to make plans around a date.  So many things were being put off, or only tentative plans made, but this is great.  I’m pleased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-long-wait&quot;&gt;Another long wait&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 17, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delays]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/delays" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/delays</id>
  <published>2015-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It seems some things take their own sweet time.&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to be seeing the specialist tomorrow to get a plan of action for removing the cyst and hopefully a surgery date.  I’ve spoken to him a couple of times since seeing him and it looks like he won’t have all the information for that appointment so it’s been delayed until late next week.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Multi-disciplinery team have discussed my case, but haven’t come to a decision as they didn’t have all my scans upon which to base it.  They have been reassured that the cyst is (most likely) not sinister because my CA125 marker levels are normal (yay!), but they still want the cyst to come out.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time the MDT meet, hopefully they’ll have all my scans and decide the extent of the surgery, namely if I need an Oophorectomy and whether it’s one or both.  There’s a line in Orange is the New Black where Rosa is discussing her cancer with her counsellor and says “Who doesn’t love a surgery with ‘Ooph!’ in it.”  We’ll go with that, because the side effects and aftermath aren’t really very pleasant, especially for someone my age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest impact all of these delays have had is that I can no longer go ahead with my reconstruction on the 28th March.  It means I get the Easter Holidays with the kids back, but it also means that everything is delayed by at least 6 weeks once I’ve had the first lot of surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so in the absence of anything else, we wait some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/delays&quot;&gt;Delays&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 24, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wait...]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wait" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wait</id>
  <published>2015-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Just a quick update after seeing the specialist yesterday.&lt;p&gt;I’ve had blood taken so it can be tested for the markers I mentioned in my last post.  These results, together with my scans, will be taken to a Multi-disciplinary (surgical/oncology) meeting on Wednesday and they’ll decide what path to take and let me know within a few days.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specialist said that if I hadn’t had the crazy events of the past year and without the weird genetic mutation, (CHEK2), thrown into the mix, they would regard it as nothing to worry about and whip the cyst out.  However, they need to take a cautious approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that whatever else happens, surgery to remove the cyst is inevitable.  The specialist said if it was less than 5cm, it would probably go away by itself, but because it’s bigger, it’s unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so we wait.  Again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wait&quot;&gt;Wait...&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 17, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lumps]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/lumps" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/lumps</id>
  <published>2015-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;m not a big fan of lumps where there shouldn&#39;t be lumps.&lt;p&gt;As far as I’m concerned, lumps are not good news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I had my scan back in January, it threw up two things.  One was that I had Tendinitis and Trochanteric Bursitis in my hip.  I’ve since seen a specialist who has suggested a steroid injection will alleviate the pain whilst walking.  However, since seeing him the pain has diminished massively, so I’m hoping that after 2 months of suffering, it’s got better by itself, and that’ll be the end of it.  Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing is that they’ve found an 8cm cyst in my abdomen.  I’ve had a couple of scans on it now, and my Oncologist is keen to stress that he is not worried about it.  I get that.  However, I was told that my breast lumps were ‘only’ cysts, and we all know how that turned out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, these cysts are quite common in women my age, it just seems to be the size of it that’s causing the headache.  The doctors need to decide what to do about it.  In most cases they would just wait and see if it sorted itself out, and if it didn’t they’d whip it out in a few months time.  The complexity with me, is that I’ve got reconstructive surgery booked in at the end of March, which will be using tissue from my stomach.  Once that’s been done, it makes getting into my belly that bit trickier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, in the back of my mind I am worried that it could be cancer again.  From what I’ve read from reliable and reputable sources, it is difficult to tell if this type on cyst is cancer from a scan alone.  There are blood tests that can be done to see if there is an elevated marker, but a benign cyst could cause that too.  In my head, I am aware that it would be very unlikely to be cancer as I only just finished Herceptin last month.  It would have to be a different kind of cancer (HER-) to get past that marvellous piece of modern medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the plan is, I see a specialist this afternoon to get his take on it.  Then I reconvene with my Oncologist next week to see what the plan will be.
I sometimes feel like I’m a poor excuse for a human being.  All these things seem to keep happening.  I just want a quiet life.  I want to work on getting my brain back, I want to feel less tired ALL THE TIME, I just want to stop getting these curve balls.  I want to stop feeling so sorry for myself and as Mel off Bake Off would say “Get a ruddy grip!”.  I’ve done the hard bit, but the end doesn’t seem to be in sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in the absence of anything else,  I’ll just have to keep on, keeping on.  Seems to be standard these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/lumps&quot;&gt;Lumps&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 16, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I put myself through Dryathlon and Janathon]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/dryathlon-janathon-why" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/dryathlon-janathon-why</id>
  <published>2015-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Huzzah! Drythalon is all but over and as I&#39;ve just come back from a swim I&#39;ve successfully completed Janathon!&lt;p&gt;January being the start of the year is probably the best time to reflect on life, especially as it’s pace is soo slow compared to the maelstrom of festivities, food and family chaos that is December.  Going dry for the month as per &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cancerresearchuk.org/support-us/find-an-event/charity-challenges/dryathlon&quot;&gt;Dryathlon&lt;/a&gt; and exercising everyday for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.janathon.com/rules.html&quot;&gt;Janathon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; makes January the longest month of the year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-why-did-i-put-myself-through-it-for-the-second-year-running&quot;&gt;So why did I put myself through it for the second year running?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well for the past 16 months Julia (the mrs) has been fighting breast cancer.  Julia hates the fighting / survivor anology, comments “like you have any choice!” or “I just turn up to the appointments and do as I’m told - the rest is up to the treatment”.  I can totally understand that, her body at some level might have been geared up for all the “fighting” but her mind has been focused on the now and family life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think about last year I have two big thoughts*. Firstly, last winter was horrid - long, dark and looking back I felt like I was stuck in a fog of anxiety.  This time last year Julia was nearing the end of her weekly Chemotherapy and was totally and utterly wiped out.  The pure fatigue was shocking and as powerless I felt, I thought I could do my bit by joining Dryathlon and Janathon.  The festive season was fun but my mood was low and knowing that exercising is soul food I was happy to do it. I struggled through the daily exercise and there were times I really could have done with a beer but I made it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a year and Julia is much better and the christmas season was busy, boozy and a hell of a lot of fun!  It’s soo much nicer to have a functioning Julia to help out ;) To give something back and my liver a rest I signed up to Dryathlon and Janathon again - also people kept asking if I was doing it again which made it much harder to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I was determined to give Janathon a proper crack of the whip and go for it with a bit more effort.  There’s been times when I’ve not wanted to do anything but I just had to do something, so I did a fast run round town - weirdly, I kept bumping into members of the Gaskells on my Thursday night dash.  Dan Strong was my wingman on the long weekend runs making them less of a drag.  Also, I should mention the Insanity workouts at the Knights Templar gym - they are serious fun and no word of a lie, I ached for &lt;em&gt;4 days&lt;/em&gt; after the first one but I still went back for 3 more and will be continuing the class.  Here’s my Janathon numbers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 hours running some 64km&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 hours in the Gym&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 hours swimming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 hours of Insanity workouts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t lost much weight, I ate too many biscuits at the start of the month for that, but my scales tell me I have reduced my fat percentage and I’m happy to trade fat for muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I’ve really enjoyed taking part and happily after her last Herceptin treatment, on the 12th of January Julia was finally declared cancer free and officially in remission!  Thanks in no small part to the great work of Cancer Research and also to the lessons learnt in the past from those who’ve also had the misfortune get cancer.  To help those in the future please donate anything you can:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://justgiving.com/Ross-dryathlete2015/&quot;&gt;http://justgiving.com/Ross-dryathlete2015/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* Whats the second thing? Well, as horrible as 2014 was it was also a year filled with love, laughter and friends. Julia and I made sure we enjoyed the year and looked forward with both honesty and optimism. Imogen and Felix have been brilliant and whilst you wouldn’t wish any 6 or 8 year olds to go through this, they have and continue to amaze Julia and I, you’re both brilliant xx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/dryathlon-janathon-why&quot;&gt;Why I put myself through Dryathlon and Janathon&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scanxiety]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scanxiety" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scanxiety</id>
  <published>2015-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Is that a word?&lt;p&gt;Let me assure you, that it is indeed a word, and one that is used to describe the period in the run up a scan, and until you get the results of said scan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I saw the cardiologist who did an echocardiogram and was able to give me the results straight away, thus minimising my scanxiety.  All is fine with my heart, and any chest pains that I’m experiencing are not due to my heart not functioning properly.  In fact it’s in tip top condition.  The Herceptin hasn’t caused me any problems in that respect.  Jolly good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Ross and I once again found ourselves at the Spire in Harpenden for yet another scan and to see the breast surgeon for a six monthly review.  The purpose of the scan was to ensure that the treatment has been successful, to give the plastic surgeon an idea of what he has to work with for my reconstruction and to check there’s nothing sinister going on with my every increasing hip pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The breast surgeon and the radiographer had a quick look at my scan and were able to deduce that there is no secondary cancer lurking in my liver, lungs and, crucially, my bones.  This means that whatever is causing my hip pain, it’s not &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breastcancercare.org.uk/breast-cancer-information/about-breast-cancer/secondary-metastatic-breast-cancer/bones&quot;&gt;bone mets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The breast surgeon suggested that any chest pains I have been having were due to muscle pain in the scar tissue and radiotherapy site.  Again, nothing to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now have to wait for my Oncologist to review the scans and decide what to do about the pain.  I’m currently taking Tramadol which is a fairly hefty painkiller, which can leave me feeling a bit light headed and woosey.  I don’t really want to be taking it long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed I can get to see the Oncologist soon so we can come up with a plan.  One thing that was mentioned by the Oncologist and the breast surgeon, is that my port can be taken out at the same time as my reconstruction, which means one less surgical procedure to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scanxiety&quot;&gt;Scanxiety&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 21, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Remission]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/in-remission" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/in-remission</id>
  <published>2015-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">There&#39;s four magic words anyone who has been diagnosed with Cancer wants to hear.&lt;p&gt;And they are “You are in remission”.  They are so much more positive and overall so much better than the ones uttered at the beginning of this journey, “I’m sorry, it’s cancer”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I went to see my Oncologist, and he told me now I’ve finished my active treatment, I’m officially in remission.  He told me that because of the response I’d had to chemo and Herceptin, he is pretty confident that this will be the end of my Cancer Journey, and I’m cured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this is brilliant.  Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What isn’t so brilliant, is the fact I’m still dealing with all the side effects of the treatments.  The fatigue, (I know I keep going on about it, but it’s so debilitating and frustrating), the rib pain from radiotherapy, the hot flushes, and recently the hip and pelvis pain.  I am finding walking to be very painful and am knocking back the painkillers just to get to school and back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Shah seems to think that this is due to the Tamoxifen interfering with my hormones and therefore interfering with my joints.  He wants to do a scan to double check, but it’s still a worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some joined up thinking, as well as Dr Shah’s scans, I will also be having some scans for the Plastic Surgeon so he can see what he’s got to deal with.  The basic principle is that he’ll remove stomach tissue and create me two new boobs.  It’s a very fiddley job, and involves grafting blood vessels together, but it’ll be worth it.  Another step closer to putting me back together again, albeit, quite not all in one piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/in-remission&quot;&gt;In Remission&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 13, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Big Day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/big-day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/big-day</id>
  <published>2015-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today, I finished Active Treatment.&lt;p&gt;It was with mixed emotions today when I turned up to the hospital for my last Herceptin.  The last time I was there, just before Christmas, my port decided not to work properly.  They were able to administer the Herceptin, but, unfortunately, they weren’t able to get any blood to test.  Before I left that time, they pumped a drug into it to hopefully blast the clot that had clearly developed.  When I got there today, it looked like the same was going to happen, but with a bit of jiggling, it seemed the clot buster had worked, bloods were taken and the Herceptin was pumped through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/last_herceptin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Last Herceptin&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forty minutes later, the Herceptin was in, the saline flush had been done, and I was unclipped for the last time.  I’m seeing the Oncologist next week and he’ll hopefully say I can have my port taken out, and tell me I am officially “In Remission”.  Then it’s to see the Cardiologist to check the Herceptin hasn’t done any damage to my heart.  After that it’s to the breast surgeon to make sure he’s happy I’ve healed well enough to crack on with the reconstruction surgery.  I’m not off the rollercoaster yet, but at least it’s slowed down for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, there’s been mixed emotions.  I’m obviously feeling delighted to no longer need to have chemicals pumped into me every three weeks.  But I’m also feeling a bit teary.  I’ve spent 15 months dealing with very scary treatments since I was diagnosed in October 2013, but also not dealing with them as I’ve just been concentrating on turning to each appointment when I’m told to.  At some point I’m going to have to face up to the fact that “I have had Cancer”.  Despite losing my hair, my boobs, being ridiculously tired, it’s still quite hard to understand that this has all happened to me as life has gone on.  I’ve still had to get up each morning to take the kids to school.  I’ve still had to watch them play rugby, watch school concerts, take them to various parties, swimming, etc.  We’ve tried to keep life as normal for them as we can, as they are children and shouldn’t have to deal with this in their short lives.  I kiss them when they are asleep each night, and am thankful they are as resilient as they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had thought I’d want to celebrate tonight.  But Ross is doing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/Ross-dryathlete2015/&quot;&gt;Dryathlon&lt;/a&gt;,  (please donate if you can), and to be honest, I don’t really feel like celebrating.  It’s not over.  I thought I’d be walking on air, but I’m not.  The nurses in the Chemo ward have given me some booklets to read, “Life After Cancer Treatment” and “Your Feelings After Cancer Treatment”.  I’ll be reading them both with interest because life can never go back to how it was before.  I’m never going to be “Julia - Pre Lump”.  She’s gone.  This is “Julia - Post Lump”, not quite as confident, a bit more needy, more dependent on Ross, family, friends, and frightened,  I’ll always be thinking “Will I get Cancer again?”.  The genetic abnormality I have, not only raises the chances of breast cancer, but one or two other cancers too, so it’s not an unfounded fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will I carry on?  The same way that I’ve got through things since I found the lump in May 2013.  Take each day as it comes, and Keep on, Keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much Love&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/big-day&quot;&gt;A Big Day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 08, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Year Resolutions]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/new-year" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/new-year</id>
  <published>2014-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s the time of year where we make resolutions and reflect on the past year.&lt;p&gt;Ross and I took the bairns for a walk this morning and we discussed New Year’s Resolutions.  My main aim for 2014 was to stay alive.  I’ve managed it 100% with less than 12 hours to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a blog post from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happiness-and-sadness/&quot;&gt;12th April&lt;/a&gt;, I said “I’ve added a few things to my to do list: sort the garden, stain/paint some furniture, do a 10k run, do a Race for life Pretty Muddy, and do a triathlon. What’s to stop me? Only my own mental attitude. At least that’s on my side!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can check a couple of them off too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I painted our bedside tables, and was very pleased with the results.  I’ll definitely be doing another project.
I did the Standalone 10k with Michelle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on recovery from surgery, I’ll be signing up for a Pretty Muddy event in June, and a triathlon later in the year.  If I don’t do it in 2015, I’ll do it in 2016.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen, Felix and I have signed up for the Race for Life 5k run again, as we all enjoyed it so much last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much to do, and I have the time to do it thanks to the wonders of modern medicine.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/new-year&quot;&gt;New Year Resolutions&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Christmas!!!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-christmas-time" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-christmas-time</id>
  <published>2014-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The Christmas period is upon us, and The Lawley&#39;s have been enjoying it.&lt;p&gt;Sadly it didn’t get off to the best of starts.  Both bairns were off school for most of the last week of term with a horrible lurgy bug that appeared to have decimated the school population.  They missed out on the rugby club christmas party, Imogen missed all performances of her school play, and they weren’t really that fussed as they were so poorly.  Lots of films, and lounging around on the sofa with lots of Calpol and Ibruprofen were required.  Ross took Imogen to A&amp;amp;E twice when her temperature spiked above 40’c and we couldn’t get it below 39’c.  At one point they were going to keep her in over night, but due to there being “no room at the inn”, she was sent home once her temperature got below 38.9’c.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also managed to get the bug and tried to manage it valiantly at home with the usual selection of home remedies.  I gave in after 5 days and sought medical advice when I started coughing up blood.  A short course of antibiotics later, I’m not 100% but definitely better than I was.  The doctor was under the impression that given the past years’ events, 7 days worth of antibiotics weren’t going to do any harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we’re out the other side with lingering coughs but feeling more spritely and we enjoyed Christmas.  Grandad Mike, Grandma Julie and Uncle Max all came to stay and share the festivities with us.  Much laughing and frivolity occurred.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Christmas2014.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Christmas 2014&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a world away from last year.  Last year, where I had no hair, where I was bone tired, where we had to get up the day after Boxing Day to have blood tests and chemo, where we didn’t know whether I’d be here for this Christmas.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/jandjoneyearon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;One Year On&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting that now we are just about to close the Active Treatment chapter, Ross and I have started discussing things that a lot of the time were left unsaid.  If I’m honest, I didn’t like to think too much about what would happen if the treatment didn’t work, as that would be admitting that I could die.  That’s not really a thought I wanted to entertain.  And Ross said that he didn’t really want to think about it either because that would mean he’d be left behind alone to look after the bairns. Not a scenario either of us liked the sound of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I have my last Herceptin and end active treatment.  Fifteen months of chemicals and procedures.  In some ways it’s quite hard to get my head around the fact that it’s lasted so long.  Usually when you are ill, it’s a short solution, and you’re up and at it before too long.  This just seems to be a marathon.  I’ll be so relieved when it’s finished.  They can then put me back together again, and we go to the new normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie, there of times when I’ve been having dark moments and though to myself “I’ve had Cancer”.  It’s something that happens to other people. Despite all the treatments, it has felt like it’s happened to someone else, to Evil Julia.  It’s really scary, because everyone knows that Cancer is a really scary thing to have.  The disease is scary, and the treatments are scary, and the side effects are scary.  And it’s happened to me.  Why me?  What did I do wrong?  Dwell on it for too long, and I’ll go mad. So I pull myself up by my bootstraps, have a word with myself and tell myself to count myself lucky to have everything go my way.  I’ve got Ross, I’ve got the bairns, I’ve got Dad and Julie and I’ve got the Gin Club.  With all that support, how can things not go my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reread last year’s blog post, and in it I said “Bring on next Christmas when I WILL be free of cancer and this year will just be a memory. Oh how we’ll laugh!”.  I’m not quite at the stage where I can laugh about the whole situation.  If I dwell on it for too long, it brings tears to my eyes.  Maybe next year, I’ll be far enough away that the rose tinted glasses can be engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping once the treatment finishes, I’ll stop feeling so tired all the time, and my brain and memory will start to work again.  I need to completely recover from this bug so I can get running again.  I haven’t run since Michelle and I did the Standalone 10k and I think I’ve turned to jelly.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Christmas holidays have contained a few social occasions with the Gin Club, and we’ve got a couple more before the bairns return to school.  They are looking forward to rugby training starting again, although given how cold it’s been recently, I haven’t missed standing on the sidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we’ll keep on, keeping on.  As we always do.  Because what else is there to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-christmas-time&quot;&gt;It's Christmas!!!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 30, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Its been a while]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/been-a-while" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/been-a-while</id>
  <published>2014-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Hi, its been ages - 4 months and 20 something days since my last post!&lt;p&gt;So I probably should write something down, so when I look back and reflect in years to come I will have some thoughts of my own to read also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer has been good, Julia’s radiotherapy came and went in a busy, busy month. Julia got very fatigued and then started to get better and then fatigued again.  The gin club turned out on mass for the race for life and it was a great event, the post run drinks were also highly amusing and liver pickling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We lost Merlin or rather Merlin lost himself somewhere, god only knows what happened to him. I looked like a local lunatic for weeks when I went walking around the neighbourhood whistling and shouting out: &lt;br /&gt;“♪ ♫ ♩Here kitty, kitty, kitty! ♪ ♫ ♩ Merlin ♭♫”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few sightings were had but he is still awol.  Maybe he really was the cancer cat and as soon as he knew Julia was ok he buggered off to help someone else.  I hope where ever he is he’s happy, he brightened up a dark year for us Lawleys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herceptin is ongoing for Julia but only two more to go!  For over a year the chemicals have been pumped into Mrs L and it’s now noticable that it’s taking longer to recover.  There’s barely time to bounce back and then the three weeks are up and it’s back for some more.  It seems to be more of a frustration to Julia as it’s not the crippling fatigue of Chemotherapy just a slow trudge up a big hill.  Still the end is in sight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holiday wise, we a couple of great camping trips - one seeing the tail of hurricane Bertha trying to blow down our tents!  We had a fabulous day out thanks to the Willow foundation - it really was magical.  We went to Newcastle and to the races!  I managed to put a bet on a horse that the jockey fell off before even starting the race! The shame they must have felt as they had to run with the horse to the start line and then only to be bucked off as soon as the gates opened.  During autumn half term we went to the peak district - and walked the legs off the kids. They were brilliant and hardly complained, the weather, like the hills was fantastic. Google maps took us down some of the smallest lanes, I’ve ever seen and I was cursing under my breath when a car came up the hill meaning I had to reverse until we reached a passing point. I really showed my skills by reversing and zigzagging across the small lane. As soon as we came back from the peaks (within hours) we got a new kitten, Mundungus, he’s a cheaky chappie and causing mischief like only kittens can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kids are loving sport and music. Imogen rocked the duck n dash and is getting stuck in at rugby - 5 tries in the last game! Felix is coming on leaps and bounds in rugby also, he has grown a hunger for tags and tries. Their smiles after a game, warm the coldest of days and they’ve played on some of them.  Their swimming is coming on, Felix has sorted out his legs and moved up a cap after being parked for a while, it looks like progression out of this one will be quick.  Imogen’s gymnastics is coming on leaps and bounds (pun intended).  Julia and I resorted to blackmail to get Felix to sign up to the choir and learning ocarina - it paid off and he’s loving it. Imogen bought a flute (with her own savings!) her learning of music and skills have blown me away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its not all gravy though, the years events have taken their toll on me. The stress flared up my already bad stomach acid.  I finally went to the doctors who give me some great tummy tablets, which has stopped it in it’s tracks - totally life changing. However, I had to endure and endoscopy, which even with the sedative wasn’t the most pleasant experience.  I thought I came out quite well - I have a small hernia which helps explain the reflux.  Today, I got a letter today out the blue telling me I have a condition called Barretts Oesophagus.  Seems years of reflux has left its mark - that’ll teach me for not getting the doctors to sort it sooner. Apart from being a little freaked, mainly because googling it took me straight to the Macmillan website, I’m not sure what the ramifications are and time will tell, if its sinister or not - I’ll leave those things I can’t control aside until I get referred and find out more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing can stop the excitement mounting in the Lawley household! The advent calendars are emptying of chocolate at what feels like a speeded up rate.  I loved last years Christmas as it was the first one in the new house and the first one at home for us Lawleys.  This year I even get Julia to help! and I’m much looking forward to cementing tradition with a Christmas day pint down the Orange Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/been-a-while&quot;&gt;Its been a while&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 11, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retrospective]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/retrospective" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/retrospective</id>
  <published>2014-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s been quite odd to think that this time last year I was preparing for a course of events which would have such far reaching implications.&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t to know that my body wouldn’t be able to deal with the toxicity of the chemotherapy regime that had been selected for me, and that instead I’d have to have the infusions every week which would leave me with so little energy I would become a shadow of my former self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t to know that my hair would fall out over a period of weeks.  I had thought it would happen straight away.  I also wasn’t prepared for the uncomfortable wigs.  In the end, I just wore cotton hats, or wooly ones when I was outside, no one really knew on the school run that I was bald.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t to know that I would be told that I had a genetic abnormality which meant that my risks of getting breast cancer were increased from 1 in 10, to between 1 in 4 and 1 in 2.  At least with this information we were able to make informed decisions about further surgery, and resulted in having a risk reducing mastectomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t to know how wonderful Ross would be.  He stepped up to pretty much do everything associated with TeamRJ whilst my energy levels dropped to all time lows.  I know he found it tough at times, but he was always able to call on the Gin Club Dad’s to go for a cheeky pint and bend someone’s ear.  Or just talk about normal things.  Normal is so underated.  Love you. x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t to know how brilliantly the Bairns would deal with everything.  Despite having the rug pulled from under them, they have been fantastic.  Imogen and Felix got star reports at the end of the school year, and have settled into the new school year well.  I have always been a believer in that things are only scary if you don’t understand them.  They knew I went to hospital every Friday for Chemo and come home and go to sleep.  This worried them.  So, they came with me a few times.  They saw what happened, a small needle inserted into my port and then bags of what looked like water dripped in.  No big deal.  No longer scary.  They skyped me when I was in hospital after I’d had my surgery, and they came to see me when I was feeling up to it.  They make me so proud and I love them so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t to know a lot of things, and to be honest, some of them, I might have been happy not to know.  But I’m here, I’m ok and that’s what counts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of 1 year anniversary’s happening over the next few weeks.  1 year since I had my port implanted, 1 year since I had my first chemotherapy and herceptin, 1 year since I was in A&amp;amp;E with horrific chest pains caused by the chemotherapy, the list goes on.  Anyone who has spent any time with me over the past year will know that it hasn’t been plain sailing, it hasn’t been a walk in the park, but neither has it been all completely horrific.  There’s been good times along the way, and to each of you who has supported us, I offer my heartfelt thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/retrospective&quot;&gt;Retrospective&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 06, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[November Newbies]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/november-newbies" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/november-newbies</id>
  <published>2014-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">A post all of it&#39;s own, because they deserve it.&lt;p&gt;I started Chemo in November last year and stumbled upon the Breast Cancer Care forum.  There was a thread where any ladies who started Chemo in November 2013 could chat about side effects, surgery, wigs or just general cancer or non-cancer related things. Through this forum, I was invited to join a Facebook group where we could discuss things privately. At times discussing things that we felt we couldn’t share with anyone else, because no one else could understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you how amazing these women are.  Each on their own rather crappy journey, but each and every one of them giving and receiving support when it’s been needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some had surgery before chemo, some after, some had Herceptin, some had rads, no two journey’s are the same. But we were all there, at the end of a computer, sometimes in the middle of the night, helping one another through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, we lost one of our NN’s, Rachel.  She was one of a kind, only 42 with two beautiful children.  She had a wicked sense of humour and told us some hilarious stories.  The whole group is devastated.  We all knew the statistics, and despite the fact we’d all been on the wrong side of a cancer diagnosis, some of which happened at a very young age, this wasn’t supposed to happen. This wasn’t in the script. I’m on the road to recovery, I expect all the November Newbies to be so too.  Unfortunately, this isn’t the case, and it sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachel, we miss you.  Fly high with laughter on your wings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/november-newbies&quot;&gt;November Newbies&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 06, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Because I can...]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mundungus" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mundungus</id>
  <published>2014-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">And because this is what the Internet is for...&lt;p&gt;Here’s a photo of our new Itty Bitty Kitty, Mundungus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mundungus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mundungus&quot; /&gt;

Jx
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mundungus&quot;&gt;Because I can...&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 06, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once around the Sun]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/once-around-the-sun" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/once-around-the-sun</id>
  <published>2014-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">So, here we on on my 1 year Cancerversary.&lt;p&gt;One year since hearing those words that have turned my life upside down. “It’s Cancer.”  The disbelief, how can this happen to me? I was only 36, with a husband and two bairns who needed me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that year, I’ve had:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A port implanted to allow for easier administration of drugs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 lots of surgery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 genetics consultation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;24 appointments with Consultants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11 CT/MRI/ECG scans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At least 10 blood tests.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 doses of chemotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14 doses of Herceptin, (4 to go!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 radiotherapy sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 trip to A&amp;amp;E with chest pains.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;275+ daily Tamoxifen tablets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve lost my hair, and it’s growing back curly!&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve spent a lot of time in bed as I’ve struggled with fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve walked the Race for Life 5k with the Gin Club, and together we raised over £2800 for Cancer Research.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve completed the Standalone 10k road race with Michelle.&lt;br /&gt;
We’ve had a wonderful family holiday to Center Parcs.&lt;br /&gt;
We’ve been on a really special day out to London courtesy of the Willow Foundation.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve left my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general friends and family, old and new, real life and internet weirdies have been amazing. The support we’ve received has ranged from babysitting and providing meals to hugs, flowers, and just well timed messages. I’m not going to dwell on those that have let us down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I will be celebrating with the Gin Club, and looking forward to getting through the next few months which will bring the end of active treatment, and hopefully reconstruction surgery. I’m still here, albeit not quite in one piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over half term we are going on holiday with my Dad and Julie, and we get to be a normal family. (Even though we’ve never been a normal family!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who has been on this journey with us so far. It’s been a marathon, but we’ll get there. And I’ll just keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/once-around-the-sun&quot;&gt;Once around the Sun&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 23, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charity Netball Tournament]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/charity-netball" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/charity-netball</id>
  <published>2014-09-08T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-09-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The Gin Club decided to field a team in a local netball tournament.&lt;p&gt;In a moment of insanity, I agreed to join the team, along with Michelle, Charli, Rachel, Anna and James.  I haven’t played netball in a long time, but as the aim was to raise money for Macmillan, I thought I’d give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to yesterday morning.  We arrived, registered, paid our £5, got our bibs on and  before long we were actually playing.  It was fun.  I played Wing Attack, and once I remembered the rules, soon got into the swing of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played 5 games, won one, drew one, lost the rest, but it didn’t overly matter, we knew we weren’t going to win.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was being organised by the cousin of a lady who is currently undergoing treatment for breast cancer.  At a break in our games I went to talk to her.  As it turns out she has the same consultants as I do, although she see’s them at a different hospital.  I haven’t met anyone locally who is going through Breast Cancer and who is near to me in age.  I have met some wonderful ladies online (Big Up! November Newbies), some of whom are about my age, and I know relatives and friends who have been through this, but they tend to be older.  I don’t wish this horrible disease on anyone, but it was nice to meet such a lovely lady, who seemed so positive and was even playing netball whilst in the middle of chemotherapy.  I don’t think I would have been able to do it.  We had a good chat about what treatment we were both having, the consultants, etc. and also about wigs, hats and hair.  I wish her well with her treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we finished playing I came home and pretty much vegged for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning aching!  All over!  It hurts to walk, sit down, get up. Stairs?  Ouch!  I’ve had to take a couple of painkillers.  What a plonker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh well, it’s all helping me to get my fitness back.  I’ve got 4 weeks until the Standalone 10k run.  I’ve got a 5k in the bag and hopefully tomorrow I’ll be able to get a short run in before a longer run on Thursday.  My prediction is that I’ll be very near the back of the finishers, if not the last.  But do you know what?  Just finishing will be good enough.  Especially after the year I’ve had.  The race is nearly one year to the day I had the ultrasound, mammogram and biopsy which lead to my cancer diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may need some support on the day though, Ross will be with the bairns at their first rugby festival of the season.  He was supposed to be running with me, but he needs to support the bairns.  Any volunteers?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/charity-netball&quot;&gt;Charity Netball Tournament&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 08, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back To School]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-school" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-school</id>
  <published>2014-09-03T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-09-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">All too soon, the holidays are over and it&#39;s back to school.&lt;p&gt;I’m probably in the minority here, but I don’t think the holidays were long enough.  Just as we got into the swing of things, it was time for them to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, they are very excited about this.  Felix is looking forward to playing with his friends again, and Imogen is looking forward to learning to play the flute.  I am going to have to find myself things to do during the day whilst they aren’t here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross is going to have to come with my to my appointments again.  The bairns came with me the last couple of times I had Herceptin.  It’s quite nice to sit in a room with them and listen to them chatter on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/back2school.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beautiful Bairns&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-school&quot;&gt;Back To School&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 03, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Duck N Dash]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/duck-n-dash" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/duck-n-dash</id>
  <published>2014-08-31T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-08-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">As the final days of the summer holidays pass, Imogen makes the most of it.&lt;p&gt;One thing that helps us maintain the facade of being a ‘normal’ family, is having things to focus on.  Back in May, Ross decided to sign Imogen up for a Aquathlon called the Duck N Dash.  It’s organised by a local Triathlon club, and involves a swim in the outdoor pool and then a run round the common.  Ross has done the adult version before, and given how active Imogen is, thought she’d enjoy it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for Imogen, she picked up an ear infection and perforated ear drum in June which meant she was unable to swim.  She missed weeks of swimming lessons and wasn’t even allowed to get her ear wet when she washed her hair.  Finally on the 14th August, she was given the all clear to swim again.  Her ear had healed, the infection was gone, and she was good to go!  Then another spanner in the works, rugby training started on the same day!  She’s moving into the Under 9 age group which involves contact and tackling.  She’s the only girl on the team, so we wanted to make sure she was there at the very start of the season so she could get the most out of the training sessions so she was confident enough to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, due to the lack of swimming, and because of rugby, we decided she wasn’t going to do it.  She was a bit disappointed, but understood why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday evening, Ross got an email with the start times.  Because everyone has their own individual start time, Imogen was due to start at 9:02am.  She had to swim one length of a 50m pool, and then do a 600m run.  I know how fast she can swim, and I know how fast she can run 600m as we’d practiced that distance during the holidays, so reckoned she’d be finished by 9:15am and have enough time to get changed and to rugby for the start of training.  It was all back on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday afternoon, Ross and Imogen went to the outdoor pool to register, pick up her number, her chip she had to wear around her ankle and have the number ‘13’ written in permanent marker on her arm and leg.  The people from Freedom Tri were on hand to give her some information on the transition and also where she’d have to run.  This was really helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening she practiced putting her shoes and socks on quickly and got herself prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday morning, we were up early and all had a fortifying breakfast.  The sun was shining, it was a beautiful day for it.  We got there early and Imogen went to set up her transition gear.  I realised at this point, we’d forgotten her goggles!  Panic!  A quick dash home to collect them and she was ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/duckndash_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Getting In The Zone&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 9:00am, the first competitor started, Imogen’s friend Freddie from school.  Also taking part was Jenson from the Gin Club, and Daniel from her rugby squad.  There were 16 in total in her age group.  They all looked really confident, and it was great to see them competing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 9:02am, she was in and got off to a great start.  She overtook a couple on the swim and was out and putting her shoes and t-shirt on before I knew it.  I have to admit to being a bit shouty at this point.  Anyone who knows me, will tell you that I can be quite loud.  I think I drew a few funny looks as I stood on the opposite side of the pool, shouting like a Fish Wife “Hurry up Imogen!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She ran out the pool onto the common where Ross was waiting to cheer her on.  I raced round and got to the end just in time to see her cross the line.  I was so proud.  She did so well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We waited for Daniel and Jenson to cross the line so we could cheer them on, and then raced to get changed and off to rugby.  We didn’t hang around to find out her time, its the old saying, it’s the taking part that counts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rugby training went really well for both Imogen and Felix.  Felix slotted straight back in with his friends and spent an hour and a half running around, chasing balls, and having fun.  Imogen listened carefully to her coaches as the started giving instructions on how to tackle safely and confidently.  They both got registered for the new season and wore their new Letchworth Rugby Club t-shirts with pride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once training was over we had to go back to the outdoor pool to collect Imogen’s towel and goggles.  We still didn’t know what time she’d done it in, and couldn’t find anyone to ask, so we just went home, and Imogen went to Katy’s pamper party for a bit of girly time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all went to bed exhausted that night, and I’d just dropped off when Ross’s phone beeped with an email telling us the times had been published.  We had a quick look and were delighted to find Imogen had won her category!  Girls Under 8 Duck N Dash champion.  We were so proud.  She did it in 6 minutes and 6 seconds!  What a girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/duckndash2_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Champion&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/duck-n-dash&quot;&gt;Duck N Dash&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on August 31, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>