<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2017-09-20T12:37:17+01:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Versions of Me]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/version-of-me" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/version-of-me</id>
  <published>2017-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">In June this year, when we received the news that the cancer had spread again, Imy was upset that I was going to lose my hair again.&lt;p&gt;She said that she didn’t like the “No Hair” version of me, and that she wished it didn’t have to happen.  We explained that it was an unfortunate inevitability to my treatment, and it was better to lose my hair, than let the cancer grow any more, and I wouldn’t be bald forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then got into a discussion about different versions of me, and I’ve decided to document it in pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-1&quot;&gt;Version 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the Pre-Cancer version of me.  I was working 4 days a week as a Software Team Leader.  Family life was good.  I had Friday as my Mummy Day and we were in a good routine with the kids enjoying their swimming, gymnastics, Little Ruggers, etc.  Then we sere served a curve ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-2&quot;&gt;Version 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is me during my Primary Breast Cancer treatment.  Treatment that involved two lots of surgery, (Sentinal Node Biopsy and Double Mastectomy), chemotherapy, Herceptin, radiotherapy and hormone therapy. From diagnosis in October 2013, to finishing Herceptin in 2015, I had treatment for 15 grueling months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-3&quot;&gt;Version 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is me when I finished most of my primary treatments (except Herceptin) and was adjusting to the New Normal.  During this time I had 2 lots of surgery, an Oophorectomy and my DIEP reconstruction.  It gave us time to regroup and take a long needed breath of fresh air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-4&quot;&gt;Version 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the version of me that was diagnosed with Secondary Breast Cancer in January 2016.  Only giving me 12 months as Version 3.  When I was in so much pain that I would wake up screaming with the pain, and when I had to have two weeks in the Garden House Hospice to get it under control.  I had been put on enough Morphine to fell an elephant.  I had surgery to remove and reconstruct a vertebrae after it collapsed, and started the long road to recovery with a few clear scans in between.  Things were starting to look up.
I was able to have an extended celebration for my 40th birthday with friends and family.  By June 2017, I felt the best I had done since Version 3, but then we had another curve ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-5&quot;&gt;Version 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/version5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Version5&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the current version of me.  The version that has just finished another course of chemotherapy.  I have no hair, although as I’ve finished, it is growing back, and I am struggling with low mood and fatigue.  Hopefully with support of my medical team, this version won’t last long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-6&quot;&gt;Version 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the future version of me, when I will still be dealing with Secondary cancer, but I’ll have my hair back, and look more like Version 1 or 3.  Hopefully it won’t be too long, at least until I have a covering of hair so I don’t feel I have to cover up with a hat/scarf or wig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/version-of-me&quot;&gt;Versions of Me&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 20, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemo Catch-up, etc.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/catchup" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/catchup</id>
  <published>2017-09-07T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-09-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Since the last post I&#39;ve finished chemo, the kids have had their school holidays, we&#39;ve been on our highly anticipated family summer holiday and Imy has started a new school.&lt;p&gt;For some reason it’s harder to write the blog posts now than it was when I was dealing with my Primary diagnosis nearly 4 years ago.  I don’t know if it’s because I’ve done a lot of it before, fatigue, or general “Cantbearseditis”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last post, I’ve finished my course of chemo and am now completely bald.  To be fair, there’s a little bit of fluff, but not much.  I got to ring the End of Treatment Bell at the hospital - very exciting!.  It was a bit of a cheat really, as although I’d finished the course of 7 sessions of chemo, I will still be returning to the unit every 3 weeks for Herceptin, Zoledronic Acid and Perjeta.  Technically my treatment will never end, so I took this opportunity to ring that bell!&lt;br /&gt;
(Note the hat, I crocheted that myself out of bamboo yarn!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FSpireHarpendenHospital%2Fvideos%2F2195347237157793%2F&amp;amp;show_text=1&amp;amp;width=560&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;528&quot; style=&quot;border:none;overflow:hidden&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late July, Imy finished primary school.  She’s not going to the same secondary school as the majority of her old classmates, so during the Leavers Assembly, she got very tearful.  There was lots of hugs and love being shared. Later on in the day they all got together at our local Muddy Obstacle Arena, where they had one last blow out together which involved lots of water, mud, laughs and daftness.  It was a great way to end her time at a lovely school.  A school that holds lots of fond memories and which has supported her when she needed supporting the most.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fast forward to Tuesday this week, and she started secondary school.  She has to get up just before 7am (she’s not a morning person) so she can catch the train there.  The majority of her primary school classmates decided to go to the local secondary school, but Imy preferred the Girl’s School, the downside being a longer commute.  Ross accompanied her on the train on her first day, her friend’s mum went with them yesterday, and today they went by themselves - armed with their travel passes. Already so independent!  They get the 7:54am train in the morning, walk for 15 minutes from the station to school and then return home at about 4:10pm in the afternoon.  So far, she’s loving it, making lots of new friends, and enjoying the new experiences.  Long may it continue!  I really do think it’ll be great for her and allow her to unlock all the potential she has.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/newschool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New School&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
During the summer holiday’s we tried to continue as normal, and the kids had a lot of free time whilst I recovered from the weekly chemo sessions.  They went on a rugby camp, spent a few days with their Granny and Grandad Lawley, and saw their cousins which was fun as it involved sleeping in a tent in Uncle Rich’s garden!&lt;br /&gt;
My Dad and Julie came down for a visit, and amongst other fun things, took the kids out to the zoo, and to the local trampolining centre.  Dad also did a few bits of DIY that Ross hadn’t had time to do.&lt;br /&gt;
Then before we knew it, we were off on our holiday to Portugal!  We had thought about cancelling it when we got the news of the cancer spread, but my Oncologist said he would work the treatment dates around it, and that it would be best all around if we went on holiday. Doctor’s Orders!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m so glad we went.  We’d rented a villa with it’s own pool, in the middle of no-where on the Algarve, about an hour away from Faro through James Villas.  We hired a car and therefore we were on our own timetable, could eat when we wanted, go in the pool when we wanted, explore if and when we wanted, and it was a resounding success.  We all had a great time.  A lot of time was spent at the villa, just relaxing (and swimming).  But we did go out and about to have a look at a few beaches, look at some tourist shops, ate out a few times and navigate around a huge hypermarket, marveling at the local delicacies…chicken toes anyone?  It was a fabulous holiday which we will remember for a long time to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/portugalaug2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Portugal Holiday&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I think that brings us up to date.  The day after we got back, I was back on treatment, and this afternoon I’m off to have an MRI to see if the chemo/Perjeta has made any difference to the two new spots.  Fingers crossed!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/catchup&quot;&gt;Chemo Catch-up, etc.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 07, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shovel List]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/shovel-list" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/shovel-list</id>
  <published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">In Marian Keyes&#39; book, The Mystery of Mercy Close, we meet the main character, Helen Walsh.&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently listened to this book which I borrowed as a digital download from the library for free.  Clever stuff, but I digress…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helen has a “Shovel List”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A shovel..?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“No, a shovel list. It’s more of a conceptual thing. It’s a list of all the people and things I hate so much I want to hit them in the face with a shovel.” [^fn]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a similar list for a while, but since reading the book I have been inspired to give it the name ‘The Shovel List’.  A small part of it is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wine being referred as “Vino”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calling someone “Hun”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The word “Bliss”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The phrase “I can’t believe it’s been &lt;em&gt;insert time period&lt;/em&gt; since &lt;em&gt;insert event&lt;/em&gt;”.  E.g.  “I can’t believe it’s been 11 years since I was in labour with Imy!  Where did the time go!?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I may have mentioned these peeves before in a previous blog post, but I can’t find it.  If I find it, I’ll add the link here.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I’m going to break my rule and say “I can’t believe it’s been a month since my last blog post”.  In that blog post, I was saying how we didn’t have a set plan in place for the next part of treatment and that we’d just have to wait and see, and it was business as usual until then including the bairns birthday party, Imy’s 11th birthday and Ross’s 40th birthday.  Great fun on all fronts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/muddybirthdays.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Muddy Birthday Party Fun&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 68%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ross40.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ross is 40&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 28%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; New Treatment Regime&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The treatment regime is changing by adding Perjeta (Pertuzumab – HER2 targeted) alongside the 3 weekly Herceptin (Trastuzumab - HER2 targeted) and Zoledronic acid (bone strengthener).  This combination will be ongoing until it doesn&#39;t or stops working.  In addition, I&#39;m having a course of up to 7 sessions of chemotherapy (Paclitaxel ), which I&#39;ll receive weekly.
&lt;br /&gt;
My first Perjeta was on Tuesday 27th June, with the chemo starting the day after.  There’s been one Perjeta and three chemo sessions since, and so far, things are going to plan, with only minor side effects in the form of an upset stomach and an increase in fatigue levels.
&lt;br /&gt;
Thankfully, and helpfully, my Dad came down to stay for the first week so he could take some of the weight by the kids to and from school and feeding us all. Grandma Julie came down this week for my third chemo session to help out in the same way. (In fact she&#39;s just gone home :-( ). It was one less thing for Ross and myself to worry about. Thank you both for coming and helping, it really does take the pressure off Ross, who is working full-time and accompanying me to my appointments, and stops me from &quot;sweating the small stuff&quot;.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Going, Going, Going...&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Since Monday, my hair has started falling out.  It started slowly, but it&#39;s now coming out in handfuls.  I washed my hair on Wednesday, and I couldn&#39;t believe (Shovel List) how much came out whilst washing, brushing and drying.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/goodbye_hair.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goodbye Hair&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 68%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I have a lot of hair, so despite there being hair shed all over the house, there&#39;s still quite a lot on my head.  I&#39;m having to wear a hat for bed as I&#39;ve woken up with so much hair on my pillow I made me quite upset.  The hair is collateral damage.  Another local Mum, Donna, who also has Stage 4 Cancer and looking at yet another lot of chemo and hair loss says, when it comes to the choice of Hair or Death, it&#39;s a no brainer.  (Check out her blog here:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://itsallgonetitsoff.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;It&#39;s All Gone Tit&#39;s Off. &lt;/a&gt;  She&#39;s amazing.)
&lt;br /&gt;
After seeing how much hair had come out on Wednesday, and after it had been recommended, I went to see &lt;a href=&quot;http://cancerhaircare.com/&quot;&gt; Cancer Hair Care&lt;/a&gt; in Stevenage to seek their advice. Having such a marvelous resource so close, I&#39;m annoyed with myself that I hadn&#39;t gone when I had chemo previously!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My visit was very successful and I came away with a lot of information. From looking after my hair as it falls out, how to care for my scalp, recommendations for scalp/hair products, a couple of head coverings, and best of all, a new wig that actually suited me! &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d bought a wig off the Internet in 2014, but it didn&#39;t look right, so I didn&#39;t wear it. I took it with me to see if they could do anything with it, as amongst everything else they do, they work with the hair salon next door to offer a cutting service. The lady was very honest with me and told me that my wig was never going to look right: it was too heavy, too shiny and too big for my head as I have no forehead. Not to be defeated, she disappeared for a few minutes before reappearing with a wig which was very similar to a previous hairstyle I&#39;ve had.  Win! A few adjustments to the fringe and I now have a wig that I can wear should I go somewhere where I think a wig would be more appropriate than a hat or scarf.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The services I received were for a nominal donation. Considering how much wigs can cost, it has saved a lot of money, but it&#39;s not about the money, it&#39;s about how they treated me with dignity and respect from the moment I stepped into the room. All the ladies who were working for the charity had all lost their hair through chemo, so they knew how I was feeling. They were so knowledgeable and empathetic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To anyone who is local to Stevenage and faces losing their hair, I wholeheartedly recommend them. Not only can you pop into their studio, but they run sessions at Barnet Hospital, Chase Farm Hospital in Enfield, Lister Hospital in Stevenage and the Princess Alexandra Hospital in Essex.&lt;br /&gt;
And to everyone else, if you see a charity box for them, stick a bit of spare change in it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[^fn] http://www.mariankeyes.com/books/the-mystery-of-mercy-close &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/shovel-list&quot;&gt;Shovel List&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on July 14, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last still counts.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-still-counts" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-still-counts</id>
  <published>2017-07-09T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">On Sunday 9th June, accompanied by a group of friends, I managed to complete the Race For Life.  &lt;p&gt;I had warned my fellow Racers, (ladies from my work, school Mum’s and original Gin Club Members),  that I would be walking very slowly and wouldn’t be surprised if I finished towards the back of the crowd.  As it turns out, I finished last!  (There were ladies doing the 10km run, so we weren’t the final ones to cross the line). I felt no shame in coming last, in fact, I was very pleased to have actually finished!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rfl_2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Race For Life 2017&quot; /&gt;
Photo credits. Top and bottom left:  James McClung.  Bottom right:  Ross Lawley
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a previous life, I was quite good at doing a 5km, (ok I was never the fastest, but I could do them with fairly little training involved), and I’ve got a fair few medals!  However, after last year’s surgery on my spine, the new tumour in my hip, treatment related fatigue and the new chemo regime, this year was always going to be a lot tougher.  I don’t think I appreciated how hard it would be, though.  Mentally as well as physically.  But after about an hour and a quarter, my walking buddies, Caroline, Rachel, Rebecca, Rachel and myself, accompanied by the cheers of the crowds, we crossed the line.  I was hugged by Courtney, the CRUK Event Coordinator, and the rest of the teamies who had waited around for me to finish.  I kept a lid on things until I got a hug from Ross, but that was the final straw and I was reduced to a blubbering mess, moaning about my hurty hip. (You can probably see from my face in the photo how much pain I was in.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once home, after a shower, I went to bed, and didn’t get up until the next morning.  In years gone by, I’d have gone to a beer garden to celebrate the Race’s success, but this year, I had to bow out and the celebrations had to go on without me.  Thankfully, my hip hasn’t been hurting as a consequence of the Race, so I’m pretty pleased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundraising page is still open, so if anyone has any spare pennies &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mariankeyes.com/books/the-mystery-of-mercy-close&quot;&gt; head over here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-still-counts&quot;&gt;Last still counts.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on July 09, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holidays, Birthdays & Bad News]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/holidays-birthdays-bumps" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/holidays-birthdays-bumps</id>
  <published>2017-06-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-06-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">As a family, the past month has been great!&lt;p&gt;Over half term Felix turned 9, and we went on holiday to Norfolk.  We didn’t quite march the kids for miles as we’ve done on holidays in the past, but we did go for short walks and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.treasuretrails.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Treasure Trails&lt;/a&gt;, which were great fun.  We went for a (very short) swim in the sea, caught some crabs off Cromer Pier, ate out for Felix’s birthday treat and had a thoroughly relaxing time.  In fact it’s fair to say, that apart from the fatigue, I’m feeling the best I have in 18 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/norfolkmay2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norfolk Holiday&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad and Julie came down to visit for the weekend to look after the kids whilst Ross and I went off to a fancy hotel as a joint 40th present from them. I’d managed to forget my handbag, so after an emergency run to Boots for a private prescription (top tip: carry your repeat prescription with you, or have it in the car at all times), and then a purchase of a new handbag, we were able to relax.  We had a great time - saw a man walking his parrot down the street, we drank cocktails, ate like lords, chatted, laughed a lot and saw Rod Stewart in a garden centre on the way home.  Thank you Dad &amp;amp; Julie. xx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/downhall2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Down Hall&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we went to see the Oncologist for the results of the scan I’d had the week before.  Given how well I’m feeling, we were quite optimistic, but as it turns out, that optimism was misplaced.  The scan has picked up two new tumours, one in my shoulder and one in my hip.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple of weeks, the change in treatment will be finalised, and I may have to have another course of chemo.  I don’t know the full details as it’s being decided between my Oncologist and the health insurance company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s fair to say, that Ross and I are both gutted.  We had thought we were on a winning streak, and things would continue on an even keel.  Sadly, this is not to be.  Family and friends are rallying once again, getting ready to step into the breach should Ross and I need any help. Help that is completely priceless, and for which we are very thankful and humbled by.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, whilst we wait, I’m keen to keep things as normal as possible, and then we’ll deal with whatever happens next when it happens.  But first things first, family life goes on, and we’ve got Imy and Felix’s joint birthday party on Saturday to organise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/holidays-birthdays-bumps&quot;&gt;Holidays, Birthdays & Bad News&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Headaches & Flashbacks]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/headaches-flashbacks" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/headaches-flashbacks</id>
  <published>2017-05-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-05-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">For the third time in 10 months I&#39;ve been trying to come off Morphine.&lt;p&gt;** &lt;strong&gt;I wrote this post at the beginning of May but didn’t get around to publishing it.  Better late than never!&lt;/strong&gt; **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The surgeon who did my back operation has said that he wouldn’t be surprised if I am permanently on painkillers.  The surgery was very invasive, and caused a lot of trauma around my spine.  In an area that has a lot of nerves, it’s logical to expect that painkillers would be on the cards long term.  Except, for me, I don’t want to take the painkillers.  I don’t want to take Morphine long term, for no other reason than failure to stop taking the painkillers is just that - Failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is completely illogical.  I know there are no prizes for not taking painkillers.  For grinning and bearing it.  But I don’t want to be reliant on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly, I’ve reduced the Morphine and instead of being on 130mg twice a day, as I was before my surgery, (enough to knock a grown man off his feet), I’m now on 10mg twice a day.  I’ve also stopped taking Gabapentin for nerve pain, and Naproxen which is similar but stronger than Ibuprofen.  Two weeks ago, I tried to swap the Morphine for Codeine.  Previously, I’d taken it before with no problems, but this time it gave me an incredible headache.  I managed a week on codeine before I relented and went back to the Morphine.  Unfortunately, my Headache didn’t get the memo and I’m still suffering with the headaches.  Hopefully with time, they’ll get better.  Of course, it doesn’t stop me thinking that the Cancer has come back.  I’ve developed a bit of hip pain too, which is annoying.  I have a scan in 4 weeks so all will be clear then.  I’m not bringing it forward…what happens happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every so often I find a photo and I try and think when it was taken.  Was it before the Shit hit the fan?  Or was it in the period before, when life was normal?  When it was straightforward?  I sometimes forget than Felix was only 5 when I was diagnosed the first time.  5 -  only in Year One.  Imy was 7, and in Year 3.  So small.  Like yesterday, but forever at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to think back to what you remember about being in Year 1.  What about before that?  It breaks my heart that my kids will have there childhood memories tainted by Cancer.  I shouldn’t have to explain to my eight-year-old boy that there is no Stage 5 Cancer.  Stage 4 is the highest it goes.  No-one goes from Stage 4 Cancer to nothing, even though technically I have No Evidence of Disease, it basically means the cancer cells aren’t big enough to be picked up in a scan, and that the treatment regime is keeping everything under control.  It can turn on a sixpence, and I could be on chemo before you can say “My Goodness!  What rotten Luck!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as life goes on, we’re planning our holiday in Norfolk, Felix’s birthday, shortly followed by Imy’s and then Ross’s.  Busy, busy.  Live is for living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/headaches-flashbacks&quot;&gt;Headaches & Flashbacks&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Singing, SATs and Flying Solo]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-sats-solo" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-sats-solo</id>
  <published>2017-05-11T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-05-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The past few weeks have been quite busy!&lt;p&gt;The Bank Holiday weekend saw the 10th Independent Baldock Beer Festival take place.  This event is a firm Lawley favourite, having been to them all so far.  Over the past 3 years, we’ve started volunteering as well as being (very) willing customers.  Ross is a dab hand behind the bar now, and I decided that this year, I’d have a go too.  It was fun!  I selected the Cider and Wine bar as it was quieter, the drinks easier to pour, and I can now tick “Work behind a Bar” off my Bucket List.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My choir, Singing Aloud, performed at the Festival, and it was great to be part of something that had such good feedback. Very generously, the choir gave their performance fee to the Garden House Hospice which has helped my family and I so much over the past year and a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following week involved both bairns going to their Rugby Award’s Ceremony.  As Imy is part of a junior team which is a collaboration of three rugby clubs, she went off for an evening sit down formal do on a school night!  I had bought her a lovely dress to wear, but after a conversation with her teammates, it seemed jeans, funky t-shirts and high tops were the order of the day.  She did relent to wearing some makeup.  (Unusually for a 10 year old girl, she doesn’t like wearing make up!)  She came home delighted to have been nominated for Most Improved Player and was very happy for the person who won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix’s awards were an altogether different affair, as it was for the Mini’s section, and they were a bit rowdier!  They had a few fun games to start with, and then it was time for the awards bit.  There were 6 age groups, and at least 3 prizes per age group, so it took a bit of time to get through…
Felix picked up the under 9’s Tackle Machine award and the Player’s Player Of The Year award.  He was also nominated for Player of The Year, and so came back with two trophies and lots of sweets.  He was so chuffed, and I was so proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross now coaches Felix’s age group, but unfortunately due to him having to go to New York, he was unable to see Felix pick up his awards, or collect his own gift of Beer for giving up his Sunday morning’s to train the kids.  More on that in a bit.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/felix_rugbyawards2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Felix Awards&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week has been the week of Imy’s SATs.  We decided that the weekend preceding it was not to be for school work, but for fun.  We knew we had the rugby awards to look forward to, and planned a visit to the Splash Park too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning, the postman brought us a rather unexpected parcel. On Facebook, I had seen an advert for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/mrsbeesemporium&quot;&gt;Mrs Bee’s Emporium&lt;/a&gt;, and she was sending out good luck letters and small token gift to the kids doing their SATs.  I thought this was a brilliant idea, so I ordered one for Imy, to show how much we were thinking about her.  However, when it arrived, the parcel was A LOT BIGGER than I had expected.  Little did I know that a group of ladies who I knew from years ago, on an online forum, had decided to club together and get a gift of a Pug, Star and Letter for Imy, a Pug for Felix and a Star and Letter for me.  Once a few dots had been joined and we realised what had happened, Ross and I both had to have a moment!  Sometimes we are so engrossed in being in The Eye Of The Storm, and just getting through the day, that we forget that we have a legion of people rooting for us, and understanding that, yes, all families with Year 6 kids are under pressure, but we’ve got an extra layer of unpleasantness going on. Imy has had the star in her pocket all week, and my star has been close to hand too. The gifts were completely unexpected, and very much appreciated.  Thank you. xx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mrsbee_starspugs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mrs Bee&#39;s Gifts&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so we get to this week.  The week of the Dreaded SATs.  In an unfortunate piece of bad timing, Ross had to be in the US with work.  So it was up to me to steer the Lawley ship solo. The first time I’ve had to do it on my own for some time.  It’s Thursday, and we’ve done ok!  Everyone has got to where they need to be, on time, wearing the appropriate clothes.  All tummies have been filled with easy to cook meals, and I have only had to call in help once to get Felix to school on Wednesday morning.  I’m very tired, so anything that hasn’t been absolutely necessary, has not been done.  It can wait.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one sense it’s good that I have proven to myself that I am capable of doing things on my own, but it has also made me appreciate how much Ross does when he’s around, and how much I rely on him.  In general, he takes the kids to school, and will pick them up if I’m too tired.  I try and make all meals, but he will step in if it looks like dinner isn’t going to cook itself.  He’s back tomorrow, and it can’t come soon enough.  I’m looking forward to an epic nap!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imy has taken the SATs, so far, in her stride, and we’ll all be thankful when the last one is over and she can go back to being a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as always, we’ll just keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/singing-sats-solo&quot;&gt;Singing, SATs and Flying Solo&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 11, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'll Do It My Way]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/my-way" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/my-way</id>
  <published>2017-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Like most people, I follow some newspapers on Facebook to keep up to date with the news.&lt;p&gt;Last week The Independent, re-shared a story about a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/91-year-old-inspired-thousands-skipping-chemotherapy-to-go-on-end-of-life-road-trip-dies-a7345951.html?cmpid=facebook-post&quot; target=&quot;new&quot;&gt;a 90 year old American lady, Ms Bauerschmidt, who was diagnosed with uterine cancer&lt;/a&gt; in the summer of 2015 and rather than go along with the standard treatment of surgery, radiotherapy and chemotherapy, she decided that she would, instead, go on the roadtrip of a lifetime.  After a year on the road, driving 13,000 miles, staying in over 75 locations in 32 states, she died in October 2016.  The article wasn’t a sad one, it was a happy one.  Ms Bauerschmidt’s motto was “Say ‘Yes’ to Living”, and she packed in so much that year.  It looked like she had a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading the heartwarming article, it got me thinking about my treatment and if saying “No” to it was an option.  (Spoiler Alert…it’s not.)  Ms Bauerschmidt was 90 when she was diagnosed with her primary cancer.  I was 36, and at the time, Imy and Felix were 5 and 7.  Ross and I had been married for less than 10 years.  So, I decided to comment on the post and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p width=&quot;50%&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/TheIndependentOnline/posts/10154620732761636&quot; target=&quot;new&quot;&gt;&quot;I think if I was 90 and told that I had Stage 4 Cancer ( there is no Stage 5, it&#39;s already spread outside the primary cancer site) I would do that. But I&#39;m not. I&#39;m 40, with two young children and I need more time.&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in Internet Land, we all know there be ‘Trolls’, I’m not completely naive, but I didn’t expect, what I thought to be an innocuous comment, would receive some of the attention it did.  But I learned the hard way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headline of the article was “91-year-old who inspired thousands by skipping chemotherapy to go on end of life road trip dies”.  It’s slightly misleading.  She didn’t refuse chemo alone,  she refused all treatment options.  So my response wasn’t just based on a refusal of chemo, it was all treatments: biological; hormonal; chemo; radio; surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t expect anyone to even look at the comment, never mind give me their opinion on it. The majority of the comments were positive, encouraging ones: “I wish you well with your treatment.”, “You’re in my prayers.”, “All the best.”, etc.  Thank you people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good.  And then this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IndyComment1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comment 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hold on… what?  Chemo gives you cancer?  I need to find out what “caused” my cancer and cut it out? Kill off the elderly?  Holy Moly! This was something else!! I have learned over the years I’ve been on Facebook that sometimes it’s not about retaliating, it’s about just leaving things alone.  Except, how can I leave it alone?  This person has just jumped to huge conclusions about me and my treatment and decided to tell me how I should be living my life.  Erm…no.  I think not.  I had to acknowledge the comment as it was so preposterous and I think I was rather restrained in my reply!
FYI, when she is talking about MIM, she is referring to a directory that medics can refer to when they are prescribing drugs.  As ‘Normal Folk’, we won’t have access to it, or generally know what it is, but this lady is “Educated” so she knows what she’s talking about. (Sit down at the back…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IndyComment2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comment 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My original comment has been like over 300 times.  Most people get where I’m coming from.  And yet, this person comes back again.  Really?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IndyComment3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crazy comment&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 48%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IndyComment4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crazy comment etc&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 48%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;

I know I&#39;m going back on what I said about not commenting further by writing this blog post, but I&#39;m still astounded that someone would say something like that.  Keyboard Warriors, Trolls, whatever you want to call them hide behind a keyboard, spew their bile and vitriol, tell other people how to live their lives and what?  Expect to be thanked for it?  &lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m so sorry that this woman&#39;s mother died from cancer.  It is an unforgiving and nondiscriminating disease.  But millions of pounds are being poured into research to find a cure.  There is no conspiracy.  The drugs companies are not hiding the cure.  They *are* researching cannabis (but it&#39;s not a silver bullet).  The management of these companies are as affected by cancer as anyone else.  They will have friends and/or family that are diagnosed with it.  They gain nothing by sitting by and watching people die.  Five to ten years ago, without Herceptin, my prognosis would have been bleak.  I may not even have been here to write this blog post.  Where did Herceptin come from?  A big drugs company that ran proper clinical trials, and now it is a standard treatment for certain cancers.  More trials are being run as I type, so that treatments and maybe a cure are found.  My role in *my* Cancer Story has not been that of a sheep.  I have grilled my Oncologist at length about the treatments I have had and currently having.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One in two people will receive a cancer diagnosis at some point in their life. But!  We have more screenings available, more treatments are available and as a result more people are surviving the diagnosis and go on to live full and healthy lives.  The statistics tell us that people are living longer, but everyone has to die at some point.  No one is immortal.  It&#39;s one of the two givens in life.  That and taxes. Life expectancy was &quot;three score years and ten&quot; or 70.  I&#39;m 30 years away from that age, and the odds of me getting there are slim.  But, I&#39;m here for the foreseeable.  The treatments are doing their job and we are more positive about things.  Long may the treatment continue to work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And as the Queen song goes, &quot;Who wants to live forever...when love must die?&quot;  
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Jx
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/my-way&quot;&gt;I'll Do It My Way&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 30, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turning 40]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/turning-40" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/turning-40</id>
  <published>2017-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I made it!!!&lt;p&gt;There’s the “Life begins at 40” Crew, and then there’s the “Forty is over the hill” Party.  I’m just delighted to have made it into another decade of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, I’ve had such a lovely birthday, and it hasn’t just been limited to one day.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the run up to the Big Day, we went up to the North East to visit my family.  My brother Max couldn’t join us as he’s a teacher in Manchester and our half term’s didn’t match up.  However, Grandma Julie organised the rest of the family so that we had a meal out complete with birthday cake and fizz with her and my Dad, my two other brothers, Callum and Regan, and their families.  It was a very nice evening, and I was spoilt with very lovely and generous gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also managed to meet up with Karen and Alison who I’ve known since we met at 6th Form College and did a fair amount of underaged drinking together.  With five kids between us now, we had a more sober celebration, but it was enjoyable nonetheless.  It’s funny how no matter how much time passes between the times we get together, it’s like we met last week.  It’s just nice to meet up and know we’ll have a laugh.  I left with a massive 40 balloon, a full stomach and sore cheeks from laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18th February 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days up there, we were back home so I could wake up in my own bed on my birthday itself.  Ross and the kids made me an amazing breakfast of American pancakes with fruit, maple syrup and cream.  Delicious.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was then presented with an huge pile of gifts.  I was absolutely stunned.  Ross had been squirreling away parcels and cards that had been arriving whilst I’d been in the house, none the wiser.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, friends dropped in for a cuppa and a slice of cake. It was a bit of an open house, so people could come and go, and so I didn’t feel so overwhelmed.  There was a steady stream of people and a lot of cake was consumed. This has lead Felix to tell people that he has had cake every day for a week.  That’s not a bad thing for an eight year old boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t help draw comparisons between this year and last year when I had to be signed out of the Hospice so that Ross and I could go out for an evening meal and I didn’t make it to dessert before I was asking to go back.  This year, we booked a taxi and went somewhere a bit special and had the most expensive meal we have ever had in our life together.  We splashed out on a bottle of Champagne.  It was magnificent!!  And I felt very lucky not only to be there enjoying it, but having Ross there with me to share it with me.  He’s been amazing and deserves it just as much as me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The days after were spent recovering as I’m still suffering from fatigue which means I have to plan when I can do things and when I need to take a nap and generally try not to overdo it.  I can mostly do what I want to, but it has to be planned with military precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the medical side of things, I have had my 4 weekly Zoladex injection and also had to catch up on Herceptin and Zometa treatments which had been delayed for a week so that I could go away at half term.&lt;br /&gt;
I have had a heart scan, which I have to have every 3 months to check the Herceptin isn’t damaging it, which can happen, but in my case it isn’t.  The cardiologist thinks that if I was going to have any heart damage, it would have happened by now, so I’m pleased about that.&lt;br /&gt;
My regular blood tests have showed that my platelets are a bit on the low side of normal, so I’m not clotting particularly well after I’m pricked with needles.  This has lead to a few bloody incidents, and also large bruises.  Fun fun fun!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Max came down for a flying visit, which was fantastic although it was too short.  I’m now looking forward to a few more events that we’ve got planned.  Everything, right now, is ok.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all,  I’m enjoying being 40.  So far, so good!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/fortycake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40th Birthday Cake&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 58%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cakeandballoon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;More 40th Birthday Cake&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 38%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/turning-40&quot;&gt;Turning 40&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 07, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Results Are In.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clear-scan" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clear-scan</id>
  <published>2017-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">My latest scan has revealed there is no new cancer activity anywhere in my body.&lt;p&gt;This is great news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I not on Cloud Nine?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why aren’t I celebrating?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why can’t I accept the good news and be happy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends and family are all offering good wishes and I am surrounded by love.  I am extremely lucky in more ways than one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be turning 40 next week, and doesn’t life begin there? I’ve got a few things lined up with friends and family to help me celebrate.  At one point I didn’t think I’d get to 40.  But here I am, 10 days to go, and the world should be my oyster. Except I don’t feel it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to get to the bottom of why I’m not feeling “Happy as Larry”.  (Whoever Larry is, I’d like to meet him and ask him his secret.)  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it comes down to the fact that I feel so fatigued still, and I can’t seem to get back to normal.  The doctors, who are involved in my medical wellbeing, are trying to find a reason for this fatigue are certain that it is not due to there being any cancer lurking anywhere. The scan proves this.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what else can it be?  What can it be that leaves me waking in the morning feeling like I need another 5 hours sleep?  That leaves me asleep in front of the tv after spending a 4 or 5 hours doing software development work?  That if I want to watch the kids partake in any event or fixture, I have to work out whether I can fit a nap in?  On Sunday’s, if I feel up to watching the bairns play rugby, I often have to choose which one I watch, because I can’t do both.  They both understand this, but I wish it wasn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should I have to plan my weeks, and my family’s activities, around my energy levels?  I feel like I’m cheating them out of their childhood.  The fun with me has to be rationed, or else it happens without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not asking for sympathy.  I’m not having a ‘Pity Party’, I just want to enjoy being cancer free, for as long I am.  I want to enjoy these times in between scans.  I want to give Ross and the kids a better version of me.  They deserve better than the current version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clear-scan&quot;&gt;The Results Are In.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 08, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Herceptin #18]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Herceptin-18" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Herceptin-18</id>
  <published>2017-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This is the magic number that usually hails the end of treatment.&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, on the 8th January 2015, I had my 18th and last dose of Herceptin.  Or so we thought.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
18 doses of Herceptin is the standard course for anyone who has Stage 2 or 3 breast cancer which is HER2+. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macmillan.org.uk/cancerinformation/cancertypes/breast/aboutbreastcancer/typesandrelatedconditions/her2%20positive.aspx&quot;&gt;There’s more info on HER2+ breast cancer here.&lt;/a&gt; 1 in 4 breast cancer diagnosis are HER2+.  It’s not a nice type of cancer.  It likes to travel and it spreads quickly.  Herceptin was regarded as a wonder drug when it was first developed.  As it targets a specific cell type, it isn’t as brutal as traditional chemo.  It still has side effects though, and I find it fatigues me.  Two years ago, as we drew to the end of the course of treatment, we were counting down, “3 to go”, “2 to go”, “1 to go”, “We’re done!!”.  Yippee!!!  Get out the banners and balloons! We’re done!!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today, I had Herceptin no.18, only this time we are not counting down, we are counting up.  I want to have as many doses of them as possible, as that means that it’s keeping the cancer under control and stopping any new tumours from growing.  And crucially, we can maintain some sort of semblance of normal family life.  Herceptin is the least brutal of the treatments that are on the table for me now.  Long may this treatment regime continue.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/herceptin18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Herceptin 18&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the 3 monthly scan next week which will tell us if the treatment is working.  Fingers crossed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Update…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I find Timehop does one of two thing:  Pops up with boring statuses about the weather, the kids annoying me or something, or, alternatively, it comes up with something relevant.  Today it popped up with a couple of photos I took on the day of my (second) first Herceptin last year.  I looked awful!  And the port had only just been put in surgically, so it was still healing hence the extra plasters.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/oneyearon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;One Year On&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 49%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/newportacath.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Portacath&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 49%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;

I&#39;m not sure which photo I look better in, this years or last years...
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Herceptin-18&quot;&gt;Herceptin #18&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 25, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memories - with Voices]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/memories" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/memories</id>
  <published>2017-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">As a family, we have an uncertain future.&lt;p&gt;We live our lives in 3 month periods.  There’s an MRI at the beginning, followed by an appointment with the Oncologist, if it’s not good, we deal with it, if it is, we wait until the next scan.  So in these 3 month periods of calm, (and long may they continue), the idea is that we set up as many fun and interesting experiences for the family, and me as an individual or with friends, as we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current chunk of ‘Well Time’ included Christmas and visits from Grandad Mike and Grandma Julie and Uncle Max, a New Year’s Eve party, and a New Year’s Day party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took the opportunity to get the stairs and Felix’s room decorated, and then a new carpet put down on the stairs.  Things we’ve had in mind for ages, but haven’t got round to.  Now they are done, and we only have Ross’s study left to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw The Son’s of Pitches in St. Albans, we went to see Star Wars: Rogue One, and also to the panto, Peter Pan, at the Gordon Craig in Stevenage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imy is in her school choir, and they performed in a few Christmas concerts in churches in Stevenage and Baldock, but the highlight for Imy and the choir was singing at The O2.  You heard me right, The O2!  The arena which has seen Rihanna, Prince, Bon Jovi, Plácido Doming, Beyoncé, One Direction, Monty Python, The Spice Girls, 2012 Olympic Artistic Gymnastics, and Olympic and Paralympic Basketball finals, AND… Hartsfield JMI as part of the Young Voices Choir.  Amazing!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young Voices is a big organisation which signs up loads of schools, gets them to learn the same songs, have a rehearsal in the afternoon, and then perform to a packed arena audience in the evening.  There were nearly eight thousand children in the choir, and they perform on the night with a band, and special guests including Natalie Williams, who is well known on the live music circuit, The Beat Box Collective, and a very funky street dance crew.  But the real stars, the kids, were amazing.  We had such a great time.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/youngvoices02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Young Voices at The O2&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 58%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/youngvoiceimy02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Young Voices - Imy&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 38%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The programme and the ticket will be put in our Family Memory Box, because that&#39;s one heck of a memory for us all, not least for our songbird, Imy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We are drawing to the end of our current three month period which means the anxiety of the impending scan is increasing.  However, we are still planning on making as many memories as a family as we can, and have a few already in the diary for 2017.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/memories&quot;&gt;Memories - with Voices&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 20, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stage 4 Cancerversary]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-cancerversary" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-cancerversary</id>
  <published>2017-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The Queen has two birthday&#39;s, I have two Cancerversary&#39;s&lt;p&gt;If I’m honest I’d prefer just the one, but these are the cards I’ve been dealt, so if I have to have two, I might as well acknowledge them both. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On the 1st Cancerversary of my Stage 2 diagnosis in October 2014, I went out for a fancy lunch with my friends.  I was still having Herceptin, and probably had 3 or 4 more treatments to go, but after a year, I felt amazing. The chemo, the surgeries, the radiotherapy were all in the past.  We enjoyed good food, wine and laughs, and I picked up my kids from school feeling a little bit tiddley. And why shouldn’t I? I’d beaten the beast…or so I thought.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fast forward to January 2016.  After a CT scan the day before, I was called in to see my Oncologist to get the results.  Getting results that soon, Ross and I knew something was very wrong.  You don’t get called in that quickly for a slipped disk.  The thing is Ross and I had a copy of the CT scan on a CD and we couldn’t see anything…but how could we?  We didn’t know what to look for.  What was it that was wrong?  The scan picture below gives it away.  The L4 vertebrae was a slightly different shade of grey to the other vertebrae.  That’s it.  Thank goodness for Radiologist’s who know what to look for.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/l4naughtyvertebrae.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Naughty Vertebrae&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read the blog, you’ll know what has happened in the last year, and if I’m honest I didn’t want to acknowledge this Cancerversary in the same way as the Stage 2 1st Cancerversary.  This one is different.  It isn’t a happy occasion.  I’m still having treatment, just like last time, but this time there is no count down to finishing.  This is how it is. Three monthly scans, four weekly hormone inhibitor implant, three weekly Herceptin and Zometa, and daily hormone tablets, and enough painkillers to fell a horse.  The fear that every niggle, every pain, anything unusual will be another tumour raising it’s ugly head. This is my life.  This is the New New New Normal.  And it sucks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Last week I saw the Spine Doctor, and apparently I’m doing incredibly well for someone who has had this operation. It’s a big operation and he had his work cut out. He’s one of the best, and if he hadn’t been so good, things could have been very different.  I could be in a wheelchair, not able to walk at all. You don’t want the work experience kid doing spinal surgery.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Naughty Vertebrae had ended up in pieces after the CyberKnife radiotherapy, and had to be partially removed as well as the remains of a still active tumour which was crushing the nerve to my leg, and then using cement and metal work to reconstruct my spine.  Clever stuff!  The image below shows my broken spine on the left and different views of the metalwork solution on the right.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brokenfixed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spinal Story&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this morning, I few friends came round, for coffee and cake.  I didn’t mention the Cancerversary, I didn’t want it to overshadow a normal morning.  Cancer has taken so much from me, I didn’t want it to take away the few snatches of normality I get.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Right now, things are stable, and I’m hoping it stays that way for a long time yet. I’ll happily count up the Stage 4 Cancerversary’s, because that means things are ok.  But I won’t celebrate it.  That gives it some significance that it doesn’t deserve.  I may have Stage 4 cancer, there may be no cure for it, but I am not terminal.  I am only terminal when there are no treatment options left, and I’m on round one.  I have options.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It is my 40th birthday next month and there are a few events planned so I can celebrate with my friends and family. Birthdays and anniversaries are the things that we need to celebrate.  Not cancerversary’s.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-cancerversary&quot;&gt;Stage 4 Cancerversary&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 13, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What A Year!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-a-year" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-a-year</id>
  <published>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">And not in a good way...&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of people have the year 2016 in their Room 101 for a number of reasons.  For the removal of any doubt, the Room I refer to is that of the George Orwell novel , “1984”, whereby any person who enters it, faces their worst fear, nightmare or phobia - essentially a torture chamber.  I’m not referring to the BBC One series where ‘celebrities’ talk about pet hates and grievances, which are then locked away in Room 101 as some sort of detention.
Anyway, back to the reasons:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ‘Great” British public deciding to leave the safety, sanctuary and sanity of The EU.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Great British Bake Off leaves the BBC.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The residents of The Land of The Free voting for a man I can’t come up with a title scathing enough other than, The Idiot that is Donald Trump.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The deaths of so many of those we refer to as Celebrities. A few which made me feel especially sad as they were part of my childhood and formative years: George Michael, Carrie Fisher, Terry Wogan, Victoria Wood, Ronnie Corbett, Alan Rickman and Paul Daniels.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The government has ridden roughshod over our NHS and education system.  (There’s better people out there to comment on this in more detail…but I thought that it should be mentioned.)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my family and I, the year 2016 will be regarded as the Year the Cancer Came Back.  The year things all went a bit weird.  The year I never want to have to go through again.  My Room 101.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started January 2016 filled with optimism.  We saw in the New Year with our very good friends, and then enjoyed a Strong Special on New Year’s Day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015newyearseve.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 58%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016beef.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 38%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

So far, so good!  I made some New Year&#39;s Resolutions which I documented in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.  Well, that got messed up quickly. (And I shout as much or even more than I did in 2015...oops).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The kids went back to school on January the 5th, and my back started to give me grief.  But nothing to worry about.  I&#39;d had back pain before.  Extra painkillers, no drama.  I went swimming, I did Pilates and I carried on as normal.  On Sunday the 10th, we trekked down to Hertford for a rugby match with the kids.  Each at different ends of Hertford&#39;s massive grounds.  I got the short straw and had the longest walk to where Felix was playing.  Whilst there, I spoke to Pinky, who suggested that rather than stick to the painkillers, I have a word with my Oncologist.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That Monday morning, I walked the kids to school, and two women I knew by sight but not to talk to, asked if they could walk them rather than me, as I was obviously in pain. I declined, and soldiered on.  I laughed about it to my friends.  It couldn&#39;t possibly be  sinister. All evidence pointed to a slipped disk.  Never has anyone wanted a slipped disk more than me at that point.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So, on Pinky’s advice and listening to the voice in my head that said something wasn’t quite right, I spoke to the Oncologist the Monday, had a scan on the Tuesday and on Wednesday 13th January, he told me I was looking at a 90% chance that the cancer was back, this time in my spine.  This was  most likely a secondary.  No cure.  Only management.  New Year&#39;s Resolutions completely upended.  And also not quite like Craig David’s 7 day’s.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Once the diagnosis was confirmed, in 2016, I had 143 medical appointments, including blood tests, scans, consultations, radiotherapy, infusions, counseling sessions and also reflexology sessions.  That works out at about one every three days. &lt;br /&gt;   
&lt;br /&gt;
I restarted Herceptin and Zometa infusions every three weeks to continue indefinitely.  I woke up in the night screaming as the pain in my leg and back was horrendous. I had to use a walking stick.  I got a Blue Badge.  I have had 3, hour long sessions on consecutive days of Cyberknife radiotherapy. I have had two weeks in a Hospice for pain management. I had a blood transfusion (and associated guilt). I have had a week in the Royal National Orthopedic hospital as the Cyberknife had caused my vertebrae to collapse, so I needed my vertebrae to be reconstructed and another blood transfusion (and associated guilt).  They found active cancer cells which meant the Herceptin hadn’t worked on that particular tumour.  The tumour had wrapped itself around the nerve to my leg and was slowly crushing it.  I had two weeks of daily radiotherapy sessions.  I’ve been on Morphine for the most part of this year.  I was unable to drive due to the Morphine and pain from January until August.  Walking the kids to school became the exception, rather than the rule.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So tomorrow, I will be spending the evening with friends, all with the hope that 2017 will be better than 2016.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-a-year&quot;&gt;What A Year!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Christmas 2016]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/christmas" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/christmas</id>
  <published>2016-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">(This a festive post).&lt;p&gt;This year’s Christmas was very similar to last year’s.  We had my Dad and Julie round a day or two before Christmas and Uncle Max arrived on Christmas Eve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year on Christmas Eve, we Lawley’s always get new pyjamas.  The reason behind this is so that if any photo’s are taken on Christmas Day, before we’ve got dressed, we’ll at least have decent PJ’s and not have worn out, holey abominations on.
For the past 4 or 5 year’s, we’ve also had a Christmas Eve box.  It’s a cardboard box in wrapping paper.  Well it was.  This year I upgraded and got a proper wooden, personalised box from ebay.  The contents are a family secret, but it’s a tradition that we’ve come up with over the years that Ross and I have made together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016christmaseve.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016 Christmas day&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went for the traditional pre-lunch drink to The Orange Tree and got a traditional hug from The Land Lord who has recently returned from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Orange-Tree-Everest-Trek-2016-1113912225351879/&quot;&gt; his intrepid adventures in Nepal to Everest Base Camp.&lt;/a&gt;  We both made it to Christmas 2016!! And we both have Wills thanks to the very clever Robert from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbwlaw.biz/&quot;&gt;BBW.&lt;/a&gt; (At least that’s one thing ticked off the To Do list.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016christmasday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016 Christmas Day&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at home, Uncle Max produced a magnum of Prosecco which went down very well with Ross’s Christmas Dinner which was just as amazing, if not more so than last year’s. I can’t drink as much alcohol these days, so after 2 G&amp;amp;T’s, a prosecco and a Bailey’s, I was done in, and along with everyone else, slipped happily and easily into a Food Coma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, on Boxing Day, Dad and Julie went off to the Kent Hoggs on the next stage of their Christmas Travels. After waving them off, we decided to get some fresh air and went off to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationaltrust.org.uk/wimpole-estate&quot;&gt;Wimpole Hall&lt;/a&gt;.  A lot of other families seemed to have the same idea but we went off the beaten track and  walked the way of the kids ParkRun.  I hadn’t gone that way before and it was fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016boxingdaywalk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016 Boxing Day&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all it was a pretty normal Christmas.  And I like it when things are normal.  When things were quiet.  Normal and quiet are good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/christmas&quot;&gt;Christmas 2016&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 26, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safe Cycles]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/safety-cycles" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/safety-cycles</id>
  <published>2016-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">(This isn&#39;t a festive post).&lt;p&gt;In my last blog post, I spoke about having a two week break in Anastrozole, the daily hormone inhibitor tablet, to see if it made a difference to my tiredness.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It didn’t.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So, back to square one.  I need to go back to have my thyroid levels checked, and then go to discuss the results with the GP.  The last ones have been normal, so I don’t expect these ones to be much different.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So, still no answers.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m still constantly, bone crushingly, tired. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But it’s the type of tiredness that even if I go to bed at 9pm and wake up at 9am, I don’t feel refreshed or rested. I feel like I want to go back to sleep.  Often, despite feeling so tired, it can be impossible to sleep.  This is so frustrating, and when I resort to the prescription sleeping tablets, I feel like I’ve failed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Most recently, I’ve been struggling mentally, with the perpetual cycles of scans and treatment.  When I was having treatment for the Stage II cancer, I had 18 cycles of Herceptin.  One infusion every 3 weeks with a break for surgery, starting on Thursday 21st November 2013, ending on Thursday 8th January 2015.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m up to cycle 16.  At this point last time, I was counting down, ”2 to go”! &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Now, there is no countdown.  I have to get as many treatments under my belt as I can.  Because this treatment is keeping the cancer under control, it needs to keep working for as many cycles as we can.  The longer it works, the more the tumours are kept at bay and the longer I live…it’s as simple as that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Treatment every 3 weeks. Blood tests, one or two days before each treatment. Scans every 3 months.  Daily tablets.  Hormone inhibitor implant every 4 weeks. Constant pain.  Completely random sleep patterns. This is my normal now.  And I hate it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016newnormal.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Normal&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking at me, you’ll see a normal person.  No visible signs of anything untoward going on.  But that’s a facade.  It’s a mask.  The person behind that mask is not the Julia who went into this maelstrom in October 2013.  That person was confident, capable and carefree.  The current one backs away from people and social situations, and gets anxious about the smallest thing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thankfully, I have access to the fantastic support and services from my local hospice, Garden House Hospice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I regularly see a palliative consultant to discuss my overall physical and mental health. In one of my last appointments the subject of Depression was raised along with a potential treatment plan of anti-depressants.  Having taken them in the past when I had Postnatal Depression after Felix, I know how they can help, but I want to try other things first.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Hospice allows me to access reflexology and aromatherapy, which I find helps to relax me.  I also see a Music Therapist.  It’s a new service, but it’s fantastic.  I’m surprised people aren’t banging the door down to book a session.   I love these sessions, as I get to sing in a safe environment, and I love singing.  It can make me cry if a song hits me with it’s lyrics.  Queen’s “Who want’s To Live Forever” is a killer, but I still sing it!  The hour I have is so precious.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Crucially, I also had access to a counsellor.  I saw her earlier in the year when I was coming to terms with my Stage IV diagnosis.  This time though, it’s coming to terms with the fact that this is how my life is now.  Even when I’m well, I still have the same cycles of treatments and scans.  And that’s rubbish.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So, if you see me when I’m out (which isn’t as often as I used to), and you ask me how I am, I’ll probably tell you I’m fine.  I don’t think you are actually interested in what is really going on.  This is less to do with you, and more to do with me.  Don’t be insulted.  Don’t think I need to “get it all out” or “open up”.  I talk about things with my counsellor.  I talk about things to Ross.  I talk about different things to different people.  Don’t be offended if I say “I’m ok” , it’s a safe answer and at the minute, more than anything, I need to feel safe.
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/safety-cycles&quot;&gt;Safe Cycles&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 22, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quarterly Scan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/all-clear" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/all-clear</id>
  <published>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Friday 4th November, Ross and I schlepped down to Mount Vernon for my quarterly scan.  The one that I have to have to check that I don’t have any gremlins getting together and having a little party and growing into a tumour.  I don’t like lumps and I don’t like tumours.    We’ve had a lot to deal with this year and if I’m honest 2016 has been pretty awful.  It was supposed to be the year we started living again.  We’d got all the big surgeries, including reconstruction, out the way.  We were going to go on a big abroad holiday, somewhere with a pool, an beach and some sunshine.  We were going to get the house decorated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it wasn’t to be, 2016 was The Lawley’s ‘Annus Horribilis’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We waited for the results of the scan to come through, and a few days later, I got an email from my consultants secretary saying he wanted to see me at his evening clinic.  I think it’s fair to say, Ross and I pretty much freaked out at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phrases including “It’s never good news to get called in this quick”, “Results this fast?  F**k”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after dropping the kids off to a, lets be fair, very worried Michelle, we went to meet the Oncologist.  We waited, we moved to a different part of the hospital, and then we were called in.  “The scan was fine!” he said!  Ross and I came down from the ceiling.  All was fine!!  Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concern now is my continuing tiredness.  As we know I’m cancer free right now,  the plan is for me to come off my daily hormone tablet, (Anastrozole), for two weeks to see if that’s the cause.  It’s been worrying, but as I’ve had a lingering cold for so long, it’s been pushed to the back of my mind.  The two weeks is up on the 28th November, so we’ll see what happens next.  I don’t think it’s made too much of a difference.  Maybe a little bit, but I’ll be put on a sister drug of Anastrolzole which will reduce the amount of Oestrogen in my body.  I won’t be left without a daily hormone restricter.  As my type of cancer is er+ it likes hormones.  It gets bigger by eating hormones (sort of).  And the less Oestrogen in my body the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be back with an update on that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/all-clear&quot;&gt;Quarterly Scan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 13, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Half Term]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/half-term" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/half-term</id>
  <published>2016-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier in October, Ross was scheduled to go away to New York for work.  This was the first time I’d been left on my own without extra help in the form of my Dad and/or Julie.  It was decided that if I felt I needed help, I could ask some of my local friends.  I needed to see if I could cope with the kids on my own.  I only have a finite amount of energy, and I have to work out how to use that energy.  A lady called Christine Miserandino wrote a great post on her blog in which she described &lt;a href=&quot;https://butyoudontlooksick.com/articles/written-by-christine/the-spoon-theory/&quot;&gt;The Spoon Theory.&lt;/a&gt;  It’s very interesting, and explains how it feels to live day to day with a condition which stops you living the kind of life you want to live - stopping you from living it to the full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Ross went to Heathrow to start his long journey to The States on the Monday afternoon, and he was due to get back early Friday morning.  We have to apply for her secondary school place by the end of October, and there was an open day at out local high school which he needed to be at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I walk to school, it’s a mile each way, and doing that twice a day pretty much uses up all my energy, all my spoons.  It means I can’t cook tea, I can’t take them to clubs or lessons.  It was not an option to walk them whilst he was away.  Thankfully, the school have been great and I’m able to park in the school grounds when I take them and drop them off.  Imy likes to walk into school with a friend most of the time, but on Tuesday’s she comes in with us.  So, on Tuesday morning, we all drove to school, and I gave myself a pat on the back for getting there on time.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Wednesday, I was starting to need flag and I had to call in a few favours.  One was to collect them from school, and another to bring Imy home from Street Dance.  I had hoped to go to choir, but despite having a few people offer to look after the kids, there were no spoons left.  I couldn’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got through the week, but I was exhausted.  And that was despite the fact that the kids were at school for most of the day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when Ross was due to go away at half term, we knew I wasn’t going to be able to cope, so we decamped up to my Dad’s and Grandma Julie’s house.  We had a lovely time.  Ross drove us up there on the Saturday, he went to Brussels on Tuesday and then he came back on the Thursday.  My Dad was able to take the strain with the kids, they were able run off their energy on the beach.  Imy and Felix spent time with their cousins Oscar and Elsie, I made my Christmas cake and we spent time with my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/halfterm2016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Half Term Fun&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s.  Sometimes I don’t have time to write a full on blog post, so I’ve set up a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/TeamLawley/&quot;&gt;Facebook page - @TeamLawley Big Lump and The Lawley’s&lt;/a&gt; which the new blog posts will be shared on, as well as other mutterings and musings.  Give it a ‘Thumbs Up’ so you keep up to date with everything.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/half-term&quot;&gt;Half Term&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 01, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweet Sounds and Kind Messages]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sweet-sounds" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sweet-sounds</id>
  <published>2016-10-06T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-10-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back in April 2014, whilst I was recovering from my bilateral mastectomy and Axillary node clearance, I decided to write a &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happiness-and-sadness/&quot;&gt;bucket list.&lt;/a&gt;  I didn’t call it a Bucket List, it was a “To do list”.  Whatever I called it, this is what was on the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sort the garden - I&#39;m not sure what I meant by this, but the garden is now a lot tidier than it was. tick!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Stain/paint some furniture - I&#39;ve painted three bedside tables and a chest of drawers. tick!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Run a 10k - I ran the Standalone 10km in October 2014 with Michelle.  tick!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Race for Life Pretty Muddy - A hardy bunch of Gin Clubbers helped me get round a Muddy 5km in June 2015.  tick!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; do a triathlon - I&#39;ll come back to this in another blog post in the future...there is a plan...sort of!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one thing that I didn’t have written down, but was on the list in my head.  This was to join a choir and start singing again.  I love singing, but for some reason, I lost my confidence and I stopped singing in public when I was about 16.  Prior to that, I’d been in the school choir, school session group, I’d sang as the performing part of my music GCSE (I got a B by the way), my friend, Jenny, and I wrote and performed a song in a local songwriting competition, (we didn’t win, but we had fun).  I’d sung solos in charity concerts, I even sang some big show tunes at a family friend’s wedding - accompanied by my Grandad on the piano.  But something changed in my head, I thought I had an awful voice and no one would want to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2014, whilst still having Herceptin, with a chemo crew cut, and no boobs, I pulled up my Big Girl Pants and I joined a choir.  On the evening I decided to join &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.singingaloud.com/&quot;&gt;Singing Aloud&lt;/a&gt; at Baldock Town Hall, I didn’t know if I’d know anyone there.  I walked in and was enveloped in warmth and kindness and I sang again.  It was lovely.  As it happened, I did know a couple of people.  Tash - I knew from when our boys were a nursery together.  Kerry - a mum from rugby.  It was going to be fine.  I was going to be fine.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to get to choir as much as I can.  I enjoyed the practice and I enjoyed the concerts.  I felt like I belonged in the group, and I wasn’t a bad X-Factor audition.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I haven’t been able to go as often as I would have liked, although I did manage to practice enough so that I could take part in a performance at the Baldock Beer Festival with my friends and family watching.
 I have started to gauge how well I am, based on if I can go to choir practice or not.  Last Wednesday, I made it for the first time since May. Once again, I was enveloped in the warmth and kindness and I sang.  It was lovely.  Unfortunately, I missed it again last night.  Ross is away in New York, and I’m flying solo with the kids.  It’s really stretching my energy levels.  But I’m hoping to be there again soon…it’s a measure of my health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s.  Last week I had a message from someone who reads the blog.  She was very kind telling me how much she enjoys the blog and how informative she finds it.  It was a lovely and unexpected message and really brightened my day.  There are two reasons I write the blog.  The first is as it’s cathartic for me to write down the thoughts to get them out of my head and stop them swirling around getting in the way of me doing other things.  The second is to keep my family and friends up to date with me and my treatment.  If anyone else reads it and finds it helpful, then that’s brilliant. The more the merrier.  Thank you for your message Joe.  It spurred me into writing a couple more posts. xx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sweet-sounds&quot;&gt;Sweet Sounds and Kind Messages&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Railway Children]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/railway_children" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/railway_children</id>
  <published>2016-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">On Saturday, Felix and I had an Adventure!&lt;p&gt;Saturday was a very exciting day for Felix and I.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elliesfriends.org/&quot;&gt;Ellie’s Friends&lt;/a&gt;, a charity we have been a grateful recipient for in the past (with a Hotel Chocolat voucher), had given me two complimentary front row seats to see The Railway Children in London! &lt;strong&gt;London!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was slightly anxious about getting the train with just myself and The Boy, but it was fine.  We got into Kings Cross and set about looking for somewhere to grab a quick bite to eat.  We weren’t fussy.  Felix had downloaded Pokemon Go! onto my phone when we were waiting at Baldock Station, so he was more interested in catching Pokemon than eating.  A quick scout round found us an M&amp;amp;S and we each got a sarnie (£5 for a Meal Deal?  Really?  Is that just station prices, or is that how much they actually cost!), and some Percy Pigs for the show.  It was a nice, sunny day, so we plonked ourselves down on a bench and ate our lunch.  Kings Cross has certainly changed since we moved to Baldock and began commuting into work in London.  Back then, you wouldn’t want to stay for any length of time.  Now it’s clean, open and more appealing!  You still get the Wierdies.  I noticed one particular Lady Wierdy who was approaching other ladies asking for something.  Thankfully she didn’t approach me, so we ate our lunch in peace, before making our way to the theatre.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theatre is actually a temporary structure built over the railway tracks and will eventually become the Google offices.  It’s very clever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bar area is set up to look like a turn of the century ticket office, with period luggage.  Even better, they had Fentiman’s Rose Lemonade and Ginger Beer.  Felix was very impressed that we could order drinks at the bar and collect them at the interval without having to queue at the bar.  It was just as well as there were several packs of Brownies there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were sitting down in our seats, the cast of the play came out to interact with the audience.  Caroline Harker spoke to Felix and asked him if he’d seen the film or knew the story.  When he said “no” she was very nice and said she thought he would enjoy the play.  She was right.  It was fantastic.  We had a great time.  We munched our way through the Percy Pigs we’d bought and enjoyed the superb adaptation of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the play was over, we headed back to Kings Cross to head home, but not before making some purchases from Paperchase and Hotel Chocolat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived home exhausted, but I was so pleased I got to spend some one to one time with Felix. That doesn’t happen often. In fact I haven’t spent much time with just Imy recently.  We’ll have to change that!  And soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/railwaychildren.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Railway Children Trip to London&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/railway_children&quot;&gt;Railway Children&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 26, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>