<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2016-01-19T12:56:53+00:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scans and Results]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scans-and-results" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scans-and-results</id>
  <published>2016-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Yesterday, we went for the final scan.&lt;p&gt;This one was to last an hour an a half, and when I came out I was a bit annoyed when they radiologist told me the results would be through in 3 days.  I had a bit of a strop and told them I was seeing the consultant that evening and he needed to report by then.  There was lots of huffing and puffing on their part and I left them to it.  In the car park on the way out, I phoned my consultant’s secretarial team and told them they might need to put some pressure on them to get the results.  These ladies are brilliant and whatever they did, it worked.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 7pm I was in the consultants office and he told me that it was indeed cancer in the vertebrae, but by some miracle that’s the only place it was.  He’s currently deciding on a treatment plan, which is likely to include a bone biopsy, cemented the vertebrae to sure it up a bit and try and avoid it collapsing, radiotherapy, possible changes to me Hormone therapy, and the likely restarting of Herceptin, which means I’ll be having a port reinserted.  The Herceptin will be every 3 weeks for the rest of my life.  There may be chemotherapy involved but that’s not definite yet.  Things are going to move quickly, I’ve just got to be ready to go where I’m told, when I’m told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this all being an awful lot to take on, we’ve got to look at the positives.  The consultant is talking in terms of years, not weeks or months.  The fact it’s only in one vertebrae is also on my side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I phoned my brothers to let them know the news.  And felt better for them to know.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been to the GP’s this morning to get some more painkillers, and more drugs to deal with the side effects of the said painkillers.  I’m also being referred to a Macmillan nurse who will help me deal with things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kids have been told, and the school is aware so that they can help them through this.  Imogen can be a delicate flower, and will no doubt need a lot of help from her friends, and adult key workers.  Felix is a very different fish, we just need to make sure he doesn’t bottle things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, once again, here we are, keeping on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scans-and-results&quot;&gt;Scans and Results&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 19, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[An unwelcome surprise]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/an-unwelcome-surprise" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/an-unwelcome-surprise</id>
  <published>2016-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s been a year since I last wrote, I was starting to believe I would only to come back to the blog as a visitor.&lt;p&gt;You’ve should have read Julia’s post so you have an idea of whats occurring, if not catch up there first. I write in this blog to help me process and connect with my feelings. It’s also been a great conduit for me and Julia to communicate our inner thoughts in a way thats less burdening than a conversation would be.
I digress…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-pain-in-the-back&quot;&gt;A pain in the back&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Julia’s had back pain and its been worse than normal. Deep down Julia knows this and calls the oncologist to discuss it. I think she’s being a drama queen and tell her off for not going to the GP first! A few of our friends also agree but Dr Shah plays it safe and orders an MRI. On &lt;em&gt;Tuesday&lt;/em&gt; we make the journey to Spire Harpenden and I can’t help be nostalgic, the journey may have been a pain in the bum but I enjoyed the time Julia and I had when she was on treatment. It was our time, it bought us closer and helped make me feel useful whilst she had her treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MRI goes swimmingly and we are a little anxious as we await the results. They gave us a dvd with the images on, how cool is that? Julia looks at it and Googles. “Is that a bulging disk?” That’ll explain it. I look through, Google MRI spine and learn about disks, vertebrae and the like. It all looks good to my untrained eye, which is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-hate-the-qe2&quot;&gt;I hate the QE2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head to the QE2 on &lt;em&gt;Wednesday&lt;/em&gt;, its been such a long time since we were last there. In fact the old hospital seems to have fallen down and a new smaller hospital sits in its shadow. Julia and I like the new QE2 it’s shiny. We potter round to the yellow zone in search of Dr Shah. Julia’s nervous, I can tell, shouldn’t I be nervous? No, it’s just muscular back pain, Julia is being a drama queen and Dr Shah moved the appointment because it was more convenient for him as he has 2 hospitals and a university to lecture at today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get called into see Dr Shah, comment on how nice the hospital is. Dr Shah cuts to the chase - he doesn’t have the images but has been told it’s cancer. My mind is slow to react, it’s like I’m watching myself, looking out of my eyes. I can’t comprehend what he just said. He’s still explaining and I see Julia shaking. How did this happen? Treatment went so well we weren’t even having scans to check. We hand over the images to Dr Shah and Julia walks him getting the program started - “it’s IT it’s what &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; do” says Julia. One vertebrae is the wrong shade of grey. Dr Shah explains that theres a 90% chance it’s cancer and tells us not to hold out for the 10%. He says we need blood tests, a CT Scan and full spinal MRI to confirm and see if its spread. He’ll sort this out and we should see him Monday evening. He says we should be prepared for a hard meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He offers the NHS’s drug cabinet to Julia and writes a big prescription. Julia’s painkiller of choice is liquid Morphine. I’m stunned and in a daze, we’re leaving his office and the news is hitting home. Its so hard and unfair, Julia is white as a sheet and shaking.  We head to the pharmacist and are told there’s a 40 minute wait as the Morphine is a controlled drug. We have a coffee and cry in the coffee shop. Julia is much better than me, more prepared and more composed. I’ve been sideswiped, I must have lied to myself as I hadn’t entertained the thought. We’ve been through so much and we were supposed to be out the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prepare-for-the-worst&quot;&gt;Prepare for the worst&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie, the next few days were hard. The hardest I’ve ever been through. My stupid imagination is relentlessly cruel and feelings hit me like waves. I’m working hard to stay afloat in this maelstrom but at times I break. Weirdly, its at odd times, a glib comment by Julia or when doing things with the kids whilst Julia rests, I ask is this how it will be in the future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia shames me with her composure, I guess the drugs are numbing her feelings also and is in a world of sadness of her own. I also know that I have to work hard get past my feelings. I’m not a strong person but I know bottling the tears is not the way, anyway I seem to have developed my own personal spring, so I can’t. Crying is sadness leaving the body and I have to prepare for the worst, just in case it comes, because if it does I have to be strong for Julia and the kids. It’s an indulgence or necessity now that I can’t take later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friends have been great in helping and offering to pick up kids and sending good wishes. We haven’t told everyone yet - we still don’t know what the answer will be. The kids are having to deal with, what must appear to them as a pair of emotionally disfunctional parents! However, they help keep spirits high with their energy and their laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insomnia&quot;&gt;Insomnia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve fallen into the habit of waking up early and not being able to go back to sleep as our minds are racing. Julia’s pain wakes her and I wake as she gets up and takes more drugs to dampen it down. Even with all the drugs she’s taking I’m concerned that she still feels pain from her back, it might fade to the background but its still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My head is not in the right place to do any coding, so I tell work whats happening and that I will report in on Tuesday when we have the answers about her back. Work again have been brilliant, allowing me to take time and wishing us the best. I’m so grateful to be working for them, in so many ways they’ve been brilliant through this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weekend&quot;&gt;Weekend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday, comes and its CT Scan day, but first some of Julia’s friends are keen to see her in person and Julia invites them round for coffee after the school drop off. We bump into Neil and its good to see him up and about after a rather nasty chest infection. Neil, asks what folks are doing and I invite him for coffee. We chat, he asks after Julia and I mention her back and then choke. For a few moments I can’t speak and tears well. Eventually, I get the words out and he’s shocked by the news. Rather than join the Julia and the ladies for coffee we head off to the coffee shop and that coffee was great. Just talking about it for a few moments and then talking about normal things lifts helps lift a burden and raise spirits. Thanks Neil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we head back to the Spire and it’s done quick enough. The journey to and from the hospital gives us time to reflect and chat. In the past week we’ve had so &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; hard conversations. Ones that I couldn’t imagined having just the week before. We are preparing for the worst and Julia is getting her stuff together. We’ve talked about wills, funerals, the kids, life, the future. It might seem morbid and in away it is, but Julia would hate for me to get it wrong - or more correctly she’d hate for me to worry that I’d got stuff wrong. And yes we know there is hope, that it might be muscular and not sinister at all but it’d be foolish to delude ourselves totally. Anyway, doing this and organising things is what Julia is good at. It keeps her busy and is the most proactive thing to do in the circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beers&quot;&gt;Beers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday, I ferry Felix to the pool for his lesson and take time out to read whilst he swims. I bump into the Strongs at the pool and there’s talk of a beer in the evening with Adam - sounds good to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep ourselves busy, Julia and I planned a trip to the IMAX to see Star Wars again. It’s pretty “in your face” cool with the 3D visuals and super sound. I notice Julia looks to be in pain at times during the film, so once its over we ditch the dinner plans and opt for takeaway instead. After dinner and painkillers Julia zones out, whilst the kids cheer for the latest round of contestants in Ninja Warrior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I head out the pub and its nice to have a few beers. I probably had more than I had planned but Dan, Adam and Marcus are good company. By the time we leave the pub its snowing. Theres always a touch of magic walking through the first flakes of snow. Dan and I have a chat about Julia whilst heading home and for the first time since the news, I feel at peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunday-feeling&quot;&gt;Sunday feeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always think the downside to having beers, is you pay for the previous nights happiness with todays. As if happiness is some kind of limited resource. The hangover wasn’t great and I have a touch of the blues. I make a mental note I can’t be having too many, too often as it has a high happiness cost!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rugby was cancelled, so Imogen decides to make cheesecake. A brilliant plan! I walk them to the supermarket whilst Julia takes it easy. We grab snow from the tops of walls and throw snowballs there and back. I become Imogen’s sous chef - man she’s demanding! Later on I watch the rugby on tv and generally chill. The kids get a little cabin fevered - note to self I need to exercise them more when rugby is off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sunday feeling is hard to bare, there’s some dread about what tomorrow may bring. Finding sleep is hard and moods are low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monday-monday&quot;&gt;Monday, Monday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, this is the worst Monday of the year, the newspapers say so, so it must be true. We’re on board with that, but we also are hoping for sciatica. That’s in our script, so lets hope it becomes so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased that Julia was up for the school run today. It’s even better that she has the chance to head to the community centre for coffee with friends after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia is currently having an mammoth MRI scan an hour and half (we know how to get the most out of our insurance). I’m in the waiting room, drinking coffee and, well, waiting. There’s an odd bunch in today. I’m not a fan of the man whose been listening to loud music, farting and burping as he has to down a litre of water for some scan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way I’m glad today’s come even though it’s ominous at least we’ll know what’s what. We’ll be able to talk about it with clarity. The kids can finally know why we’ve been so weird and we can be open with all our friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it is what it is and tonight we find out, here’s hoping for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/an-unwelcome-surprise&quot;&gt;An unwelcome surprise&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 18, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long Weekend]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-long-weekend" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-long-weekend</id>
  <published>2016-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Saturday started early again, with the usual pain waking me up.&lt;p&gt;After a few hours the kids came in and were despatched to play on the Playstation or read.  Next thing I know, it’s time for Ross to take Felix to his swimming lesson and Imogen was instructed to get her homework done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we’d had lunch it was time to see Star Wars again.  This time at the IMAX.  It was brilliant.  We really enjoyed it.  It was quite uncomfortable for me to sit for over two hours and I was glad to get home to top up the painkillers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A curry was ordered in for tea, and Ross went out for a couple of beers.  I went to bed when the kids did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday we were praying that rugby training would be cancelled due to it being so cold and a covering of snow.  Luckily it was, so despite my early waking, I had Breakfast in bed and was back asleep by 10am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was quiet, but with the anticipation building for tomorrow’s final scan and the results we’ll get, to say I’m a bit anxious is an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-long-weekend&quot;&gt;The Long Weekend&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 17, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Day, Another Scan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-day-another-scan" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-day-another-scan</id>
  <published>2016-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;ve been waking up in the night by the pain in my back.&lt;p&gt;I usually take some morphine and some diazepam to try and relieve it before going back to sleep.  Unfortunately, sleep tends to be illusive, and by the time I’ve huffed and puffed a bit, Ross has woken up.  We chat for a while, maybe read, maybe chat to the other insomniacs on social media, and if we’re lucky get back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I had some visitors, which was nice.  Some of the Gin Club came round after the morning school with biscuits and made their own tea and coffee. (They are good like that.)  It’s good to have news from the outside world.  Something that doesn’t involve me, pain, cancer or hospitals.  I appreciate it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was due a CT with contrast today and was nil by mouth from 9am.  This included painkillers.  The imaging department at the hospital was very efficient, I was given water, changed into a robe, had a cannula fitted and was led into the CT suite.  By this point I was in agony.  20 minutes later, I was all done, the radiographers helped me up out of the scanner as I can’t get from lying to sitting on my own, and sent on my way, but not before I dosed up on morphine and other painkillers, and snuck in a cup of coffee and some jammy dodgers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once home I tried to keep busy.  Felix was out at a friends and Imy got on with her music practice.  We haven’t said anything to the bairns yet about any of this.  They know I have a bad back, and that I’ve been having scans and seeing doctors. I don’t think Cancer is even on their radar.  They don’t know you can get cancer in your back or bones.  Why would they?  They are children.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, I have another MRI, and then in the evening, after we’ve seen the Oncologist and find out what we are dealing with, we’ll decide what to tell them and how best to do it.  I don’t expect it’ll be an easy conversation.  But - it still could be a trapped nerve…there’s a 10% chance it’s not cancer.  Please let that be the case.  Please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-day-another-scan&quot;&gt;Another Day, Another Scan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 15, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bad Back, Bad News]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/bad-back-bad-news" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/bad-back-bad-news</id>
  <published>2016-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">After the upbeat nature of my last post, I&#39;m afraid to say things aren&#39;t going to plan.&lt;p&gt;I had said I wanted to have no medical interventions I didn’t choose myself.  Nope - I’ve failed at that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, after the kids went back to school, I started to get a pain in my back.  Back pain is not unusual for me, so I ignored it for a bit.  But it got progressively worse.  I became permanently attached to a hot water bottle, even taking it into the office with me.  I started talking painkillers but the paracetamol and ibuprofen weren’t cutting it, so I broke into my stash of Tramadol.  This was a mistake as it sends me a bit doo-lally.  It didn’t make the pain much better either, so I went back to the paracetamol and ibuprofen.  Walking was becoming laboured, bending and twisting was agony and I couldn’t sleep properly as the pain was waking me up.  I like to think I have quite a high pain threshold, but this was something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross suggested I do some stretches and use his roller for easing muscular pain.  For a quiet life I gave them a go, but nothing helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time Monday morning rolled around, I’d had enough.  Ross suggested seeing the GP for painkillers, but instead I emailed my Oncologist’s secretary to see if he could fit me in for a quick telephone chat.  I wanted him to tell me to “Man up and get on with things”.  I even told him this when we spoke later that evening on the phone.  I explained my symptoms, and he thought it sounded like a slipped disk.  Oh! I haven’t had one of them before!  Then he said given my history, that I should go for an MRI and he’d get his secretary to organise it quickly for me.  He also told me to go to the GP for the painkillers.  He gave me a list of what to ask for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, I go to the GP’s and come back with a good haul of painkillers, including anti-inflamitories and valium.  ( :-o )  He tells me if I don’t get an MRI through quickly via my consultant, then I was to go back and let them know and they would organise one for me.  This is a bit odd.  People are taking me seriously!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At lunchtime I get a call telling me to go for a scan at 4:30 that afternoon, and that the Oncologist will catch up with me the following Monday to discuss the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the scan is done, I get all my images on disk.  This is quite exciting, considering all the scans I’ve had, I’ve never actually seen any!  But I’ve got my own disk!  To keep!  Obviously Ross and I have a look at them, but can’t make head or tail of them so put it back in it’s envelope and wait to see the Oncologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The appointment comes through quicker than we anticipated.  His secretary contacted me the next day to tell me that he wanted to see me as soon as possible and could I get to the hospital for lunchtime.  Oh.  Ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the hospital we are sat down and Dr Shah makes no bones about the fact (no pun intended) that he is 90% sure my pain is caused by cancer in the vertebrae which is causing it to bulge and press on my spinal cord.  Obviously this is bad news.  Very bad news.  It means the breast cancer has metastasized and gone traveling.  If it is the 90%, then I’ll be classed as Stage 4 or terminal.  There is no cure for this, only management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing he wants to do is get my pain under control.  In addition to the painkillers given to me by the GP, he has given me steroids and oral morphine, as well as a couple of drugs to counteract the side effects of these.  He’s said if the pain can’t be controlled by this method, he’ll get me admitted so it can be done in a more controlled environment.  Obviously, I don’t want to go into hospital, I want to be with me family.  I want to watch Imy and Felix play rugby on Sunday.  I want to see Star Wars again on Saturday, but this time at the IMAX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To confirm the diagnosis, I need the have a couple more scans.  A CT is booked in for Friday, and another MRI for Monday.  The idea is they confirm that the suspect vertebrae is in fact Cancer (although there’s still a 10% chance it’s not), and also see if it’s managed to go anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment plan would involve radiotherapy and “therapy” but he wasn’t clear on whether that would be chemotherapy or targeted therapy like Herceptin or it’s sisters.  He said there was no point having a big long discussion about it now, as until he’s got all the facts, he won’t have a plan of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question “How long have I got?” was also evaded.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then went to the chemo ward to have some bloods taken.  It was bizarre to be back there, seeing the lovely chemo nurses.  They gave me big hugs, and I told them as much as it was nice to see them, I hadn’t really wanted to go back there.  They completely understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are, back playing the Waiting Game.  Thankfully we won’t have to wait long.  I’ll be seeing him again on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/bad-back-bad-news&quot;&gt;Bad Back, Bad News&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 14, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another New Year]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year</id>
  <published>2015-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Three years ago, we were thinking to ourselves that 2012 had been a pretty good year, and looking forward to another good one in 2013.&lt;p&gt;As it transpired, it was a good year.  We moved into a new house, we had a couple of great holidays, as a family, things were fantastic, everyone was happy but it was also the year where things changed for me forever.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gone over what it feels like to have the rug pulled out from under you before, I’m not going to rake over old ground. I’m here 2 years on, feeling very grateful I’ve got to another New Year, still not dead.  But it’s going to take me a long time yet to get over it mentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen has requested that as a New Year’s resolution, I try not to shout as much.  I’ll give it a go, but I’m also going to try and not have any medical interventions that I don’t choose myself. (Ha, like I have any say in that!)  In 2015, I finished Herceptin, and had two lots of surgery and still more scans, and consultant appointments.  I’m tired of hospitals.  Tired of doctors. Tired of tests. And just generally tired.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the latest round of tests, I’ve been told that my health is pretty perfect, which is obviously great news!  I’m just experiencing the after effects of 2 years of medical interventions.  Just.  Ok, great.  Thanks.  I’ve had Cancer, can I just move on now?  No!  I need to build up my stamina again, but it’s proving tricky.  I can swim 40 lengths in half an hour, do a pilates class, walk the kids to and from school, but every morning I wake up feeling like I could sleep for a week. I can’t even do a full day at work without having to take two days to recover! It’s just annoying.  I want to be able to do everything that I want to do, everything that I used to be able to do, and I can’t and it’s really frustrating me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are my New Year Resolutions?  It may sound dramatic, but I’d like to stay alive.  I’d like to get to my 40th birthday in Feb 2017.  The type of cancer I had, before the days of Herceptin, it would have been game over.  Grade 3, HER2+ breast cancer is not good news, it spreads fast and wide.  Luckily, I’ve had the Herceptin, hopefully it’s got rid of all the baddies that were lingering that the surgery didn’t get, and we can carry on. I’ve been signed up for a Macmillan Hope course in January which will hopefully help me deal with The Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the second one and to be fair, I think I’ll stop there.  That’s enough to be going on with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all my friends and family who have been with me on the journey so far, I thank you.  I’m sorry to be a Cancer bore.  I can rely on you all to keep my spirits up, and tell me how it is.  In fact, I think Rachel said “God, Julia, just because you’ve had cancer doesn’t mean you get special treatment!”.  Keeping it real!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year&quot;&gt;Another New Year&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[2nd Cancerversary]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/2nd-Cancerversary" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/2nd-Cancerversary</id>
  <published>2015-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today is my Cancerversary.&lt;p&gt;It’s two years since Ross and I were ushered into a room and told I had breast cancer. I can’t remember the exact words that were used. All I know is that a bomb went off that day and we’ve been feeling the effects of that explosion since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite hard having my Cancerversary in Breast Cancer Awareness Month, as it’s everywhere. I’m constantly being reminded of how devastating it is. But…without that awareness how many more women will die from the disease?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will reiterate a point I’ve made before, breast cancer is not pink, nor fluffy, nor is it one of the “best ones” to get. It kills. Even the “lucky” ones don’t come out unscathed. The treatments that are life saving, are also life changing. Many of us have to deal with fatigue which is more than just feeling a bit tired. It’s waking in the morning after 8 hours sleep and feeling like you could roll over and sleep for a week. It’s the constant feeling of having to pull against the crushing force of gravity just to get off the sofa. It’s the feeling that you’d love to do something, make plans, but when it comes to it, just wanting a nap instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there’s the medication which interferes with your hormones. I’ve got 8 more years of hot flushes and mood swings to contend with. Poor Ross will wake up in the night, in the dead of winter, and find the bedroom windows wide open just so I can sleep comfortably, whilst having night sweats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you’ve got the scars. Whereas once I just had a few stretch marks from being pregnant, I now have a wide array of scars in varying sizes, from 5mm to 30cm. I don’t look upon them as being ugly, but rather as way markers from the path I’ve walked to get me to where I am today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have I mentioned the memory loss? It’s very frustrating for someone that had the memory of an elephant to now not have the capacity to remember the 3 things I needed to get from the shop. It’s changed the way Ross remembers things too. He would just ask me where something was. That’s no longer reliable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m lucky, I’m Cancer free. I get to walk my kids to school everyday, help with their homework, watch them play rugby, all normal things that maybe once I took for granted. But everyday I have the cloud hanging over me that it’ll return. I have to deal with a vast array of “what if’s” that are, quite frankly, terrifying. I’ve even discussed my funeral with Ross. Not something you normally think about in your 30s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is my point after all this rambling on? Check your boobs. If you think something isn’t right, go to your GP. Get thinks checked by the professionals. If you think you are being fobbed off, ask for a referral to the breast clinic. Don’t just do nothing. It’s important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Ross? He’s amazing. He’s had to run Team Lawley on his own on more than one occasion, and has done a magnificent job. ❤&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/2nd-Cancerversary&quot;&gt;2nd Cancerversary&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 23, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Boob Day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/New-Boob-Day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/New-Boob-Day</id>
  <published>2015-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">September 17th will from now on be known as &#39;New Boob Day&#39;&lt;p&gt;On the 17th I was admitted into hospital for my reconstruction surgery. The surgery is DIEP Flap reconstruction.  It involves taking a large piece of skin and fat from my stomach, (luckily there was plenty), and then replumbing it in to create me two new boobs.  It’s very long, fiddly surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the run up to surgery, I’d caught Imogen’s cold, and I was concerned that it may be postponed.  Thankfully, it wasn’t and after nearly 11 hours of surgery, I was in recovery, chucking my guts up which I had told everyone involved would happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first night and next day on the ward are a bit hazy.  I remember being very rude to a nurse who brought me a cup of tea.  (I’m mortified about this.)  Ross came to visit in the afternoon and I was pleased to see him.  He decided to bring the kids in to visit, as they’d been missing me, and me them.  Imogen proudly showed me her certificate she’d been presented in Golden Assembly for passing her Grade 1 Flute exam.  She’d also got Star of The Week for great maths.  Such was the anesthetic haze, I couldn’t remember any of this until Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I was encouraged to get up, have a wash, and eventually had the drains and other tubes removed.  I was also taken off the morphine pump, but as I wasn’t really using it, this wasn’t too much of a drama.  Every so often someone would come in and ask to “check my flaps”.  This invariably caused me much amusement, but laughing about it with Ross hurt my stomach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday morning rolled around, and the doctor told me I could go home if the Consultant agreed.  Luckily he did, so after 11 hours of surgery, 4 nights in hospital, armed with a packet of paracetamol and some replacement dressings, I was off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad had come down the day before surgery to look after the kids, and when I got home, Grandma Julie had arrived too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent most of the next week in bed, only getting up for mealtimes, and The Great British Bake Off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad returned home after 2 weeks.  It was brilliant having him stay, as it meant Ross could get on with work, and the kids could stay in their normal routine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gradually I’ve been getting better, and am no longer reliant on the painkillers. I’ve had all my dressings and stitches removed, and the wounds are healing well. I’m hoping over the next week to start getting out for walks again, and build up some stamina.  I had assumed that I would be still incapacitated at this stage, and I think I have surprised everyone, including the Consultant, with how well I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw the Consultant on Wednesday, he told me to “keep doing whatever you are doing as it’s obviously working”.  So that’s what I’m going to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/New-Boob-Day&quot;&gt;New Boob Day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 02, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long Time No See]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Long-time-no-see" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Long-time-no-see</id>
  <published>2015-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s been a long time since my last post.&lt;p&gt;It’s been five months since my last post, and a lot has happened but I’ll try to be brief!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of May, I had the key hole surgery to remove the cyst on my ovary.  It turns out that there was in fact two cysts, of different types, but both completely benign.  They were both removed successfully along with the offending ovary.  The surgeon was happy with the outcome and has decided he doesn’t need to see me again.  Good news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four weeks after this surgery, I completed the Pretty Muddy Race For Life with Allison, Caroline, Charli and Michelle.  It was great fun, and we were all suitably grubby when we’d finished.  The supporting squad were very much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July, a larger Gin Club contingent took part in the Stevenage Race for Life, followed by a post race fundraising BBQ at The Orange Tree.  Thanks Rob!  We managed to raise over £1000 for Cancer Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August brought us school holidays and our two week family break away.  The first week we went to the Peak District with my Dad ad Julie and had some great days out.  The second week we went to the Lake District and marched up and down hills most days, but also ventured over the Hardknott and Wrynose Pass which was an interesting drive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to school in September and the kids settled back into their new classes well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in January, I’d mentioned to my good friend Fiona, that I fancied doing a Trialthlon.  “I’ll do it with you” she said.  Well, she did do it, and I didn’t.  I didn’t know when the reconstruction surgery was going to be, so I thought it best not to commit to such a big thing.  I now owe her a triathlon.  She was amazing.  It was a hot day and a hard course, but she did it.  And with a smile on her face (not all the time, there might have been swearing at times, but we can forgive her that.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that brings us to New Boob Day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Long-time-no-see&quot;&gt;Long Time No See&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 01, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook Follow-up]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Facebook-Follow-up" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Facebook-Follow-up</id>
  <published>2015-05-04T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This post started off as a a Facebook Status update.&lt;p&gt;This weekend I’ve been called a Facebook Warrior, as I am quite active on Facebook whilst also dabbling in Twitter.  (Does that make me a Twitter Twerp?)  Anyway, when I was writing it, it became clear that I needed to write a proper blog post for it because there was a lot of information I wanted to get across and lots of links to other sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original post was prompted by Rio Ferdinand’s wife, Rebecca, dying on Friday from breast cancer.  Here is what I said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s easy to think that Breast Cancer is one thing of the “best” cancers to get. But we should not get complacent. Breast Cancer kills. It is ignorant and non discriminating, and it’s pot luck if those who are diagnosed live or die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rebecca Ferdinand had been given the all clear, but it returned and sadly she died on Friday, aged 35, leaving her 3 kids without a Mummy. Heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lisa Lynch, in The C Word, on tonight, was also given the all clear, only for the Cancer to return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cancer is a Bitch. I’ll always be wondering whether my luck will change and we’ll have the Bitch come back. In the meantime, I’ll be living my life, enjoying watching my bairns grow up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ll also be raising money for Cancer Research, because we need to stop ladies like Rebecca and Lisa dying.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being told you have Cancer is horrendous.  Your life flashes in front of your eyes and you are suddenly given a very harsh lesson in the limitations of your own mortality. Whilst the medical team try and assure you that they hope to rid your body of Cancer, you are acutely aware that this disease has the potential to end your life.  (Insert your own Bad Swear here.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.breakthrough.org.uk/research/secondary/what-secondary-breast-cancer&quot;&gt;Breast Cancer Campaign&lt;/a&gt;, nearly 1,000 women in the UK die from breast cancer each month. Most of these deaths are from where the original breast cancer has spread to other parts of the body like liver, brain or bones.  Every month, 1000 families are left devastated at the loss of a Wife, Mum, Grandma, Sister, Aunt, Daughter.  1000 families discover that Breast Cancer isn’t the ‘best’ type of cancer to get, that it’s not easy to treat and are left with a gaping hole that no amount of condolences will fill.  Families like those of Rebecca Ellison, Lisa Lynch, Lulu and Rachel.  The latter two being ladies I’ve come across on my own cancer journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must continue to raise awareness to get women (and men) to know what the signs of breast cancer are.  Get familiar with your breasts, find out what’s normal and see the doctor if something’s not right.  Early detection is key.  Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.breakthrough.org.uk/about-breast-cancer/touch-look-check&quot;&gt;Breakthrough Breast Cancer’s&lt;/a&gt; guide for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must also continue to raise funds for research into finding a cure for Cancer.  Whilst Cancer is not pink and fluffy, if a pink and fluffy event gets people raising money, then that’s got to be a good thing.  So, if I can do the Race for Life and the Pretty Muddy one, you can sponsor me.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/the-gin-club-2015/&quot;&gt;Sponsor the Gin Club at Race For Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t underestimate Cancer.  It sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/football/2015/may/02/rebecca-ellisson-wife-of-footballer-rio-ferdinand-dies&quot;&gt;Rebecca Ellison wife of Rio Ferdinand Dies - The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3066155/Rio-Ferdinand-s-sister-thanks-fans-friends-love-support-tributes-continue-pour-footballer-s-wife-Rebecca-Ellison-died-cancer.html&quot;&gt;Rio Ferdinand’s Wife Died from Cancer - The Daily Mail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alrighttit.blogspot.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Lisa Lynch’s Blog - Alright Tit &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Facebook-Follow-up&quot;&gt;Facebook Follow-up&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 04, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last Port]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-port" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-port</id>
  <published>2015-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">In November 2013, I had a Chemotherapy port fitted.&lt;p&gt;It’s about the size of a pound coin with a thin tube going into a vein and sits under the skin on my chest.  I can feel it, the kids can feel it, and on occasion if they hug me too fervently, it can hurt.  But, it’s done it’s job.  It has made for easy administration of 10 rounds of chemo, 18 rounds of Herceptin, 1 dye for a CT scan and at least 20 blood tests.  That’s all things that would normally have been done via a needle in my arm.  And so now, after a conversation with my Oncologist and the Radiologist, it’s coming out next Friday.  It was put in under sedation, and I was given the option of being sedated to have it taken out.  It’s the difference between being admitted as an inpatient and waiting around for hours, or rocking up, and 20 minutes later going home.  I don’t imagine that it’s going to be particularly pleasant as they pull the tube out from the vein, but I’ll put my Big Girl Pants on, and crack on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I saw the Cardiologist today for a final Echo scan.  Herceptin, the biological treatment which targets the HER2+ bit of the cancer and has worked so well for me, has been proven in clinical trials to increase the risk of damage to the heart.  So throughout the course of treatments, (18 doses over 15 months, 3 weeks apart with a break for surgery and radiotherapy), I have been having regular heart scans to check nothing sinister is going on.  It seems I’ve been lucky and the Cardiologist has said that he’s happy there’s been no damage and I don’t need to see him again.  Yippee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back from the hospital I was telling Ross how lucky I was.  He was a bit surprised I thought this, “Lucky for getting Cancer?”  Well, no, not lucky for getting Cancer, as to be honest, that’s been a bit rubbish, but lucky to have responded so well to treatment, with no major drama’s along the way and not to have any lasting side effects apart from the fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifteen months ago, I felt like I had a mountain to climb.  On reflection, I’m not sure how I’ve done it, but I appear to be on the other side.  I suppose I kept my head down, and put one foot in front of the other and just kept going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could say anything to someone who has found themselves in a similar situation to me, I would say “Trust the experts, take it one day at a time, and accept help when offered.  Cancer is scary, some people will surprise you, others will let you down but try not to dwell on it.  Keep on, keeping on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/last-port&quot;&gt;Last Port&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 22, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Goes On]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/life-goes-on" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/life-goes-on</id>
  <published>2015-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Winter is turning to Spring and all around us the buds of new beginnings are peaking up.&lt;p&gt;I love seeing the snowdrops, crocuses, daffodils and the blossom on the trees. Spring has always been my favourite time of year.  Full of possibilities, of opportunities, and lots of what can be’s. It’s a reminder that life goes on and it’s no different in the Lawley house.  We’ve got the usual round of school, music lessons, swimming lessons, rugby and dancing.  It’s almost as if we are a normal family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to add to the normality, I’ve started working again.  Its not much.  Only 10-15 hours a week, and I’m working at home, but it gets my brain working again.  It’s spent the last 8 months slowly turning to mush.  It’ll be good to get my teeth into something again.  Plus we need to refill the Lawley coffers that have taken a battering whilst I haven’t been working.  Boring, but necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also spending 2 hours a week in the local Library as their IT Champion.  I’m helping out the public who maybe aren’t so confident using computers.  It’s early days yet, and I haven’t had a massive uptake, but it’ll take time to get word out that I’m around.  In the meantime, I’m writing a blog post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I said I would do last year when I was being a little bit fatalistic was that I would stop putting things off, and do the things that I wanted to do.  So far I’ve joined a choir, and will be performing in a concert in May, I’ve run another Standalone 10km, and the latest thing is that I’ve signed up to do a Race For Life Pretty Muddy in June.  It’s not as hard core as the Tough Mudder/Beach Warrior/One True Grit, etc, but given that I’ll only be one month past keyhole surgery it’s probably not a bad thing.  I’ve got a few of the Gin Club ladies to sign up too, so it should be a good laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, life goes on, and we are planning this years camping trips and summer holidays.  Something that this time last year, and to an extent this year until we got the surgery date, we felt we weren’t able to do.  Ross and I have decided that we’ll delay reconstruction  until September time.  Then we can have the kids back at school and I can get the long recovery time I need without interfering in our family time too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as is standard, we’ll keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/life-goes-on&quot;&gt;Life Goes On&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 02, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fighting Fit!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fighting%20fit" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fighting fit</id>
  <published>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">My Oncologist is keen that I don&#39;t turn into a blimp.&lt;p&gt;He’s told me I’m not allowed to just sit on the sofa all day and watch daytime tv.  (Meanie).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve been using Ross’s Fitbit and trying to get 10,000 steps in a day. This works out at about 7km or 4.5 miles a day. Some days it’s fine, as I can pretty much do that by walking the kids to and from school.  Other days it’s a bit harder.  Like at the weekends.  I’ve come to realise that I don’t move very much at the weekends.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, a friend, (that’s you Fiona), has challenged me to a step race.  It’s basically who can get the most steps in Monday to Friday.  My competitive streak kicked in, and I managed to win last week.  I came last in the weekend challenge, (lol), but I’m on track this week and managed my 10,000 steps before 10:10am this morning after a brisk walk round Baldock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve just checked my stats for the past 7 days, and I’ve walked nearly 50km which is just over 31 miles.  That’s got to be doing something for my fitness levels surely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see me walking round Baldock purposefully, you know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fighting%20fit&quot;&gt;Fighting Fit!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 17, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another long wait]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-long-wait" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-long-wait</id>
  <published>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Back in October 2013, I wrote a blog post called A Long Wait.&lt;p&gt;It seems I’ve found myself in the midst of another long wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of the year, I’ve had two CT scans, two MRI scans and an ultrasound scan.  That’s quite a lot of scans.  The Multi-disciplinary team have discussed me three times and at last, this week I heard the decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s good news.  All the scans and blood tests indicate that this lump is benign.  Yay!  It still needs to be removed as it’s unlikely to go away by itself, and the ‘wait and see’ option isn’t really an option when I want to have reconstruction at some point this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m booked in to have surgery on the 11th of May.  It’ll involve at most one night in hospital, and I’ll be out of action for a week, but it is so good to be able to make plans around a date.  So many things were being put off, or only tentative plans made, but this is great.  I’m pleased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-long-wait&quot;&gt;Another long wait&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 17, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delays]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/delays" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/delays</id>
  <published>2015-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It seems some things take their own sweet time.&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to be seeing the specialist tomorrow to get a plan of action for removing the cyst and hopefully a surgery date.  I’ve spoken to him a couple of times since seeing him and it looks like he won’t have all the information for that appointment so it’s been delayed until late next week.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Multi-disciplinery team have discussed my case, but haven’t come to a decision as they didn’t have all my scans upon which to base it.  They have been reassured that the cyst is (most likely) not sinister because my CA125 marker levels are normal (yay!), but they still want the cyst to come out.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time the MDT meet, hopefully they’ll have all my scans and decide the extent of the surgery, namely if I need an Oophorectomy and whether it’s one or both.  There’s a line in Orange is the New Black where Rosa is discussing her cancer with her counsellor and says “Who doesn’t love a surgery with ‘Ooph!’ in it.”  We’ll go with that, because the side effects and aftermath aren’t really very pleasant, especially for someone my age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest impact all of these delays have had is that I can no longer go ahead with my reconstruction on the 28th March.  It means I get the Easter Holidays with the kids back, but it also means that everything is delayed by at least 6 weeks once I’ve had the first lot of surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so in the absence of anything else, we wait some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/delays&quot;&gt;Delays&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 24, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wait...]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wait" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wait</id>
  <published>2015-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Just a quick update after seeing the specialist yesterday.&lt;p&gt;I’ve had blood taken so it can be tested for the markers I mentioned in my last post.  These results, together with my scans, will be taken to a Multi-disciplinary (surgical/oncology) meeting on Wednesday and they’ll decide what path to take and let me know within a few days.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specialist said that if I hadn’t had the crazy events of the past year and without the weird genetic mutation, (CHEK2), thrown into the mix, they would regard it as nothing to worry about and whip the cyst out.  However, they need to take a cautious approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that whatever else happens, surgery to remove the cyst is inevitable.  The specialist said if it was less than 5cm, it would probably go away by itself, but because it’s bigger, it’s unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so we wait.  Again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wait&quot;&gt;Wait...&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 17, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lumps]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/lumps" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/lumps</id>
  <published>2015-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;m not a big fan of lumps where there shouldn&#39;t be lumps.&lt;p&gt;As far as I’m concerned, lumps are not good news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I had my scan back in January, it threw up two things.  One was that I had Tendinitis and Trochanteric Bursitis in my hip.  I’ve since seen a specialist who has suggested a steroid injection will alleviate the pain whilst walking.  However, since seeing him the pain has diminished massively, so I’m hoping that after 2 months of suffering, it’s got better by itself, and that’ll be the end of it.  Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing is that they’ve found an 8cm cyst in my abdomen.  I’ve had a couple of scans on it now, and my Oncologist is keen to stress that he is not worried about it.  I get that.  However, I was told that my breast lumps were ‘only’ cysts, and we all know how that turned out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, these cysts are quite common in women my age, it just seems to be the size of it that’s causing the headache.  The doctors need to decide what to do about it.  In most cases they would just wait and see if it sorted itself out, and if it didn’t they’d whip it out in a few months time.  The complexity with me, is that I’ve got reconstructive surgery booked in at the end of March, which will be using tissue from my stomach.  Once that’s been done, it makes getting into my belly that bit trickier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, in the back of my mind I am worried that it could be cancer again.  From what I’ve read from reliable and reputable sources, it is difficult to tell if this type on cyst is cancer from a scan alone.  There are blood tests that can be done to see if there is an elevated marker, but a benign cyst could cause that too.  In my head, I am aware that it would be very unlikely to be cancer as I only just finished Herceptin last month.  It would have to be a different kind of cancer (HER-) to get past that marvellous piece of modern medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the plan is, I see a specialist this afternoon to get his take on it.  Then I reconvene with my Oncologist next week to see what the plan will be.
I sometimes feel like I’m a poor excuse for a human being.  All these things seem to keep happening.  I just want a quiet life.  I want to work on getting my brain back, I want to feel less tired ALL THE TIME, I just want to stop getting these curve balls.  I want to stop feeling so sorry for myself and as Mel off Bake Off would say “Get a ruddy grip!”.  I’ve done the hard bit, but the end doesn’t seem to be in sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in the absence of anything else,  I’ll just have to keep on, keeping on.  Seems to be standard these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/lumps&quot;&gt;Lumps&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 16, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I put myself through Dryathlon and Janathon]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/dryathlon-janathon-why" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/dryathlon-janathon-why</id>
  <published>2015-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Huzzah! Drythalon is all but over and as I&#39;ve just come back from a swim I&#39;ve successfully completed Janathon!&lt;p&gt;January being the start of the year is probably the best time to reflect on life, especially as it’s pace is soo slow compared to the maelstrom of festivities, food and family chaos that is December.  Going dry for the month as per &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cancerresearchuk.org/support-us/find-an-event/charity-challenges/dryathlon&quot;&gt;Dryathlon&lt;/a&gt; and exercising everyday for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.janathon.com/rules.html&quot;&gt;Janathon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; makes January the longest month of the year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-why-did-i-put-myself-through-it-for-the-second-year-running&quot;&gt;So why did I put myself through it for the second year running?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well for the past 16 months Julia (the mrs) has been fighting breast cancer.  Julia hates the fighting / survivor anology, comments “like you have any choice!” or “I just turn up to the appointments and do as I’m told - the rest is up to the treatment”.  I can totally understand that, her body at some level might have been geared up for all the “fighting” but her mind has been focused on the now and family life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think about last year I have two big thoughts*. Firstly, last winter was horrid - long, dark and looking back I felt like I was stuck in a fog of anxiety.  This time last year Julia was nearing the end of her weekly Chemotherapy and was totally and utterly wiped out.  The pure fatigue was shocking and as powerless I felt, I thought I could do my bit by joining Dryathlon and Janathon.  The festive season was fun but my mood was low and knowing that exercising is soul food I was happy to do it. I struggled through the daily exercise and there were times I really could have done with a beer but I made it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a year and Julia is much better and the christmas season was busy, boozy and a hell of a lot of fun!  It’s soo much nicer to have a functioning Julia to help out ;) To give something back and my liver a rest I signed up to Dryathlon and Janathon again - also people kept asking if I was doing it again which made it much harder to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I was determined to give Janathon a proper crack of the whip and go for it with a bit more effort.  There’s been times when I’ve not wanted to do anything but I just had to do something, so I did a fast run round town - weirdly, I kept bumping into members of the Gaskells on my Thursday night dash.  Dan Strong was my wingman on the long weekend runs making them less of a drag.  Also, I should mention the Insanity workouts at the Knights Templar gym - they are serious fun and no word of a lie, I ached for &lt;em&gt;4 days&lt;/em&gt; after the first one but I still went back for 3 more and will be continuing the class.  Here’s my Janathon numbers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 hours running some 64km&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 hours in the Gym&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 hours swimming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 hours of Insanity workouts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t lost much weight, I ate too many biscuits at the start of the month for that, but my scales tell me I have reduced my fat percentage and I’m happy to trade fat for muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I’ve really enjoyed taking part and happily after her last Herceptin treatment, on the 12th of January Julia was finally declared cancer free and officially in remission!  Thanks in no small part to the great work of Cancer Research and also to the lessons learnt in the past from those who’ve also had the misfortune get cancer.  To help those in the future please donate anything you can:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://justgiving.com/Ross-dryathlete2015/&quot;&gt;http://justgiving.com/Ross-dryathlete2015/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* Whats the second thing? Well, as horrible as 2014 was it was also a year filled with love, laughter and friends. Julia and I made sure we enjoyed the year and looked forward with both honesty and optimism. Imogen and Felix have been brilliant and whilst you wouldn’t wish any 6 or 8 year olds to go through this, they have and continue to amaze Julia and I, you’re both brilliant xx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/dryathlon-janathon-why&quot;&gt;Why I put myself through Dryathlon and Janathon&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scanxiety]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scanxiety" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scanxiety</id>
  <published>2015-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Is that a word?&lt;p&gt;Let me assure you, that it is indeed a word, and one that is used to describe the period in the run up a scan, and until you get the results of said scan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I saw the cardiologist who did an echocardiogram and was able to give me the results straight away, thus minimising my scanxiety.  All is fine with my heart, and any chest pains that I’m experiencing are not due to my heart not functioning properly.  In fact it’s in tip top condition.  The Herceptin hasn’t caused me any problems in that respect.  Jolly good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Ross and I once again found ourselves at the Spire in Harpenden for yet another scan and to see the breast surgeon for a six monthly review.  The purpose of the scan was to ensure that the treatment has been successful, to give the plastic surgeon an idea of what he has to work with for my reconstruction and to check there’s nothing sinister going on with my every increasing hip pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The breast surgeon and the radiographer had a quick look at my scan and were able to deduce that there is no secondary cancer lurking in my liver, lungs and, crucially, my bones.  This means that whatever is causing my hip pain, it’s not &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breastcancercare.org.uk/breast-cancer-information/about-breast-cancer/secondary-metastatic-breast-cancer/bones&quot;&gt;bone mets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The breast surgeon suggested that any chest pains I have been having were due to muscle pain in the scar tissue and radiotherapy site.  Again, nothing to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now have to wait for my Oncologist to review the scans and decide what to do about the pain.  I’m currently taking Tramadol which is a fairly hefty painkiller, which can leave me feeling a bit light headed and woosey.  I don’t really want to be taking it long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed I can get to see the Oncologist soon so we can come up with a plan.  One thing that was mentioned by the Oncologist and the breast surgeon, is that my port can be taken out at the same time as my reconstruction, which means one less surgical procedure to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/scanxiety&quot;&gt;Scanxiety&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 21, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Remission]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/in-remission" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/in-remission</id>
  <published>2015-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">There&#39;s four magic words anyone who has been diagnosed with Cancer wants to hear.&lt;p&gt;And they are “You are in remission”.  They are so much more positive and overall so much better than the ones uttered at the beginning of this journey, “I’m sorry, it’s cancer”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I went to see my Oncologist, and he told me now I’ve finished my active treatment, I’m officially in remission.  He told me that because of the response I’d had to chemo and Herceptin, he is pretty confident that this will be the end of my Cancer Journey, and I’m cured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this is brilliant.  Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What isn’t so brilliant, is the fact I’m still dealing with all the side effects of the treatments.  The fatigue, (I know I keep going on about it, but it’s so debilitating and frustrating), the rib pain from radiotherapy, the hot flushes, and recently the hip and pelvis pain.  I am finding walking to be very painful and am knocking back the painkillers just to get to school and back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Shah seems to think that this is due to the Tamoxifen interfering with my hormones and therefore interfering with my joints.  He wants to do a scan to double check, but it’s still a worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some joined up thinking, as well as Dr Shah’s scans, I will also be having some scans for the Plastic Surgeon so he can see what he’s got to deal with.  The basic principle is that he’ll remove stomach tissue and create me two new boobs.  It’s a very fiddley job, and involves grafting blood vessels together, but it’ll be worth it.  Another step closer to putting me back together again, albeit, quite not all in one piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/in-remission&quot;&gt;In Remission&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 13, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>