<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2016-08-07T14:43:44+01:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Birthdays, Races and other stuff...]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/birthdays-races" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/birthdays-races</id>
  <published>2016-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Writing the blog this time round isn&#39;t as easy as it was when I had a primary diagnosis.&lt;p&gt;I would write a blog post when anything interesting happened.  Whether it be medical or personal.  I found it quite easy to just sit down and write.  This time round, I’m finding it hard.  I don’t know if it’s the constant fatigue or a case of Cantbearseditis, but it’s difficult.  (This post has taken about 4 hours to write…ridiculous!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I find myself in a position where it’s nearly two months after the last post and so much has happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we had Imy’s birthday.  It was quite interesting. As soon as she had opened her presents, her and Ross went to IKEA to get furniture for her bedroom that had been talked about, but we hadn’t got round to.  They came home with lots of boxes and then we went to Pizza Express for dinner.  A bit of a bonkers birthday if you ask me, but she was happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was Ross’s birthday. Unfortunately it was sandwiched between an MRI the day before and Herceptin the day after, so we were rather stuck in terms of what we could do. Fortunately, his parents’s were in the country so they came over for the day to make it a bit special for him and we had a great take out curry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/birthdays.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imy and Ross birthday&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In between the two birthdays, we had the Race for Life.  Thanks to a reconfigured RfL Gin Club team for 2016, Imy and Felix were able to run without me, much to their delight!  (I had been told that I hold them back…)
The week before the Race, I was contacted by the event organiser and asked if I would speak to a local newspaper about what had happened to me, and how the Race was so important to try and get more ladies to sign up. She also asked if I would go onto the stage at the event and do the same to encourage and thank the ladies involved. I even got to honk the horn to start it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imy and Felix raised over £1100, and as a team the total was well over £3000. Much needed money for a very good cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rfl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Race for Life&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to my back being so hurty after my op, Ross took this as an opportunity to replace the car.  Our car had sports suspension and I could feel every pot hole and fault in the road, (and there’s more than you know!).  We were due to replace it this year anyway, so it wasn’t long before he was going round local showrooms and reading up on cars.  Finally he decided upon a Mazda SUV and after signing on the dotted line, it was just a matter of time before it was delivered.  I hadn’t driven our old car since January, so I took it for a slow crawl around our close before we handed it over, bye bye old car.  I have yet to drive the new car, but I am looking forward to it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/newcar_oldcar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old car, new car&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few other events to mention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imy passed her grade 2 flute exam with merit.  Ross and I are so proud of her for sticking in and getting on with it, despite the tough times.  We are also very thankful to Heather&#39;s Mum, Shenna, for accompanying Imy on two of the pieces she had to play, and helping her along with the sight reading and aural tests.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ticked an item off my bucket list by going blonde. This came about as my hairdresser needed a model (for hair not looks - just as well!) who wanted to go blonde.  I&#39;m delighted with the results.  The kids thought I&#39;d be going platinum blonde, to a colour more like Felix&#39;s, so weren&#39;t too impressed with the change.  Pesky kids. :-)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Anna and Fiona organised a party for me at the Rugby Club.  The idea was to extend the Gin&#39;s I received for #GinForJulia to the Dad&#39;s so they could enjoy it as well.  We managed to get through a fair bit of it, but I had to leave early, due to reaching my limit after 2 G&amp;amp;T&#39;s, but feeling like I had a skinful.  I&#39;ll be glad when I&#39;m not taking the medication that affects me in this way.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ross&#39;s parents offered to look after the bairns for a weekend.  So, taking full advantage, we dropped them off in Newbury, and went on to Winchester.  
We had a lovely weekend, we walked a lot, we shopped, we chilled, we used the spa, we talked, and we missed the kids.  They hardly missed us, but I was delighted to hear how well they&#39;d behaved, how polite they were, and how generally wonderful they were.  I know they can play up for Ross and I, but they&#39;re ours and we are proud of them.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/winchester_collage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Winchester&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I think that’s us up to date…oh then comes radiotherapy… that’s a new post…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/birthdays-races&quot;&gt;Birthdays, Races and other stuff...&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on August 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Out the Otherside]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/out-the-otherside" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/out-the-otherside</id>
  <published>2016-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s been two weeks and five days since my surgery.&lt;p&gt;I had my operation in The Royal National Orthopaedic Hospital, Stanmore, North West London.  If you are having a tricky orthopaedic operation, you want to be in the best place, with the best equipment, and the best surgical team. I had that.  Even if the hospital is a bit wonky with sloped corridors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official name for my op was: “Combined anterior vertebrectomy with posterior fusion and instrumentation”.  In other words: Remove some of the vertebrae that had collapsed into bits, fix it into place with cement, wire, metal and screws to the vertebrae above and below.  A big operation.  However, no one told me how awful I would feel afterwards.  It took them a while, (and some tense words with a doctor) to get my pain under control, and in that time, I regretted everything.  I wish I hadn’t agreed to the op.  I was crying in the night as I was in so much pain, but the nurse wouldn’t believe I was in pain and I couldn’t move to get comfortable. The op was on the Saturday, I was in HDU until Monday, when I got moved to the regular ward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in hospital for 6 days.  Considering the surgery could have potentially left me paralysed below the waist, or with no bladder or bowel function, I think 6 days just shows how good the surgical team was and how determined I was to get home to my babies and Ross.  The hospital was 30 miles away from home, and on a good run would take 45 minutes.  Ross visited every day, but always made sure he left at a time when he wouldn’t get caught in A1/M25 traffic. My Dad and the bairns visited too, but they found it boring, so it wouldn’t be long before they were taken home. The hospital was a world away from the Garden House Hospice, which not only gave the kids things to do, but it was less than 5 minutes away, so friends and family could just pop in for as little or as long as they could. They could even take me out of the Hospice for a little while, which was an absolute no-no in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At times, in the hospital,  I found myself a bit lonely.  In general, I quite like my own company, I like pottering.  Unfortunately, I was unable to potter, as I was tied my bed, literally, with a catheter bag.  I was given various physiotherapy tasks that I had to do before I could be set free so I made sure I worked hard to get them right.  Once I was free, I had to do the Stair assessment, which made sure I was safe to go up and down stairs.  By 11am on Friday, I was all packed ready to come home.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for me to heal properly I have to be careful that I don’t bend down at the waist too far.  For example, I can’t bend in the middle to put my own socks and shoes on.  I have a grabber to help me pick things up from the floor.  I have to have a raised loo seat (sorry, to much information), and I have an Old Lady Chair, which we have borrowed from the British Red Cross.  The sofa’s in our front room are too low for me to sit on without causing damage to my newly cemented spine, and whilst the surgeon assured me, I couldn’t do any damage to his handiwork, I’d hate to think I could.  By the way, the Old Lady Chair doesn’t smell of wee.  Phew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m home, I get tired easily, but I enjoy having visitors, as long as they don’t  mind making their own tea.  I’m also enjoying online shopping, although Ross will be pleased to know I am trying to reign it in, so as not to bankrupt us.  Although, he’s giving it as good go himself with his new Bonsai obsession. (That needs a whole post to itself!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’re just waiting for the histology of the tissue taken from my spine now, which will dictate what happens next.  If the tissue is benign, then my treatment remains the same: Herceptin and Zometa infusions every 3 weeks, and hormone blockers in the form of an injection every 4 weeks, and daily tablets.  (There’s talk of surgery to remove my one remaining ovary, but I’ve asked for that to be put on hold for a bit first.)
 If the tissue is not benign (therefore cancerous), then my infusions will change to, most likely,  contain some form of chemotherapy - goodbye hair - again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t walk too far, as it hurts, but I’m not allowed to use a walking stick, unless I know we are going for a long walk, then it is necessary.  Progress is slow, but we’ll do what we have to:  keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/out-the-otherside&quot;&gt;Out the Otherside&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 23, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Half Term?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-half-term" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-half-term</id>
  <published>2016-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This half term is busy...&lt;p&gt;…really busy.  It started with an inset day on Friday, but rather than be able to put it to good use and have a nice day out in the sunshine, we had to go to the hospital to get a CT scan.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thursday evening before the inset day, I went to see The Sons of Pitches in Bury St Edmunds, just over an hours drive away.  Tash had bought me the ticket and had said that I didn’t need to decide whether I wanted to go or not, until the day came.  She knew someone else in the choir would jump at the chance to take my place.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so pleased I went!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was amazing, they are so talented. The way they use there voices is incredible.  It felt like there was a band there, but it was just the 6 of them. We had really good seats which were right over the stage.  It was quite an insightful position!  I got a picture with Joe after, and got a CD signed by Mide, and we got a group of with the ladies from the choir with him too. I also got a T-shirt, poster, and two CD’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sonjoe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Son Joe&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sat there enjoying the music, I realised that I have never been to a music gig before.  I’ve performed with various music groups either singing or playing some type of musical instrument where people have paid to see it, mostly in the North East of England. However I have performed in the Royal Festival Hall (I think, or it might have been the Queen Elizabeth Hall next door, but either way it was on the South Bank of London.) and in a beautiful church in Bergen, Norway. The groups also played in schools in London and Bergen. (I’ve just realised that I have been to a few Classical concerts, including the BBC Proms, and a couple of Picnic in the Park’s on Hampstead Heath.  What a nerd.)  It got me thinking.  I need to do a bucket list.  Not a grand, bungee jumping or potholing list, but watching a ballet at the Royal Opera House.  Punting on the Cam. Have a spa day with my friends, a boating holiday.  Little things, but things I haven’t done before.  Things that I should do.  Things I think I should do sooner rather than later.  Oh, and make a Will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Friday…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michelle offered to have the bairns, on Friday morning, which was really appreciated as she’d only just moved into her new house.  I’d gone to bed late, and had to get up early so I could eat something as I had a 4 hour fast before the CT scan.  I’ve had lots of scans, but this one I’ll remember for a while as the two tubes which connected my port to the saline and contrast solution weren’t tightened enough and came undone covering my hair me in rather sticky fluid. So that was pleasant.  They also threw in a doppler ultrasound of my legs to see if there was a clot anywhere.  There wasn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the rest of the half term is taken up with:&lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday - Appointment with the Orthopaedic Surgeon who will perform the surgery.&lt;br /&gt;
Wednesday - The 3 weekly Herceptin and Zometa infusion&lt;br /&gt;
Thursday - My Counseling session, and my Dad coming down (yay!)&lt;br /&gt;
Friday - Admitted into hospital&lt;br /&gt;
Saturday - Surgery&lt;br /&gt;
Sunday - Recovering from Surgery&lt;br /&gt;
Monday - I’m still in hospital, the bairns go back to school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I don’t feel we really get a half term.  I feel so bad for the kids. It’s all full of stupid medical stuff. This was the week we were going to go abroad on holiday.  Somewhere with a pool, somewhere reasonably hot. To get away from it all, have fun as a family.  But we can’t, because the stupid cancer got in the way.  I hate it.  I hate the way we have to change our plans to make room for it.  I hate it that form now on, I’m going to struggle to get travel insurance.  Get stuffed Cancer.  I want you out of my life.  I want it to be how it was before.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-half-term&quot;&gt;What Half Term?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 01, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Boy is 8]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/boy-is-8" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/boy-is-8</id>
  <published>2016-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">8!&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Felix had a few friends round to run around, have Nerf gun battles, and eat pizza.  Imogen got stuck in too, and a good time was had by all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is his birthday.  Ross and I had to wrap the birthday presents that were contained in a number of Amazon boxes.  We’d left pretty much everything until the last minute.  But luckily, we pulled it off and we got it all done on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/boyis8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Boy is 8&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix was very pleased with his presents including “Exploding Kittens” which I had been a bit dubious about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Birthday Tea was a curry at the Lancer.  Everyone was a winner with that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Birthday to my Beautiful Boy.   Love you to the Moon and Back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/boy-is-8&quot;&gt;The Boy is 8&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 'C' Word]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-c-word" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-c-word</id>
  <published>2016-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">And I don&#39;t mean the book...&lt;p&gt;…written by Lisa Lynch. Not because I found it difficult or to close to home, but because I borrowed it from the library and had to give it back when I tried to renew it, as someone else wanted it. (humph). I had to buy it in the end, but I haven’t managed to pick up where I left off, as I’m reading another book.  Slowly.  Very S L O W L Y. I used to be able to read books very quickly.  I don’t know why, but I’ve been finding it hard going.  I’m still trying to finish ‘The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August’ which I started last October, when I was recovering from my Reconstruction.  It’s very good, and I’d tell you who it was by, but I can’t be bothered to walk up stairs and find out.  You’ll have to look it up for yourselves.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, whilst I’ve been writing this blog, I am very inconsistent with the case (Grammar, yawn) of the ‘c’ in Cancer.  Should it be a lower case ‘c’, or an upper case ‘C’?  If you know, can you put it in the comments section belong, so if I do get an answer from someone who knows, I’ll try (ha!) to be more consistent in future.  I promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s.  I probably do know, but it’s been filed away in the deep, dark depths of my brain under - “Not Relevant at Present.”  Cancer has a habit of slowly taking over your brain. To be clear, I’m not talking literally, more metaphorically. At present, I do not have cancer in my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-c-word&quot;&gt;The 'C' Word&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 25, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Secondary + Silver]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/secondary+silver" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/secondary+silver</id>
  <published>2016-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Cancer.  It&#39;s a word everyone is frightened of.&lt;p&gt;Most people have been touched by it in many ways, either them themselves, a friend or a relative.  For some, it’s caught early, treated fast, and life can continue as usual.&lt;br /&gt;
 For others it’s not quite as straightforward.  The cancer may have started in one place and spread somewhere else.  Like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when people learn you have secondary cancer, it baffles me when they say something like, “You’ll be glad when this is all over!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, with secondary cancer, it will never be ‘all over’.  There is no cure there is only ‘management’.  The Oncologists and Surgeons have a lot of tricks up their sleeves in order to manage the secondary cancer in order to keep me alive for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve realised looking back over the blog, the posts the first time round were quite frequent.  Sometimes once a day.  This time round, after a flurry of posts when I was first re-diagnosed, I haven’t written any posts. I don’t know why.  Possibly, because the treatment has been largely the same.  Every 3 weeks I have my Herceptin and Zometa infusion.  Nothing has really happened.  Except something has happened…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The L4 vertebrae, which was the one the cancer spread to, and had the cyberknife radiotherapy to, has now collapsed, and is unstable, which could cause huge problems if something isn’t done.   I’ve been seeing an Spinal surgeon who has seen my scans and between him and the oncologist, they have come up with a plan.  So, on the 4th of June, I shall be having a Partial Vertebrectomy.  (If you want to look up the details, the internet is a marvelous thing!  But as far as I can tell, it’s surgery done with play dough and meccano.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another news, due to my hand swelling up, I have not been able to wear my wedding rings, although my eternity ring hung in there the longest.  I’ve been married to Ross for 11 years, and we were engaged for 18 months prior to that, so it felt very odd not having a ring on my ring finger.  Whilst I was out buying a friend’s birthday present, I started look in the trays of silver rings.  Once Ross realised what I was doing, and why, he started looking too.  Eventually we found one that we both agreed on, and I love it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ring.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wedding Ring&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/secondary+silver&quot;&gt;Secondary + Silver&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 24, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time marches on]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/time-marches-on" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/time-marches-on</id>
  <published>2016-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I can&#39;t quite believe my last post was in January. It seems an age away, but time marches on.&lt;p&gt;Looking at the blog we’ve missed out April and there’s been good reason, life settled back into some sort of routine. I’ve noticed Julia’s previous post was on mothers day, March 6th. The post made me smile because of the happy picture of Imogen with her “tackle monster” badge. A few hours after that photo was taken, I headed off to A&amp;amp;E with Imogen who was suffering from concussion after an blow to the head in a ruck earlier that day. Luckily, it was just a mild concussion but a confused and eccentric Imogen in the A&amp;amp;E waiting room is something I can chuckle at now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back now at February, it was a hard month. Lots of low points. As Julia’s pain is bought under control, she had to stay at the Garden House Hospice. However, life tries to be balanced and there were some good memories to! Julia’s birthday was one that comes to mind, a nice cream tea at Tapps and then Julia and I went out for dinner at The George. The amount of morphine swishing around her, meant that Julia couldn’t make it to pudding but it was good for her to get out the hospice for a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This neatly brings me back to the Garden House Hospice, what an amazing place. I didn’t really have a clue about such places, Julia’s initial reaction to the suggestion of going in to get some care was not positive. It shows how little we knew, quite simply they have been brilliant. They quickly got Julia’s pain under control and offered support for the family as a whole. That support is still ongoing and has and continues to be amazing. I’m so glad that such places exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia was back home from the Hospice with pain meds aplenty. These pain medicines have all sorts of side effects. The single worst being the smell that MST can make a person produce, at times it’s bordering chemical warfare grade. The first night back from the hospice, I was nearly gassed out of the bed! Thankfully with home cooking this side effect has settled, although there are times when in the supermarket when Julia suggests we quickly change aisle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike and Julie visited lots in March and April, their support was phenomenal and allowed me to get work and home life back on track. I can’t say thank you enough, those two little words don’t seem big enough. Over the Easter holidays we headed up to Cullercoats to see Julia’s family. The kids and I enjoyed plodging in the sea on Tynemouth Longsands and kicking the rugby ball about. We got to see Grandad’s boat before it was apparently nearly sunk in an incident that had been colourfully likened to an act as high sea piracy. Julia got to see her family and catch up, and although fatigue meant we had to return home early it was a good trip. The road trip also turned the kids into avid Archers fans as we listened to an Archers omnibus there and back, the rural intrigue kept them very quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fatigue we saw up in Cullercoats unfortunately has hung around. Julia rested for a couple of days then attended a weekend course for young people with secondary breast cancer in a hotel in London. It was hard for us both, her being away for the night. I found myself in a melancholic mood, missed her terribly and thought it a glimpse of the future to come. This was the result of being overly tired, something I try to avoid as it doesn’t help ones mood. Happily, it was only for a night and Julia was back home and very tired. I think she slept for the whole of Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve missed out many things really in this catchup post but the main theme is, February was hard and sucked. March was much better and quickly rolled into April where life felt pretty normal. There have been ups and downs and Julia’s recent fatigue curtailed her ability to potter or take the kids to school. But as much as we can we’ve cried, we’ve smiled and laughed together.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/time-marches-on&quot;&gt;Time marches on&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fireside Eggs & Mother's Day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/eggs" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/eggs</id>
  <published>2016-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">On Saturday night, Ross and I go out.  Out!&lt;p&gt;The town where we live, is a quirky old place.  There are several festivals that run during the year, one of which is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firesidefestival.org/&quot;&gt;The Fireside Festival.&lt;/a&gt;  It’s a Storytelling Festival, and Ross and I decide to give it a go and see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anarchistcook.info/&quot;&gt; George Egg: Anarchist Cook.&lt;/a&gt;  The premise is a man who cooks a three course meal, in an hour, using items commonly found in a hotel room.  It was good, it was funny, but I got Wobbly Head again.  I wish I didn’t get it.  Ross and Michelle both noticed that I got Wobbly Head half way through the show.  Still, I persevered, and afterwards we went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theorangetreebaldock.com/&quot;&gt;The Orange Tree&lt;/a&gt; for a quick drink.  However, after just one, I was ready to come home. I was conscious I needed to take my evening medication, so Ross walked me home, sorted my meds and then he went back out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, that I had a little cry.  It was Saturday night, we had a babysitter, we had a legitimate reason to go out.  But I just didn’t have the energy.  It just didn’t seem fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I took myself off to bed, and with the help of the sleeping pills, I was off to the Land of Nod, and soon enough woken up with cuddles from the bairns on Mother’s Day.  They had made me some lovely hand made cards, the top one in the picture being from Imy.  The the bottom right is a list of things that make me a good mum according to Felix,  I’m particularly pleased with the Bedroom Tidier - I had rather hoped that they would be doing it themselves by now, but they obviously appreciate the help.  The glass cat makes me smile.  They know me well.  Crazy Cat Lady!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mothersday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mothers Day Gift and Cards&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After breakfast, (not in bed, as that would make too many crumbs and I want to spend the time with the family), I decide to go to the rugby club and catch up with the news from there.  It was good to see people who I hadn’t seen for a while, and we also see the smiley faces of the kids as they came in from their training session covered in mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tacklemonster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tackle Monster&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick sprint (as much as you can with a stick) round the supermarket, once home, I was told to go and enjoy a Mother’s Day nap.   Which I did.  Very much so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Mather’s Day to all you lovely Mum’s out there.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/eggs&quot;&gt;Fireside Eggs & Mother's Day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sing When You're Winning]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/choir" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/choir</id>
  <published>2016-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Once home, life starts to settle, into the new, new normal.&lt;p&gt;The day after I return home, Dad decides that it’s time for him to go back home, and I have to admit, Julie needs him more than I do now.  I don’t want to be greedy, he’s spent so much time with us, and for that I will be eternally grateful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more visitors cross the threshold, and I begin to start to go out and do normal things again.  I watch Felix’s swimming lesson, I go to the supermarket, just normal things.  Normal things are good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday evening, I manage to pull off the biggest coup to date.  And that was to return to choir.  I only managed the first half of the session as I found it difficult to keep up with the pace of things, but I enjoyed it, and I’m really glad I went. After an hour, I start to get what I call Whirly Eyes and Wobbly Head.  This is where my eyes start to roll back in their sockets, or where I can’t keep my head held up.  Everyone gets it at some point or another but they are more frequent for me these days.  Luckily, Tash gives me a lift home, and hopefully, all things being equal, I’ll be there again next week, failing that, the week after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to be well enough to sing in a couple of concerts this Spring/Summer.  Fingers Crossed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx   &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/choir&quot;&gt;Sing When You're Winning&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 02, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm Going Home]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/home" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/home</id>
  <published>2016-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Home again, Home again, Jiggity Jig!&lt;p&gt;On Monday the Hospice have the Multi-Disciplinary team meeting, and it’s here that they decide what they are going do with me.  After discussions with me about my pain control, the doctors and nurses decide that they are going to aim to get me home for Wednesday.  This is great news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having such lot of food at my party, Tracey’s Magnificent Bombay Sapphire Birthday Cake was donated to the Hospice so that the in-patients could have a piece with their Monday afternoon tea, distributed by the volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cake2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bombay Sapphire Birthday Cake&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These volunteers, who give their own time up to help out, are without doubt a priceless resource, one that Letchworth and Baldock should be proud of.  One evening I found myself having my water changed by one of my neighbours.  Funny who you bump into - in the most unexpected of places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the cake had been distributed to anyone who wanted a piece (and it was decreed to be delicious by all), the rest was taken home and the kids and Grandad devoured the remainder very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening I had a meeting with my Oncologist who has decided to change my Hormone therapy tablets.  The biopsy on my spine, had confirmed that the tumour was ER+ which meant that the Tamoxifen hadn’t been doing it’s job properly.  So, I’m to switch to another hormone therapy which involves a monthly injection, and different hormone therapy tablets.  The injection is called Zoladex, and has to be done monthly by a nurse at my GP’s surgery and tablets, taken daily, are called Anastrozole for those that are interested.  The nuisance is, that had they taken out both ovaries in the Oophorectomy and Cystectomy I had in May, then this would be one part of therapy I wouldn’t have to worry about.  But, here we are, this is what we have to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after lots of visits from lots of lovely people, it was soon Wednesday morning and I was sent home with enough prescription drugs to fill an pharmacy and instructions that if I felt any worse, to go back if I felt any changes for the worse.  Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Mam had come down to see me, and we caught up over a coffee at a local coffee shop.  I think she was glad to see that I didn’t look very ill on the surface, and was in fact quite normal and like my old self, keeping on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/home&quot;&gt;I'm Going Home&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 24, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mini Gin Festival]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-festival" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-festival</id>
  <published>2016-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Great Fun, Great Friends, Great Gin!&lt;p&gt;In the run up to the Mini Gin Festival, I had a few things to do to make sure things went off well.  Thankfully I could rely on Fiona to pretty much run the show, but I did want to get involved in a few things.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to sort out getting enough vintage crockery for 20 people.  Luckily for me, a couple of years ago, through the magic of social media, I met a marvelous lady called Jenny, online who happens to own
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/THE.GREEN.HOUSE.MARKET/?fref=ts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Green House Community Market&lt;/a&gt; in Letchworth.  She was having treatment for breast cancer at the time I was restoring some furniture, (which was on my Bucket List),  and needed some help with the paint and method.  She was a star and helped me out massively.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the Green House is an Aladdin’s cave for retro, vintage and antique furniture and accessories, and I was able to go in with Rachel on Friday and select the crockery we wanted.  We also had a mooch around a little shop to buy a few bits and bobs to go on my new book shelf, but again, it wasn’t too long before I was feeling fatigued and ready to return to the Igloo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another morning and afternoon of rest, it was time for me to get ready for my party.  Fiona had done a fabulous job in getting things prepared.  The other partygoers got into the vintage tea party spirit, and made lovely cakes, sandwiches, mini quiches and other delicious little morsels in preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/goodies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cakes&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tea&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we arrive,  we were all lucky enough to have our photo’s taken by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/SimonBrooksPhotography&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Simon Brooks&lt;/a&gt; who took some amazing shots of us, some of which can been seen on his Facebook page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/juliafiona.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Julia &amp;amp; Fiona&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/party.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Party&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of how the Mini Gin Festival started can be found here:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-kindness/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gin of Human Kindness&lt;/a&gt;.  And it at this point that we must mention Katie at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/hurrahforgin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hurrah For Gin&lt;/a&gt; as without her, the #ginforjulia thing would never have happened, and we would never have been able to put on such a fantastic Mini Festival.  Katie, you rock. x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Party was fantastic, I had such a good time, and the donations we received via the #ginforjulia hashtag on social media meant the party was a huge success.  It was a shame I couldn’t have a small Gin, but I am determined that once the pain has settled and I am on fewer painkillers, I’ll be able to try a gin…or two!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pinkster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Local Pinkster Gin&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who was involved in the party, either helping me celebrate, or for making a donation.  I appreciate it all.  My birthday cake, made by Tracey was a particular hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Birthday Cake&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-festival&quot;&gt;Mini Gin Festival&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 22, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mascots]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mascots" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mascots</id>
  <published>2016-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">A brilliant, fantastic experience.&lt;p&gt;I had been instructed that Saturday was my strict day of rest.  I was not to leave the Igloo at all in preparation for Sunday’s Birthday Party.  Lesley came to visit with some jeans I’d asked her to buy for me, and then Fiona came round with Jess to organise some party bags, a surprise for our party guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Ross, my Dad, and the bairns it was a different matter.  Imogen and Felix had won a competition to be Mascots for The Saracens, their favourite premiership Rugby Union team.  The game was on Saturday afternoon, at their home game to Gloucester.   It was a minor fixture in the great scheme of rugby premiership games, but to them it was the best game of the season.  They were given a tour of the tunnel and changing rooms, and when the time came they accompanied a player onto the pitch before the game.  They had such a good time and were buzzing with excitement when they came to tell me about it all afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sarriesmascots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mascots&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mascots&quot;&gt;Mascots&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 20, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's my Birthday!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/birthday" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/birthday</id>
  <published>2016-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;m going to party like it&#39;s my Birthday!&lt;p&gt;I was adamant I wasn’t going to be in the Igloo for my birthday.  In the end, I didn’t really have a choice.  My pain wasn’t under control, and I was regularly having to top up what they were giving me. I had been to the Spire in Harpenden the day before to start my Herceptin and Zometra treatment, and on the afternoon I hoped to be sent home, I spent asleep fatigued from the excursion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan had been for me to go out for a Birthday Cream Tea at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/TeaatTapps/?fref=ts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tea at Tapps&lt;/a&gt;.   I’ve been there a few times and am always impressed with their wonderful range of teas, coffees, and cakes.  Ross picked me up from the Igloo and took me to meet the bairns and Grandma and Grandad to have out birthday cream tea.  It was delicious.  My only grumble is that the scones aren’t big enough, but that’s the steroids talking…I’m sure they are the perfect size for a normal person!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt very lucky, and overwhelmed with the amount of cards and presents I received.    After a wander around the gift shop and garden centre, I was sent back to the Igloo with strict instructions to sleep as Ross and I were going out that night for a meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross collected me from the Igloo,  all dressed up and ready to go, and then after dropping the car off at home, my Dad took us to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thegeorgeatbaldock.co.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The George&lt;/a&gt;  for a fine dining spectacular.  I enjoyed being out with Ross, spending some quality time with him in a non- medical setting.  However, I quickly started to feel very fatigued, so much so we didn’t manage a pudding.  You know things are serious when I can’t manage a pudding!
The starter and main meal were delicious and all in all we were out for about an hour, but it was a good hour, I enjoyed it.  Enjoyed being a normal couple with my husband.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thegeorge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The George&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/birthday&quot;&gt;It's my Birthday!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 18, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Garden House Hospice]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hospice" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hospice</id>
  <published>2016-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The word &#39;Hospice&#39; isn&#39;t really very user friendly.&lt;p&gt;Not for me anyway.  A Hospice is where people go to die.  So, when it was suggested to me by my Oncologist that I stay in a hospice, to say I wasn’t keen was an understatement!  However, my pain levels weren’t being managed and I needed something to happen to get back on track.  I had a conversation with Big Brother Callum on Wednesday, and I suggested that if the Hospice was called something else, I might be able to handle it a bit better.  So we coined the phrase ‘Igloo’.  You can leave an Igloo.  That’s fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is where Letchworth’s Garden House Hospice came in.  A small hospice, five minutes from my own home.  On the Thursday afternoon, I was admitted into my own little room, with a view of a lovely, cared for garden.  I met the nurses and a Doctor, and told them in no uncertain terms that I wouldn’t be staying for very long, maybe a day or two, and then I would be going home with my family.  Max was coming to see me on Saturday, and who would want to spend a day visiting someone in a Hospice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The staff nodded in agreement, went through my drugs list and I made myself comfortable.  The next day, Fiona and Michelle came to visit me in The Igloo.  Spirit’s were raised and I started to feel calmer about things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, Max assured me that he was fine to visit me in the Igloo, so when he arrived, complete with souvenir mug from Cats the Musical, I was really pleased. He’d had a late night the night before, and an early start that morning to be be able to get the train to visit me from Manchester, so at one point, the nurses came in to find him asleep on the armchair in my room, and me asleep in my bed.  They just left us to it.  They were great like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few days my opinion of the Igloo/Hospice changed substantially.  I hadn’t realised what other services they offer there.  We had support workers come in to us and offer counselling, not only to me, but to Ross and the kids.  They were given activity packs to keep them occupied as well as comfort quilts which were to be used as something that they would associate with a “safe place”.  There was a lounge next to my room so they didn’t have to spend all their time there looking at me feeling all sorry for myself.  Another massive thing that I hadn’t realised was that I wasn’t tied to the hospice.  I could come and go, as and when I wanted, as long as I was back in time for my medication.  This meant I was able to go to Rachel and Greg’s to watch the 6 Nation rugby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also able to greet Dad and Grandma Julie when they arrived at ours.  I had a little cry, and was taken back to what I had come to regard as my little oasis of calm, The Igloo.  As this was half term, we had planned on the kids going to stay up in the North East for a few days.  However, we decided that it would be best if Grandma and Grandad stayed at ours so the kids were able to visit me when they wanted, and they’d have some days out around me.  And crucially, get to see me on my birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had plenty of visitors to the Igloo, as well as support from the staff.  I was still adamant that I was going to be home for my birthday, but after a week in the Igloo, I was still there, relinquishing control of things to the staff slowly but surely and starting to realise that BIG STUFF was happening and I couldn’t deal with it all on my own.  If I was still in the Igloo for my birthday, it didn’t matter.  I was, after all, Just Visiting, and Big Brother Callum made me a sign to make sure that I remembered that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/justvisiting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Just Visiting&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hospice&quot;&gt;Garden House Hospice&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 17, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberknife]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/cyberknife" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/cyberknife</id>
  <published>2016-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It sounds all very grand and space aged doesn&#39;t it?&lt;p&gt;Super high tech stuff which will hopefully help alleviate some of my pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning it was up and out to Mount Vernon Cancer Centre for the first of three Cyberknife treatments. The bairns were safely deposited at Fiona’s so she could take them to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traffic at that time in the morning on the A1 and M25 is horrid, and people are idiots. Luckily Ross did a super job of getting us there safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once there,  we had a quick chat with Dr Shah, my Oncologist, who told us that it could be 3-4 weeks before the pain in my back started to subside, and he was mindful that my painkiller meds aren’t quite doing the job.  He was going to speak to the Palliative nurse, Julia, who I’d seen on Monday,  with the intention of having a plan of action in place to best deal with my pain, by the time I’d finished the last treatment on Thursday.  All I want to be able to do is walk the kids to school in the morning.  Make their tea again.  Start to become a more useful member of Team Lawley!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyberknifebed1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyberknife Cradle&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have a great night’s sleep, so lying still, on a vacuum packed beanbag looking up at an artificial blue sky listening to music for an hour, whilst the scanner and robot do their stuff was quite appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyberknifeready.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyberknife Ready&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment didn’t hurt.  The robotic machine just moved around me and whirred, firing beams of radiation at me.  Nothing scary, nothing nasty, it just killed off bad cancer cells accurately.  All whilst I snoozed and listened to some music.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday was the same.  Kids dropped off at Caroline’s, and I had the second of the third treatments.  All calm, all fine.  Nothing of any concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as is standard, we Keep on, Keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/cyberknife&quot;&gt;Cyberknife&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 10, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charities]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/charities" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/charities</id>
  <published>2016-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Macmillan Support&lt;p&gt;My GP had referred me on to the Community Palliative Care Specialists in order that we could tap into the information and services they have available to them.  Being under a Palliative Care team feels like a double edge sword.  On one side it’s great, they can give me pointers in what we need to do in terms of getting me out and about more by applying for a Blue Badge and also the short term hire of a wheelchair.  The other side to the sword is that whichever way I look at it, I have a Terminal Illness, Stage 4 cancer, and there is nothing anyone can do for that.  All we can do is manage the Cancer.  I will never be free from it, and I will always be living under the shadow or it.  (Even at this point now, I’m still waiting for someone to tell me there’s been a terrible mistake, and it’s a slipped disk.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say that, Julia, the Palliative Care nurse was brilliant.  She was empathetic, and a great listener.  She gave us a hope that the pain I’m in will be short-term but the Cyberknife treatment can take 3-4 weeks to actually work.  She reviewed my current medication list, made some minor adjustments and gave us another prescription.  As I say, she’s a very knowledgeable person, another good one to have on my side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing she said to me was, and the thing I came away feeling most positive about was when she said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“You are living with Cancer, not dying from Cancer”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;race-for-life&quot;&gt;Race for Life&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Race For Life has been an event that I have enjoyed participating in for  years now.  I’ve done it 8 or 9 times, including last years Pretty Muddy spectacular.  It’s got a great atmosphere and people are very generous with their donations, it’s a good cause after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past two Race’s have happened around the time of Ross’s birthday, and have rather eclipsed it somewhat.  We had thought that this year we would miss the Race, or do a different one and concentrate on Ross and his birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we told Imy and Felix that my Cancer had come back, Imy immediately asked if she could do the Race again.  Felix was in agreement, and Ross selflessly agreed with the kids that doing the Race was an important, positive thing for them to do. I don’t know what state I’ll be in in July, I many be fully mobile, I may be in a wheelchair, I don’t know, so I said I’d make a call nearer the time.  Luckily,  members of The Gin Club had already signed up for the Race and Imy and Felix joined their team, and then they helped set up their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/ImyAndFelix/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Just Giving Page&lt;/a&gt;  If you feel inclined to sponsor them, please follow the link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/charities&quot;&gt;Charities&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 09, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gin of Human Kindness]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-kindness" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-kindness</id>
  <published>2016-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s my birthday next week. I&#39;ll be 39.&lt;p&gt;Back in November, when things were on an even keel, I had organised for myself and a small group of friends to go to a Gin Festival in London to celebrate my birthday as a treat for us all.  I don’t usually celebrate my birthdays in big ways.  They are usually sedate affairs involving Ross and the bairns and Tesco Club Card vouchers.  Organising an afternoon do in London felt quite an extravagance!  I hardly ever go into London these days, I spent years commuting from North Hertfordshire to the office on Regent Street, and if I’m honest, I don’t miss the Big Smoke too much.  I like living in our little country town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I found out that I’d gotten a bit poorly again, I had assumed that my friends would just go to the festival without me.  My friends like gin!  We’re not called the Gin Club for nothing!  But then I was being told that plans needed to change, the afternoon was not going to happen without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I’m not fit for much at the minute, in quite a lot of pain, and can’t walk very far, I decided that I’d like to have a few close friends round for a sophisticated afternoon tea, for a chat, and to help me deal with my new tea and cream scone obsession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then something strange happened.  I follow blog via Facebook called &lt;a href=&quot;http://hurrahforgin.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hurrah For Gin&lt;/a&gt;.  A Mum, called Katie,  who tells it how it is in her struggles with motherhood supported by gin.  She’s hilarious and strikes a chord with me.  Read her blog, buy Gin Bunny art.  She’s funny.  I think we’d get on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other night, I noticed Katie was running a competition to win a bottle of gin.  She was after a a funny story to give everyone a giggle. I decided to enter, thinking it would have been nice to give my friends who were missing out on the Gin Festival a cheeky tipple of gin during our afternoon tea.  My story wasn’t funny, it was quite maudlin, but it attracted a lot of attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t win the competition for said bottle of gin. Katie was after a funny story, not my doom and gloom one, and the lady who won it, definitely deserved it a whole lot more than me.  I can’t mix my medication with alcohol, so at least she’ll be able to drink it and enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it didn’t stop there.  It’s fair to say, things went a bit mental!  My original comment had been that my breast cancer had spread to my bones and was no longer curable and that I’d like to win the bottle of gin to thank my friends for being there for me during such a difficult time.  There were lots of nice comments and ‘likes’.  Facebook is good for things like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My comment was still getting a lot of attention, and Katie had shared it on her page.  By Sunday morning, I had to enlist the help of my good friend Fiona to liaise with various different people and companies who wanted to donate things to my Afternoon Birthday Tea and Gin Treat.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been totally overwhelmed by the warmth and generosity of strangers.  Little me, turning 39 next week, with a husband, two kids, 3 cats, a penchant for gin, wit and sarcasm, but now with the support of the wider Gin Community helping me thank those that are closest to me for making this whole shitty journey a bit more manageable.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cancer, you really do suck.  But you will not suck the joy out of my life.  Not a chance.  Not when there are people like Katie from Hurrah for Gin, and Fiona, and the rest of my support group who will drop everything to help me out if I need anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Facebook alerts have gone mad, but it’s in a good way, and it’s taking my mind off the pain and the cancer, and it feels wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who has taken time to keep the light shining.  You have no idea how overwhelmed, humbled and grateful I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/gin-kindness&quot;&gt;Gin of Human Kindness&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brothers (Definitely not Grimm)]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/brothers-not-grimm" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/brothers-not-grimm</id>
  <published>2016-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I have three brothers, Callum is a year and a half older than me, Regan is 5 years younger, and Max is 14 years younger.&lt;p&gt;I think it’s fair to say that over the past 15 years, my brothers and I have drifted apart, and we are not as close as we once were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed a happy, if slightly unusual childhood, we all got on and all turned into reasonably well adjusted human beings.  But things change, I moved to London, and we don’t see each other as often as we want.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brothers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Brothers and Me&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This photo was taken when Regan married Lorna a few years ago.  It was a great day of laughing, celebrating and general silliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then something big happens.  Like getting told you have Cancer.  The first time round, in October 2013, everyone thought that it was just a lump (no pun intended) in the road.  A small hiccup.  Pick yourself up, dust yourself down, crack back on.   Nothing to worry about.  Modern medicine is great.  That’s what was supposed to happen. The statistics are on my side. We had all the time in the world to see each other.  During one of our visits, I was chatting to Callum asking what he was planning for his 40th birthday. I’d joked that I’d just like to be alive on my 40th.  I didn’t actually mean it, I thought I would be around for decades.  These things happen to “other people”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last week, unbeknownst to me, Ross had been in cahoots with Callum and Regan, and at 10am on Friday morning after driving for over 200 miles, they arrived on my doorstep.  They had come for the day to see me, because now it’s important.  Now we don’t have the luxury of time on our hands.  They were armed with meals, care packages, and stuff for the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chatted about this and that for a little while and then got on to the Big Stuff.  Callum had a look at my MRI images, trying to see what the doctors had decided was suspicious, he may have been able to see something, but it gave him something solid to focus on.   It was so hard telling them that this disease, that was supposed to be a minor glitch, was going to get the better of me, and there was nothing I could do about it.  That was tough.  Very tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you do after that?  Well you go to the pub next door, get sausage baguettes, get a hug off the land lord, and laugh about what we got up to as kids.  Remind ourselves that we had years of shared, happy, history, that needs to be passed on to our kids.  My kids might live ‘Down South’ but they still needs to have connections to their cousins ‘Up North’.  Callum and Regan need to make sure that this happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short while later, the school run is done and Imy and Felix are excited to see their Uncles and it’s not long before Top Trumps is being played, sweets are being eaten and the cheekiness starts.  At this point, I start to snooze, but as everything seems to be under control, there is no issue and Callum tells me to carry on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before long, it’s time for them to say goodbye, so more hugs, and we wave them off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was great to see them.  We talked more on that day than we had in years.  It was good, I enjoyed it.  I do love my brothers, I need them to know that.  I’ll be looking forward to squeezing Max when I see him next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully once we’ve got some of the pain under control, I’ll be able to go on a visit to see them.  Create some more shared, happy memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/brothers-not-grimm&quot;&gt;Brothers (Definitely not Grimm)&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 05, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[World Cancer Day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/world-cancer-day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/world-cancer-day</id>
  <published>2016-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today is World Cancer Day.&lt;p&gt;And what better way to spend it than at The Mount Vernon Cancer Centre, the East and North Hertfordshire NHS Trust specialised cancer centre.  It takes ages to get there, and as I’m not sleeping well at night, I use the opportunity to catch up on some zzzzz’s.  I feel bad about this as Ross is also sleeping badly, but he’s the one who can drive so he gets the short straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we’ve registered for our appointment, and filled in the relevant paperwork we wait to see the consultant to discuss the next phase of treatment.  Except today we don’t see my consultant.  We see someone else.  This isn’t a problem at all, he’s an expert in Cyberknife.  He knows what he’s talking about and answers our questions thoroughly.  He talks more to Ross than me, as I appear to be on another planet, and I’m not really taking things in.  This is why having Ross with me at these appointments is so important.  Goodness knows what I’d bring out from the meetings…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cyberknife technology is extremely accurate.  They are only interested in frying the bad cells.  We get shown where the treatment is going to be done, what the machine looks like, and it’s explained that during the sessions, a CT scanner will be constantly used, and the rays adjusted to ensure maximum damage to the cancer, minimal damage to me and my important nerves.  Each treatment will last about an hour, there will be one session a day and I will have 3 sessions.  My first session is in Tuesday, 9th February, and I will be finished on Thursday 11th.  I’m grateful that these sessions only take days, not weeks, like the radiotherapy for breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyberkniferoom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyberknife Room&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/world-cancer-day&quot;&gt;World Cancer Day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 04, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quirky Hospital]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/quirky-hospitals" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/quirky-hospitals</id>
  <published>2016-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Tuesday morning starts at 3am.&lt;p&gt;Ross and I wake early and chat about what is to happen today.  I’m booked into the Royal National Orthopaedic Hospital in Stanmore, North London in order that they can give me a bone biopsy of the naughty vertebrae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was due to be there for 7am, so at 6am we were on our way down the A1.  That road at that time is horrible.  There are idiots around at that time.  It is very dark, and everyone seems to need to be very close to the car in front.  Talk about making a stressful situation more stressful than in needs to be!  I’m so glad I don’t have to do that journey often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross dropped me off at the main doors, and went off to find a parking space. This hospital is very quirky.  All corridors seem to be off a very sloped corridor.  It’s just odd.  Also, because of the nature of the hospital, everyone has mobility problems, which means everyone thinks they have priority over everyone else.  This makes for some hilarious stand offs.  Who goes first?  The patient in the bed, the one in the wheelchair, the one on crutches or the one with one leg.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten minutes later, we were on the ward which I had been instructed to go to only to be told that there was no record of me on their list for that day.  More letters were produced, I turned my humour up a notch (it was either that or cry), and the relevant information was found and I was taken to another ward where my name was on the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had thought that the bone biopsy was to be done under local anaesthetic and that we would be out of the hospital quite quickly.  As it turns out, after a discussion with a very nice Anaesthetist, it is revealed that it was all to be done under a General. This means they have to go through my medical history and current medication list. This takes some time, but it gives me a chance to explain that I don’t tolerate GA’s very well and this gives her enough information to make sure that she gives me plenty anti-sickness drugs.  Once all this is done, the porter is ready to take me down to the imaging unit.  The biopsy that they are doing is being done using a CT scanner so they can have maximum accuracy when taking samples out with needles.  No one really wants to guess when you are dealing with the spine and nerves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross accompanies me down to the imaging unit, helps me change into a gown, and after a chat with the doctor who is doing the procedure, it’s not long before he’s despatched back to our ward and I’m in lying down having cannula’s inserted and the drugs are administered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What feels like five seconds later, I’m awake and before long I’m back on the ward with Ross.  I’m anxious to get my painkillers back on the go, and thanks to a wonderful nurse, we are given the permissions we need and I’m feeling more at ease with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey home happens in a whirl.  Helen, one of the wonderful ladies I met online through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breastcancercare.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Breast Cancer Care &lt;/a&gt; November Newbie 2013 support forums, organised for a charity &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/blanketssentwithlove/&quot;&gt;Sent With Love&lt;/a&gt; to send me a beautiful handmade blanket.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sent-with-love.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comfort Blanket&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blanket is the perfect size for me to take with me to hospital, to remind me of home.  The children had been given instructions to have the blanket around them whenever they can so they can get their smell on it.  (The nice after bath, clean smells, not the slightly cabbagy school smell).  This blanket is rolled up and used as a pillow and before long, Ross has got me home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so tired, Dad gives me my tea early, and off I go to bed.  The drugs alarms are all set, so I don’t have to worry about forgetting anything and that’s that.  Night night.  Off to sleep and a new day tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/quirky-hospitals&quot;&gt;Quirky Hospital&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 03, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>