<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2013-11-08T21:08:09+00:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fairly normal day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fairly-normal" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fairly-normal</id>
  <published>2013-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After sorting the laundry ready so that we could get a load on as soon as it was installed, I walked the bairns to school.  It took us a bit longer than normal, as I wasn’t able to move fast, and despite leaving 5 minutes earlier we still only just made it when the bell rang.  But we made it, and after quick (and hard fought from Boy Child) kisses, they were in and ready to learn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met up with the Gin Club at Michelle’s which was great.  It’s the first time I’ve had a chance to discuss things fully with them, and it was just the tonic I needed.  It was also lovely to see the two smiley babies, and the brand new Joni!  In all the mental ness that has enveloped the Lawley’s in the past few weeks, it’s good to remember that life goes on around us, and others have their own battles to fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left early as I was tired and came home to find the washing machine being installed.  Great news.  Once it was in, Ross and I had a cursory look at the instructions, loaded it up and started as we meant to go on.  I then took myself off to bed as I was tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I woke up it was time to got to the hairdressers. I’d decided with everything going on, I might as well get my hair cut short so it’s one less thing to worry about.  Izzy, my hairdresser, was great.  There were a few tears but I reiterated that this Cancer will not beat me, and it’s just a chapter in my life.  And I now have new hair!  It’s lush.  Thanks Iz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, at school pickup time, it was tipping it down.  Ross collected Imogen and I waited for Felix.  As I was waited, Imogen came towards me with her classmate Norah who handed me a gift bag.  I thanked her for it, I was so touched and surprised that she would want to give me something.  I got home and opened it, and it was bubble bath and a card.  It said she had chosen and bought it herself and that she hoped it would help me through my treatment.  Tears. Fat tears.  What an amazing little girl.  So compassionate.  I’m getting tearful just writing about it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way out of the school yard, Imogen asked if I’d like to talk to her teacher.  I wasn’t sure why she hadn’t asked Ross to do this, but as she was keen, I went.  I was told that I should be proud and pleased with Imogen this week.  She’d been really engaged, keen and hard-working.  I am proud of her.  She’s taken a pretty rubbish situation and turned it to around into something positive.  She’s awesome, and I’m lucky that I’m her Mummy.  Something I keep reminding both her and Felix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got home and dry we just sat, watched tv and relaxed.  The kids kept cuddling me, with Felix making sure he knew which was my sore arm so he could cuddle the other side so as not to hurt me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before long it was off to Imogen’s gymnastics with the promise of fish and chips or curry afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fairly-normal&quot;&gt;A fairly normal day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 08, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A clean sheet]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clean-sheet" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clean-sheet</id>
  <published>2013-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve slept well the last few days so can’t complain.  This stress does wierd
things - for one I’ve lost my thirst for beer at home.
For the past two nights I really wanted a beer, yet could only manage 1/2 a pint
and had to throw the rest down the drain - weird and worrying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lie in bed wondering why I’m awake and I realise that
I feel bad about the ear bashing that we had given John Lewis Customer Services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to make good I decided I’d turn it round and I started drafting an email
in my head and I decided to get up and write it down before I forgot it.  Being
the procrastinator that I am, I started drafting this blog post first! Well
I read this post first: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rats-funnybone.com/25-funny-auto-correct-fails/&quot;&gt;25 auto correct fails&lt;/a&gt; I saw it on facebook and it brightened my morning considerably!  Here’s
my email to John Lewis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hi Aimée,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thank you so much for getting the
washing machine and tumble dryer delivered. You have single handedly restored
our faith in John Lewis.  Our thanks also
go out to those others in the background who made this happen.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Julia and I are both 36 and we have two children Imogen, 7 and Felix, 5.  Three
weeks ago after 5 months of back and forth with the NHS Julia was diagnosed
with breast cancer. These have been the most stressful and emotionally turbulent
3 weeks of our lives. In preparation for the hard times to come Julia put me in
charge of the laundry, the day after we ordered the washing machine our own
washing machine took umbrage and broke down completely.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've been thinking (I awoke at 4:30am thinking about this) and would like, if
possible to ask two things from John Lewis:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
1. Julia dropped quite a bombshell on your colleague in the call center (I think
her name was Karen). It can't have made her day to have someone crying on the
phone whilst describing our situation, and although she couldn't help us
speed things up, she was kind and tried to help.  Please make sure she is ok.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
2. Compensation.  We don't want any, we have a working washing machine and would
much rather John Lewis donate any compensation you would have given to us to
charity.  Julia has run 7 Race For Life's and never thought she would be running
her own personal race this year. She is determined to get round the Race For Life
next year. If you could donate the money to a cancer charity, I'm sure they
would be grateful - as would we.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As part of our journey and as some form of therapy we are blogging our journey
at http://teamrj.co.uk and I'd like your permission to post any response there.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yours sincerely,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The Lawleys
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I got a fantastic response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hi Ross,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thank you for your email and your kind words, your thanks are truly appreciated by myself and the others who have assisted me. It really has been a pleasure getting this issue resolved, you have been patient and courteous in allowing me time to get things done.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think it is a beautiful gesture and would be happy to offer a donation to a charity of your choice. I would like to offer £100 which I know your chosen charity will put to great use. ...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I honestly can't imagine the stress you and your family have been under lately and I am genuinely sorry that John Lewis has contributed to this. I would like to offer my best wishes to you all and I hope that you succeed in your new role as the chief laundry man.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You may share your experience in your blog, you have my absolute permission. This is a wonderful idea and as you say a great form of therapy. I hope Julia enjoys the Race for Life, I'm sure she will do herself and everyone proud.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Kind regards,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Aimée
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So John Lewis have made good, the washing machine has arrived, been installed and
is working nicely. Whats more the tumble dryer has been installed in the
conservatory - a revelation!  Glad thats all sorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At lunchtime, I took Julia to have her hair cut and now it’s short, quite like
it was when we first met - she looks gorgeous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen sees my old award (if you can call it that) in the study. It’s a picture of
me when I was 8, I had just been gunged by the Hash House Harriers in Riyadh.
It’s titled “Ross Lawley the biggest little shit” - Imogen struggles with the
last word, then repeats it 5 times “shit, shit, shit, shit, shit”.
Oh brother.  Julia is not going to be happy with me!  I have to tell Imogen
she’s not allowed to used that word as it’s a swear word and I tell her it means
“poo”.  Imogen runs downstairs to tell mummy, “daddy &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; the biggest little poo
you know”.  What can you do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This evening, its been Imogen’s gymnastics and then a curry - all good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signing off for now - Chief Laundry Man&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/clean-sheet&quot;&gt;A clean sheet&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 08, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Scans]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/more-scans" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/more-scans</id>
  <published>2013-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to be having a new washing machine delivered between 2pm and 9pm.  It was getting quite desperate as Felix had wet the bed, and anyone with a family knows, it just keeps multiplying!  So I rang then at about 5:30pm for an eta only to find they had no record of the delivery. It had been arranged for Monday, but as I had my operation, I had rung to reschedule.  Only half that happened.  They cancelled Monday but didn’t rebook.  I was told they’d ring me from the distribution centre to rearrange.  We didn’t expect to hear anything that evening so carried on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday morning, I needed to go back to Harpenden for a MRI scan.  We got there a bit early, so took the opportunity to ring them again and find out what was going on.  I let Ross take over.  I couldn’t deal with that as well.  After a while of going backwards and forwards they said they needed to speak to me as I’d placed the order.  They then told me the next available delivery was the 15th Nov.  I’m afraid I lost it.  I said something along the lines of “no, I need it sooner than that.  I have breast cancer, I have a 5 year old son who is wetting the bed with worry, and I have washing mounting up.  This needs to be sorted.”  I might have cried a bit too.  She then said she’d get back to me to which I responded “you’ll have to talk to my husband as I have an MRI Scan”.  I wasn’t very kind, and feel a bit bad about it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while later, I was attached to a drip and lying face down in a very, very noisy tunnel.  There was supposed to be music to take the edge off, but I couldn’t hear it for the horrid buzzing.  I don’t know how long I was in there, but it seemed forever.  I felt faint and dizzy when I came out so they gave me coffee and biscuits to give me a boost before they let me go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came home, had lunch and a quick nap, and then it was off to my Asthma review and to get my flu jab.  The idea is to have me on top form healthwise with everything else for when the big things start kicking in.  That all done, it was back home, and into bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave Ross to update on the washing machine.  I’m too tired.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/more-scans&quot;&gt;More Scans&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 07, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A bucket full of washing]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-bucket-full-of-washing" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-bucket-full-of-washing</id>
  <published>2013-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m quite knackered at the moment, so in the morning I watched a video about
a new way to abstract code in Scala, fascinating stuff for me but probably not for you.
I also did the walk of shame and finally went to the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the gym they punish you for absence by deactivating your gym machine key
and then making you explain yourself to the personal trainer.  Promises of better
attendance did the trick and I chucked some weights about for forty minutes.
The knee I knackered doing the One True Grit challenge is considerably weaker
than its counterpart and could only manage 7kg leg extensions, compared to
22.5kg - so some work to do there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon it was more coding and video hangout meetings with colleagues.
At 5:30pm Julia comes into the study (mid meeting) to tell me the washing machine
isn’t coming. The washing has been steadily breeding and what was a small pile
is now a mountain.  She’s not happy, I’m not happy and seemingly John Lewis isn’t
happy but as the depot centre is having technical problems they can’t reschedule
at the moment. We chose John Lewis because we didn’t want to be dicked about -
we could have gone to Currys for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s another scan day, so we drive back to Spire Harpenden for 9:30am.  We arrive early, so
Julia suggests we chill in the car for a bit. I call John Lewis to ask about
the whereabouts of the washing machine. I make
it clear I’m not happy and they go away and find out what’s what.  Then they can’t
speak to me about the new delivery date as Julia ordered it - data protection
and all that. They tell Julia the next they can deliver is in 8 days time, Julia
responds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Thats just not good enough, I have breast cancer, a 5 year old son who is
so worried he has started wetting the bed and &lt;strong&gt;no washing machine&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s had enough of them and tells them to speak to me as she has to go into the
hospital for her scan. It’s a bit of a bombshell to drop on the customer service
lady and she promises to do her best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They call back telling me that 8 days time is the quickest they can deliver. I
flip and even offer to pick up a machine from a local store:
&lt;strong&gt;I just need an f’ing washing machine&lt;/strong&gt;. She says she’ll callback.
Well this is getting us nowhere fast - time to publicly shame them and use twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appalled by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johnlewisretail&quot;&gt;@johnlewisretail&lt;/a&gt; now without a washing machine. wife has cancer, son wetting bed with worry and the best new delivery is 8 days&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ross Lawley (@RossC0) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RossC0/statuses/398385647305887744&quot;&gt;November 7, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask my colleagues to retweet and I get a response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RossC0&quot;&gt;@RossC0&lt;/a&gt; Extremely concerned to read your tweet. Please: email_us@johnlewis.co.uk with your details and I will assist. Thank you, Aimee.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; John Lewis (@JLcustserv) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JLcustserv/statuses/398387106839408640&quot;&gt;November 7, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a call from the customer service lady saying there is no stock locally, so
they can’t deliver the washing machine and tumble dryer until the 15th November
and that she is very sorry but theres nothing else she can do.
I’m so pissed off I can’t agree to that, so I emailed Aimee and she promised to
sort it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few calls and emails later and the
washing machine and tumble dryer will be delivered and installed at 10am tomorrow
morning. &lt;strong&gt;Result!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the f*ck I had to call them to find out how they were
going to sort it and why someone inside John Lewis cancelled
yesterdays delivery for no reason and why I had to resort to naming and shaming
them in publicly, I don’t know.  But I do know that twitter is &lt;strong&gt;the
best way&lt;/strong&gt; to get action from complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aimee is even sending Felix a parcel as good will gesture and once its installed
they’ll look to compensate Julia for the stress caused. So lets hope it all
arrives nicely tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time for a beer, cheers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-bucket-full-of-washing&quot;&gt;A bucket full of washing&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 07, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spires and Surgery]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/spires-and-surgery" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/spires-and-surgery</id>
  <published>2013-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s Monday and I’m back at work for the first time since finding out. I have
questions about this: would I be able to do &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; work? Has my concentration
gone? I needn’t have worried as I’m one of those lucky souls who loves his job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start with the usual Monday morning meeting, which for me is a video hangout with the
rest of the EMEA drivers team.  We’re a diverse bunch, based across Europe
and its good to catch up and get some normality back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was going to be sitting in a hospital for a long time, I needed some offline
work to get on with.  Happily, it was the start of a
new programming course I’d signed up for on &lt;a href=&quot;http://coursera.org/&quot;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; (
if you haven’t checked out Coursera do – there’s awesome free online courses on all
manner of subjects).  So I downloaded this weeks lectures and assignments to keep me
busy at the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drive is nice, although annoyingly there’s a love of speed bumps on hills near
Harpenden.  The Spire hospital is really nice, staff friendly
and as in common with all hospitals time moves at a different pace. We arrive
on time for 12pm but Julia’s surgery didn’t take place until after 3pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I manage to grab some crisps and chocolate for lunch, Julia is annoyed
because she is nil by mouth.  She gets her own back later by having dinner post
op, something I missed out on. In fact she practically rubs my nose in it by
making me see it twice - bleurgh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia’s operation goes well but she comes out looking green gilled. So much so
one doctor practically panics when he sees her and has to be “shooed” out the room by
a nurse.  A quick red cell count and blood pressure check determines her fit,
although nauseous from the anesthetic and operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes some time to persuade them to discharge her, they would have
preferred her to stay in but there’s no place like home and as the anesthetist joked
you can just as easily feel nauseous there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clair was great looking after the kids - thank you and we finally made it
home for 10pm.  Julia celebrates by being sick again and I get her to bed.
She has nothing to worry about tomorrow and can stay in bed resting all day.
All of which doesn’t explain why she woke me up at 4:30am by trying to read her iPad
under the covers! I may have swore but this is how things are now,
suddenly you go from fast asleep to wide awake for no apparent reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed they don’t find anything - we’ll find out next Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/spires-and-surgery&quot;&gt;Spires and Surgery&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 05, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fireworks]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fireworks" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fireworks</id>
  <published>2013-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I had my Sentinel Node Biopsy.  It was to check whether the cancer has spread to my lymph nodes.  Scans suggest that it hasn’t, but they needed to do this to be sure.   The operation involved having a dye injected and then any lymph nodes dyed blue removed through an insertion into my armpit.  All done under general anaesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yesterday morning, the bairns went back to school after their half term break,  whilst I got things ready here.  I made a quick dash for new pj’s, dressing gown and slippers, drop the house key off to Clairs, and then we were off to the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This operation was done  using Ross’s health insurance, so we had to go to Harpenden, a bit of a trek, but we had private room.  This meant Ross was able to crack on and get some work done.  Odd, you might think, but it’s his way of keeping busy, and relaxed.  And he was right beside me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After waiting a couple of hours, I was whisked off to theatre, wearing full length surgical stockings, hospital knickers and gown.  I looked a treat!  Two hours later I was coming round in recovery with a lot of pain in my arm pit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m eventually wheeled back round to my room, where Ross is waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to do three things before they will let me leave.  Drink, eat, and wee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First one was fine.  Drink.  Done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I was presented with soup, a sarnie, ice cream and juice.  Unfortunately I was feeling very woosey, clammy and a bit sick.  So, I dozed.  The soup went cold, the ice cream melted.  The nurse came in and I asked for something to help me stop feeling sick.  She agreed, although a doctor came in and was a bit shocked at my pallor.  Apparently it was akin to corpse or vampire.  He wanted to do blood tests, but the nurse ushered him out and said she’d do it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were starting to mention keeping me in over night.  Time was marching on but I didn’t want that to happen.  I wanted to be back in my own bed with my family there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sickness drug worked, I ate the sarnie, and I was gearing up for a wee.  This had to be supervised by a nurse as I was still hooked up to a drip and they needed to check I was ok getting up after the anaesthetic.  So, buzzer pressed for wee supervision, I feel sick again.  And throw up all the painkillers, sarnie, water etc, I’d been so desperately trying to keep down.  On a side point, the blue dye they had used earlier had turned my sick a greeny, blue colour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurse comes in again, and suggests strongly I stay in over night.  I’m determined not to, so oblige with a (blue) wee, and after taking my blood count (12.1), she relents and signs the papers to let me go.  Yay!  A quick trip in a wheelchair to the car and we are homeward bound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clair had brought the bairns home, done homework with them, played disney infinity and then put them to bed.  This was a relief to Ross and I to know they were safe and well cared for, and am very thankful to her.  I snuck in to give my babies kisses whilst they sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sick again before I went to bed, but at least I was in my own bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen and Felix gave me hugs this morning and I showed them what I’d had one and why we needed to be careful with my left arm.  Imogen gave me a card she’d made with her head teacher, Mrs Summerhayes.  Apparently, Imogen had been feeling a bit anxious around lunchtime when she knew I’d be off to the hospital and had asked her teacher for time out with Mrs Summerhayes.  It’s nice to know the school are being understanding and empathetic to her.  She needs it, she’s a delicate flower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m staying in bed today.  I’ll get up for nourishment, but I’m still feeling sick and in pain.  I must make sure I do my arm exercises to make sure the wound doesn’t heal and scar tight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a long line of operations and treatments, but it’s done.  One down, plenty more to go.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/fireworks&quot;&gt;Fireworks&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 05, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trick or Treat]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/trick-or-treat" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/trick-or-treat</id>
  <published>2013-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the
alarm goes off at 5.10 I have no idea where I am or who I am - but its time to
load the car. Once we’re nearly ready I wake Imogen, who jumps out of bed saying
“Finally, I’ve been waiting all night!” - Felix was less pleased to be woken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We flew up the A1 only hindered by Lorries playing the overtaking game. The one
where they swing out into the fast lane and then try to overtake the Lorry in
front as slowly as possible. We get to the grandparents, help set up a Halloween
party and I have a beer.  Grandma Julie has been looking forward to Halloween
and made it really special for the kids - thank you Grandma!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family come round for the party. I’ve noticed Julia is taking on a role
of being strong when friends / family cry.  This warms me as it is a sign of Julia’s
inner strength and character that I’m so in love with.  There’s lots of
“I’m not dead you know”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uncle Callums pumpkins are amazing, people even had their photo taken with them
when trick or treating us.  Imogen &amp;amp; Felix &lt;strong&gt;loved&lt;/strong&gt; trick or treating. After a nervous start Felix
really got into it, I think he would have happily knocked on every door in
Cullercoats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning Grandma Julie, the kids and I walked Uncle Regans and Grandma
Lindas dogs - that sounds way more complicated that it was. Apart from missing
a massive sign saying park closed - we enjoyed the walk in the park, funnily enough
it was nice and quiet. Julia stayed home and slept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we head to see Grandma Ursula. When talking in the car, we tell
Imogen to help with the “I’m not dead” line and she practices. Felix reacts to it, he
was in a mood anyhow but grunts when she says it. Its becoming obvious that he will
need some help to communicate his feelings - he’s very young and it is impacting
him more than we initially thought. We’ll have to work on being extra understanding
with Felix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia sleeps a lot today, the fatigue worries me but its also a way for her to
charge batteries and prepare for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we have an epic roast and beers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;saturday&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off into town to see Newcastle play Chelsea! Granddad Mikie and myself get to go
to the match whilst the other (better?) halves and kids go shopping.  We got the
best deal!  Before the match we all head into Krispy Kremes for doughnuts and coffee.
Group wide chronic indecision about what people want to order hits, its too painful
I had to escape and take Felix to the loo.  There is such a thing as too
much choice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The match was awesome, the first half pretty dull and the crowd was nervous.  But
it the second half Newcastle were attacking the Gallowgate End and the crowd lifted
the team and practically willed the ball into the back of the next. I jumped and
cheered like a loon when the first goal went in.  We went expecting defeat and
came out winners - a brilliant way to spend an afternoon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the match we swung by Regan &amp;amp; Lornas new house, not sure I could have
taken on such a massive project but they’ll get a home exactly as they want it.
The house has been gutted and there’s still a mountain of work to do but from now
on it’ll come together and its going to look fantastic once done.  Looking forward
to seeing it done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sunday&quot;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pop by Julia’s brothers before heading home.  The drive is long and moods
are low when we get home.  Imogen and Felix got bored in the car and fought
over the no mans land of the middle seat.  No one helps get anything in from
the car and I get grumpy. That evening Felix is extremely rude again to
mummy. I’m really not happy with about it and react.  Once
tempers have cooled and we’ve discussed the whys and how we should have dwelt
with it, we hug and Felix and I become friends again. I think the nerves about
tomorrows operation and cancer in general are leaking out and we must come
closer as a family to get through it and remember &lt;strong&gt;we are a team&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/trick-or-treat&quot;&gt;Trick or Treat&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 03, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halloween Weekend]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/halloween-weekend" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/halloween-weekend</id>
  <published>2013-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross got us up at 5am this morning for the drive up to Newcastle.  Felix, Imogen and I slept for the first hour or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get to Grandma’s and Ross and the bairns are soon being organised with Halloween preparations.  I have a sleep on the sofa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We go and visit my Gran in the afternoon and then it’s back to Grandma’s and Grandad’s for a party with the family.  There were hugs, laughs, thoughtful presents and trick or treating.  The bairns loved it.  I got hugs.  That was nice.  It’s odd talking about my boobs with my brothers and my Dad, but this is important.  They need to know what’s going to happen to me and how I’m feeling about it all.  The fact of the matter is, I have to do what it takes to get my life back.  There is no pussy footing about this.  It’s going to be a hard road, I realise that, but it won’t be forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen reads Grandma and Grandad the Mummy’s Lump book.  She’s already read it to her cousin Holly, and the only word she struggled with was Chemotherapy.  Why should a seven or eight year old know that word?  It’s hardly everyday vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uncle Callum’s highly regarded pumpkin is being used as a nightlight tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept a lot today.  It’s nice to be able to, and know the bairns and Ross are looked after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to see my Mam this afternoon.  It’s been a while since we saw her but Imogen and Felix were great.  Something’s also don’t change.  She was telling me how I feel about having Breast Cancer.  I’m shocked.  Clearly I can’t choose my own emotions and feelings at 36years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought some headwear for when I lose my hair with the chemo.  I got some online, and others from an actual real life shop.  It’s still all a bit surreal.  Also discussing health insurance whilst waiting to have the kids feet measured was a bit odd.  Things are just going to get more odd, so I may as well get used to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;saturday&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today has been quite hectic.  Ross accompanied my Dad to see Newcastle play Chelsea at St James Park, and Imogen, Felix, grandma Julie and I did some shopping.  A successful afternoon all round with the Toon winning 2 nil, and purchasing Imogen’s new school boots, and Christmas outfits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way home we saw Regan and Lorna’s new house.  They astound me.  They’ve got two 7 month old babies, and are gutting a house.  It’ll be fantastic, I’ve no doubt, but Wowsers, there’s work to do.  I’m looking forward to seeing it all done up.  Something else to aim for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made an impromptu visit to see Karen and Alison, two of my oldest friends.  I’m glad I did.  There were hugs and tears, but also promises of support and laughter.  There’s a reason I have the friends I do, both the old ones and the (relatively) newer ones.  Mainly because they are fantastic, and I can be me. I don’t have to pretend to be someone I’m not, and they accept me as I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re off home tomorrow. It’s been a good trip. But I’m not sure when I’ll be up next.  That worries me a bit, as we normally come up every 3 or 4 months, but as we just don’t quite know what’s going to happen, we can’t make plans.  It’s been a great few days.  My family are fantastic and it’s good to know I’ve got their support.  My Dad and Julie, are amazing.  They have so much on their own plate with one thing and another, and still make it seem like nothing is too much trouble.  Much love to them.  Don’t go changing. X&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past week, I’ve even told I’m very brave, pragmatic, stoic and tenacious in my attitude and reaction to my diagnosis.  But what can I do?  I have no other choice.  I have to fight.  I have to fight for my future, because in fighting for my future I’m fighting for the future of my kids and my family, and that’s what’s important.  They need me, and I need them so I’ve got something to fight for.   I have no choice.  There is no other option.  &lt;strong&gt;I HAVE NO CHOICE BUT TO FIGHT!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sunday&quot;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We called in to see my brothers and their families before we headed home.  Ross did a sterling job of driving and 4 hours later we were walking in the front door to be greeted by the cats.  They were very happy to see us, and us them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all be a bit shouty at each other this afternoon.  I think it’s the stress of tomorrow leaching out.  We all need to remember to be kind to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/halloween-weekend&quot;&gt;Halloween Weekend&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 03, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good News]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/good-news" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/good-news</id>
  <published>2013-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was trying to tie up some loose ends today with work as I was expecting a phone call with final confirmation from the consultant that Monday’s operation is definitely happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to an extent, but it did mean I left work late, hit traffic, and I’m now very tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the consultant rang he told me the best news.  The CT scan came back clear.  The Cancer is localised and there’s no more in my body between my neck and the top of my legs.  The operation on Monday will establish whether there’s any Cancer in the lymph nodes and I am keeping everything crossed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consultant has been thinking about the best treatment plan for me and for the first time mentioned radiotherapy.  The problem is, if I have to have that, I’ll not be able to have the mastectomy and reconstruction at the same time.  It could be up to a year between the two.  I think he was trying to gauge my reaction to this proposed course of action.  To be honest, if that does happen, it’s not going to be the worst thing in the world that I’d have to face.  I have priorities.  These are watching Imogen and Felix grow up, and getting to an age ripe old age with Ross so we can sit and hold hands and look out to sea when we’ve both got grey hair (well, me with grey hair, Ross will still be bald).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been getting lots of lovely messages from people who I haven’t spoken to for ages.  These are very much appreciated.  I do try and respond to eveyone because I appreciate that people have taken the time to comment/message etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got home, dinner was on the table and the laundry had been done.  My husband is amazing, and I love him very much.  I’m very lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off to visit my family up North tomorrow.  I’m going to get lots of hugs and every single one of them will be well received and I’m looking forward to them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/good-news&quot;&gt;Good News&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 30, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Long Night]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-long-night" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-long-night</id>
  <published>2013-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The CT Scan yesterday and the operation being moved to Monday has taken its toll.  This is now
real and Julia is scared.  What happens if the CT Scan shows something up?  Her
shoulder has been sore and it’s hard not to correlate the two things. I tell her
we have to take things one day at a time, one step at a time and I’m with her
all the way.  We don’t sleep well, I dose and when I awake, I rub her back
- it will be ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen decides 6:40am is a good time to wake up and comes into the bedroom, telling
me she forgot to set her alarm.  She’s worried she’s slept in! I’m not too kind as
I tell her to get BACK to her room.  It’s ok though, she gets her own back by deciding
now’s a good time to do recorder practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The replacement tv cabinet arrives early, we get it set up and the kids scramble
about helping me hoover up the polystyrene bits so we can send a pic to mummy. It
looks great.  Then it’s time for Felix to get his hair cut, the last time we went
to the new barbers I practically had to push him in there when he saw the barber
was a lady.  He’s over it and practically jumps into the seat - he knows there’s
a lollypop coming post hair cut.  I get my hair cut as well, a grade zero which
also saw a cut throat razor. It’s hard not to gulp when one of those comes out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia has had her CT Scan results all clear! F*ck yeah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old owners had a crate of wine delivered by accident - decisions, decisions…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon involves laundry, Jesus ironing sucks.  Roll on the tumble dryer,
as no t-shirt will need ironing again.  Our neighbour kindly takes the kids out
for a walk and I steam some creases. Rock and Roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now cooking tea, drinking wine and looking forward to seeing the inlaws in Toon
tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-long-night&quot;&gt;A Long Night&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 30, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jokes & Scans]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/jokes-scans" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/jokes-scans</id>
  <published>2013-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Trying to avoid the public displays of affection from the two youngsters sat opposite me in a very small waiting room, and a drip which  made me feel hot, which was just as well as the room’s air con seemed to be set to cold gale.  Not pleasant when you’re wearing a hospital gown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a joke with the radiographers which lightened the mood somewhat.  I seem to have a habit of trying to lighten things up.  Is it my job to do that?  Probably not, but if I don’t then who will?  Do people think I’m going to cry or talk about cancer all the time?  I don’t know, but I haven’t changed my personality.   I can still be a cow, granted, but that’s normal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a long conversation with the health insurance company, which resulted in a conversation with my Consultant, and the first operation potentially being brought forward to Monday.  This Monday.  After the weekend Monday.  6 days time Monday.  (When I was supposed to be getting the new washing machine delivered.  That’s now been changed.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scares me.  It means that I really am on this journey.  It’s not a dream, and it is happening to me.  Sometimes it feels like this is all happening to someone else.     Having an operation means it is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m having a glass of wine.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/jokes-scans&quot;&gt;Jokes & Scans&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 29, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to the Hospital]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-the-hospital" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-the-hospital</id>
  <published>2013-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stuff is moving, progress is happening and this makes me feel positive.  Sleeping
well also makes me feel positive.  We drop the kids off at friends (thanks Lesley!) and
dash down the A1 to the QE2.  The hospital has the worst frontage of any I’ve
ever seen, to be fair I’m not that experienced. Today the sun is out and it looks
less depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia is made to suffer some form of water torture; drink a litre of
special stuff to help the scan out and isn’t allowed to go to the loo.
She cracks on and drinks away. I watch iplayer on the ipad whilst waiting -
downloads for the win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get nervous when Julia grabs me and we have to wait in another room - but she
was just saving me from the smallest waiting room and wanting company.  Once she’s
given the all clear to the dye injection we head off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia wasn’t as pleased as I was about the insurance.  She worried we’ll have
to schlep miles to the private hospital for chemo, so we decide to find out what’s
what.  It’s good news we can dip in and out the NHS, this feels wierd but I suppose
it saves them money so its mutally beneficial.  Her first operation can now be done
next week - its scarily close but we’ll know what we are facing sooner and start
taking steps to getting Julia healthy quicker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m feeling positive and having wine too!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-the-hospital&quot;&gt;Back to the Hospital&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 29, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monday funday]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/monday-funday" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/monday-funday</id>
  <published>2013-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s half term, so the kids are up bright and early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got the kids today and as Julia heads off to work, I
get the kids up for breakfast and a then a healthy dose of Disney Infinity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head out for a walk to see what damage the storms have done, not too much in
Baldock it seems. We wear wellies and jump in all the puddles :)  Then it rains
and we run back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix who hasn’t talked much about what’s going on asks “How old will you be
when you die?”. Not sure if its just a standard five year olds question or if
he’s worrying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the arvo we do some homework. Imogen does recorder practice and I read with
Felix.  Imogen had started getting annoyed and shouting at the recorder, so
I have a go on the recorder and turn the tables by getting Imogen to teach me.
In no time she she aces the tune!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head into the garden I do some pruning, this involves getting the electric saw out and
removing a straggly bush altogether.  This gardening lark is easy. I then WD40
the squeaky doors upstairs and fix Imogens curtain rail.  This diy lark is easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix offers me his piggy bank to pay for the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a call from the health insurance folk and our claim has been authorised - great
news, Julia can have the best care now and be seen quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really pleased and quite tired after just a day of looking after the bairns!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/monday-funday&quot;&gt;Monday funday&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 28, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to work]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-work" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-work</id>
  <published>2013-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You don’t normally get hugs off you colleagues, but today I did.  It was nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tired now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-work&quot;&gt;Back to work&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 28, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sunday runday]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sunday-run-day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sunday-run-day</id>
  <published>2013-10-27T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was good to catch up and as it was just us, we went at my pace - most would hardly
call it a run!!  We plodded round Ivel springs and up to Radwell meadows, good
stuff and I’m determined to get fit - to both keep sane by working out
frustrations and to build the strength and stamina I will need in the coming
months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After breaky, it’s over to the swimming pool for the kids lessons. I was pleased
there were less people in the swimming lane and I could charge up and down the
pool.  Felix swam his first ever length of backstroke, I was egging him on from
the otherside of the lane rope (I don’t think he noticed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the day, I walk into a room and Julia says “I could die” and bursts into
tears, I hug her tight and cry. It’s not been said so far and it needed airing
as hard and hopefully unlikely it is. We talk and try and try to regain a proper
perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a great tea (go Lidl ingredients!) I call my dad. It is his birthday and I
had forgotten. I apologise profusely and I’m angry at myself, I could have
sworn it was not until the 29th.  I’m rubbish.  The kids sing happy birthday
and I hope that made up for it in some part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it hard to sleep and feel very low, probably despair or some other
dark mood - I’m not use to those feelings and they seem so alien to me and my
personality. I’m ill equiped to cope but a quick sob and hugs from Julia sort me
right out.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sunday-run-day&quot;&gt;Sunday runday&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 27, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's the weekend!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-the-weekend" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-the-weekend</id>
  <published>2013-10-27T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve ordered a new washing machine and tumble dryer.  My existing washer is 9 years old and sounds like its going to take off when it spins.  That’s not going to be very conducive to a relaxing recovery.  The tumble dryer will just make life easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also spoken to my wonderful hairdresser.  I’ve decided that there’s no point having my hair coloured if its going to fall out and cancelled my appointments scheduled between now and Christmas. Instead I’ve made one for a couple of weeks time to have it cut short.  My reasoning is that when it falls out it doesn’t come as such big change.  It’ll also take less time to maintain and that’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to a local fireworks display on Saturday night with our friends.  There was beer and company.  Good for us all.  The fireworks were fantastic and we all had a great time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clocks went back an hour this morning and thanks to a later than normal night, the bairns got up at a reasonable time.  I stayed in bed as long as I could.  I seem to be using sleep as a coping mechanism.  If I’m asleep I can’t think about things, and there’s some things I don’t want to think about.   Unfortunately, I’m sleepwalking.  I’ve got form.  I do it in times of stress.  Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched my little fish at their swimming lessons.  Felix has come on so well in the last few weeks.  He can now swim a whole 25m length on his own.  And Imogen is amazing.  I just wish she’d listen to the teacher so she can improve her technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then this afternoon, I slept on the sofa whilst family life continued around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross is being fantastic.  He’s picking up the slack already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to work tomorrow.  During the Storm of St Jude, patron saint of lost causes.  The two are not connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-the-weekend&quot;&gt;It's the weekend!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 27, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surprises & Fireworks]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/suprises-and-fireworks" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/suprises-and-fireworks</id>
  <published>2013-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I go downstairs and kitten therapy works wonders! Merlin is a needy little thing in the morning, he keeps stopping me writing this on the ipad - some things are simply more important, it seems! I re read Julia’s post from yesterday it’s great, I’m so proud of my wonderful wife and I know that this blog will give us strength in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s little ruggers day for Felix, I take Imogen along so Julia can rest up - she’s got batteries to charge. I feel bad but I ignore the other parents that I usually speak to, I can’t face the usual chit chat today. I left the ipad at home so Imogen and I sit and read the paper in the school canteen whilst Felix plays rugby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, I’m ambushed by a sad story about a photographer documenting his wife’s journey with breast cancer. Tears fill my eyes, it’s the last thing I was expecting, someone has documented my worse fear. I have to remind myself all cancers are different, Julia is strong and we are getting the best care possible. Imogen doesn’t see it and I quickly turn the page and the conversation brightens. It seems cancer is everywhere at the moment, tv campaigns, movember, in the papers. I’m hypersensitive now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix enjoyed little ruggers and we head home via the supermarket. I start to reply to the kind messages from work mates, I tell Imogen to get ready for dance class and off she goes. Suddenly I notice the time, I shout Imogen, she comes downstairs in her normal clothes! This makes me laugh, she has been faffing again! A quick change on the stairs and we just make it to the class on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, Imogen and I clean out the smelly gerbils and do some planting in the garden. I cook enchiladas for dinner, Julia and I love them, Imogen is ambivalent, Felix decides with his eyes we are trying poison him. Lots of threats about not going to the fireworks gets him to eat it. Julia talked about having to save money and eat healthy to the kids this morning. They both agreed but being presented enchiladas on the same day is simply too much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s firework night at the school, there’s someone killing the guitar and doing tenacious d covers when we arrive, I grab the beer and we chat to friends. The kids go on some tumble dryer style ride - I’m terrified for them. Felix looked panicky at the start and they are being rolled into big kids, I expect tears but they both come off beaming “Awesome!” Imogen lost her hat in the excitement and has to fight through the queue to get it back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More beers and friends arrive. It’s so great to see them, Julia and I notice the differences in how friends (the dads) handle the situation, that’s ok it’s big bad news. We quickly break the ice and the conversation soon starts flowing. It all feels wonderfully normal, the kids all sit to watch the fireworks together “oooing”, “arrhhhing” and sometimes screaming together. The display was great and we head home tired and happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was a good day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R x&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/suprises-and-fireworks&quot;&gt;Surprises & Fireworks&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 26, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Normality creeps in]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/normality-creeps-in" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/normality-creeps-in</id>
  <published>2013-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s been a hint of normality today.  I enjoyed it.  But I have a feeling there’s going to be far fewer days like it.  There was also some not so normal bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had lots of hugs from friends on the school run.  There was a few tears, but I reminded them that “I’m not dead!”  I also said I would be requesting hugs often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Pilates and told my teacher that today would be my last class for a while.  I’ve been really enjoying them so may go back for the odd session as and when I feel up to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was the dentist.  See?  Normal things!  This is what normal people do!  As I was walking round town, I felt like running up to random strangers going about their normal business and saying “Don’t you know?  Can’t you see?  I’ve got Breast Cancer.”  Mentalist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was lunch at the Orange Tree.  Again.  Normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A call from the hospital was next to arrange a CT scan.  Not your everyday occurrence.  That’s now booked for next Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was a 15 minute call with my GP.  Who called me.  That’s not really normal is it?  It’s generally quite hard to get in touch with a GP.  And she’s told me she’s going to get one of the asthma nurses to give me a call as she wants me to get me to have a flu jab before my first operation, and ensure my asthma is ok and the rest of me is on top form before they start taking me apart to put me back together.  I tried to make an appointment at the beginning of October.  But the soonest they could give me was 7th November.  Magically, that’s going to be brought forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read something, or was told something somewhere but I can’t remember where or who.  Its regarding treating cancer and it didn’t seem relevant at the time.  It was “it takes a year of your life to get your life back”.  I’m 36 years old.  I’ve got a small family who need me, so I keep telling them, so if it takes a year to do this, I’ll do it.  I’ll take it head on and fight all the way.  The alternative is just too horrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a few statistics for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 in 8 women will be diagnosed with cancer in their life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 in 10 of these women will be under 50.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 2010, 136 women were told they had breast cancer on any given day.
(135 women are now going through the same thing as me 48 hours after being told the devastating news.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cancer, do one.  You’re not claiming me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/normality-creeps-in&quot;&gt;Normality creeps in&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 25, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Julia's Challenge]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/julias-challenge" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/julias-challenge</id>
  <published>2013-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I hugged Julia tight and my sobs woke her. Not the nicest way to start the day
for her and I feel guilty for doing it. It’s as if my emotions have betrayed me
somehow. We talk and I feel better - it seems crying really works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems we forgot to set Felix’s alarm last night, Julia set me a challenge to
set Felix’s alarm on without waking him. (I still haven’t got round to WD40’ing
the door hinges upstairs, they’re straight out of a noir horror film - almost
comically so). I creep in set it and retreat. Julia tells me the “on” setting
is up. Bugger, I’d just turned it off. I creep in again, set the alarm and Felix
rolls over, snores loudly (atta boy) and then wakes… oops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kids wake, we get hugs from the kids and get them to school. I’m
apprehensive, as ours friends know but we’ve yet to see them. It’s as if
seeing them makes it more real. Stupid really, seeing them give Julia hugs
and talking about it is &lt;strong&gt;enormously&lt;/strong&gt; reassuring. There were tears and disbelief
but I see it brightens Julia - we are lucky to have such great friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia has messages to do this morning, so I’m back home having a coffee and on
the laptop. I buy our old domain back and hunt for a blog engine, Jekyll wins as
it’s easiest and has themes.  We get the blog up and I grab Julia’s diary
entries and throw it on the web (o hai!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tell work and friends on twitter, the support messages are great.  Cancer
isn’t a rarity, many stories of how it touched peoples lives have come out and
in a strange way it’s good to hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’ll have a beer tonight and look forward to the firework display tomorrow.
Next week it’s half term and time to chill with the kids and see family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R x&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/julias-challenge&quot;&gt;Julia's Challenge&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 25, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The next day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-next-day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-next-day</id>
  <published>2013-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today has passed in a bit of a blur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 4am, and got up an hour later to send some work emails and put something live.  Funny what you think is important…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d inadvertently woken Ross up so we chatted eventually falling asleep not long before the children woke up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got them into bed with us, and read them a book called Mummy’s Lump.  It was a very high level book which discussed a bad lump, cutting it out, and strong medicine which would make my hair fall out.  They asked some questions, felt Big Lump, and what the operation would mean.  We told them my boob would be cut off.  Imogen was a bit upset, but Felix didn’t really understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this made us a bit late for school. Not by much but Felix wasn’t impressed.  We went to see Mrs Summerhayes as she would be able to ensure that things were put in place to ensure Imogen and Felix were given additional support as and when required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day has involved a trip to the doctors to get things signed, a trip to the supermarket, a walk round Radwell Meadows, an awkward conversation with my mother, ( who’s immediate reaction was to light a cigarette),  a light lunch, and a nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also told the Gin Club.  As expected the offers of help were overwhelming and also humbling.  They are a great group of friends, and were lucky to have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some beautiful flowers arrive from Dad and Julie with a card saying they were thinking if us. A conversation with my Dad followed, which was less emotionally fraught than yesterday’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross is flying solo at parents evening.  I can’t face it to be honest.  First parents evening I’ve missed.  But it needs to be focused on the kids.  I’m too much of a zombie and too leaky to make myself anything other than a nuisance right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross has been great and continues to be my rock, and to help me use our sense of humour to get us through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-next-day&quot;&gt;The next day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 24, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>