<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2014-07-15T12:26:50+01:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Race for Life]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/race-for-life" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/race-for-life</id>
  <published>2014-07-15T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-07-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">After months of planning, Sunday finally came around and it was Race Day!&lt;p&gt;Sixteen ladies and twelve children ran or walked the 5km course round Stevenage Fairlands Valley Park as part of The Gin Club Team. When I was diagnosed in October last year, it was one of the first things I asked the Breast Care Nurse.  She wasn’t very committal, and said it depend where I was in my treatment.  If I’d have had the planned FEC chemo in May/June, there was very little chance that I would have been able to participate, or if I did it was may have been in a wheelchair.  As it happened the Paclitaxel chemotherapy and the biological treatment Herceptin worked so well that there was no need for the extra chemo, and I was delighted to be able to take part.  This year it was personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GinClubRaceforLife2014.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post Race picture&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I wouldn’t be able to run it, my energy levels are still massively diminished, but Imogen and Felix were keen to do so.  Luckily, Catherine agreed to Felix running with her and James, and Michelle had Imogen running with her and Katy.  They both did so well and I am so proud of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were walking around, we decided that we’d all do it again next year, and more of us would run. We also may get customised t-shirts!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The support was fantastic, not least my Dad, the Gin Club Dad’s and Matthew, Sarah, Eddie and Betty who had travelled up from Kent to cheer us on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day was very emotional, especially when all the runners waited near the finish line so that they could all cross it with me.  I cried.  A lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn’t have been luckier with the weather either, and it only started raining once we’d all finished and were heading back to the cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/LawleyRFL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lawley&#39;s&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Post Race celebrations took place at The Orange Tree in Baldock.  A BBQ was organised and thanks to Landlord Rob, we raised another £200, bringing our total amount to £2,355.00.  An amazing amount of money for Cancer Research to do something truly magnificent, (I think there’s more to come too!).  I am proud and humbled to know that my friends did this for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment train still continues and today I am off to get another dose of Herceptin.  Ross will be with me, keeping me company, as is the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all who have donated and supported us throughout this whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/race-for-life&quot;&gt;Race for Life&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on July 15, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rads and Camping]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/end-of-rads" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/end-of-rads</id>
  <published>2014-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Last Friday I completed 15 daily sessions of Radiotherapy, and then went camping for the weekend.&lt;p&gt;The actual treatment itself wasn’t too bad, especially once I got on top of the whole breath holding technique.  The tediousness came from having to tip off down to Elstree everyday.  A boring journey in the back of a taxi.  I did see quite a lot of Red Kites, buzzards and kestrals though, which helped pass the time somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The side effects will continue for another 2 weeks when they peak, and then I should start to get some energy back.  It’s nowhere near as draining as chemo but still leaves me quite tired and unable to do as much as I want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so glad that it’s over now, I feel like it’s the end of another leg in this epic cancer journey we are on.  In December/January, I’ll finish the 18 Herceptin treatments that I have every 3 weeks, and that’ll be the end of active treatment. That’s over a year after diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being absolutely shattered after Friday’s treatment, I decided I was well enough to go camping.  I didn’t have to do much, Ross put the tent up with a bit of anti-help from the kids, and I entertained Joni, Greg and Rachel’s gorgeous smiley baby.  I then stayed around the camp and enjoyed some really good Gin Club company.  There’s a few changes that have to be made though, for next time.  I’ve realised I can’t sleep on our lovely space saving camping mattress.  I’m going to have to revert to the old faithful airbed.  I’m also going to have to have a proper pillow.  The scars and the swelling from the surgery make it just too uncomfortable so I need some extra padding.  But the next camping trip can’t come soon enough.  I really enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, Felix has lost his first two teeth!  We also got to test the Tooth Fairy, and she does indeed visit campsites.  My boy is growing up so fast.  I’ve just realised that I haven’t mentioned on the blog that he turned 6 at the end of May.  He had a fabulous birthday and really enjoyed having some friends come round and basically run riot for 2 hours.  Five boys were collected by their parents sweaty and happy…Good times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen has got her birthday next week.  She is looking forward to going bowling with her friends followed by a McDonalds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross and I have got some new bikes so we can go out with the bairns when they are on theirs.  We’ve realised that Imogen needs a new bike so Felix can have hers.  Felix really needs a bike with gears.  They are enjoying having some days where they cycle to and from school and as a side plus point, it’s improving my stamina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so it continues…keeping on, keeping on.  Trying to keep things normal as best we can and I think we are doing ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/end-of-rads&quot;&gt;Rads and Camping&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 25, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reasons I'm Lucky]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Reasons-to-be-lucky" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Reasons-to-be-lucky</id>
  <published>2014-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I worry that this blog must be a bit dull when I&#39;m just writing about what I&#39;ve been up to.&lt;p&gt;So I thought I’d write one from a different angle about why I’m lucky.  I know that sounds a bit daft, I mean, getting cancer at 36 is hardly fortuitous, but I have so many reasons to be thankful.  And here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;type-of-cancer&quot;&gt;Type of Cancer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently there was an advertising campaign run by Pancreatic Cancer Action which introduced us to people who had been diagnosed with Pancreatic Cancer and their wish that they had been diagnosed with another type of cancer.  The campaign was slated in the papers with outcries that you can’t pitch one type of cancer against another.  It was a bitter pill to swallow, but I can understand why these people feel like this.  Pancreatic Cancer has a 3% survival rate to 5 years&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  For Breast Cancer it’s over 80%, and that’s increased from 50% 40 years ago&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  Those figures speak for themselves so, yes, I’m lucky that I was diagnosed with Breast Cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stage-of-cancer&quot;&gt;Stage of Cancer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 5 Stages of Breast Cancer.  I’ve simplified it a bit, as I’m not 100% on it all, but it’s a summary of information from Cancer Research website&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tis - which is a very early stage of Cancer which is contained within the ducts of the breast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;T1 - The lumps (tumours) are less than 2cm across.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;T2 - More than 2cm but less than 5cm across.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;T3 - Bigger than 5cm across.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;T4 - The Cancer has spread from the breast into skin, or chest or elsewhere.  Most likely terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have Stage 2.  My tumours had a mass of 8cm with the biggest one not being bigger than 5cm across.  That’s still quite big in my book, but I’m pleased to remain at Stage 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;n1-m0&quot;&gt;N1, M0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The N and M Stages tell you whether the cancer has spread to the nodes or elsewhere. Again more information can be found on the Cancer Research website for this&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but in my case, N1, the cancer had spread into the Lymph Glands but hadn’t gone into the surrounding tissue.  My M stage was M0.  It hadn’t gone anywhere else, it was contained within the breast tissue and lymph nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grade-3&quot;&gt;Grade 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bit isn’t such a lucky part.  Breast Cancer is graded 1-3 with one being where the cancer cells look most like normal cells&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  Grade 3 cells are massively different, grow fast and are more likely to spread.  The lucky part is that the specialists know what to do about a Grade 3 cancer and what Chemotherapy and other drugs will work to destroy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;er&quot;&gt;ER+&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I had to sign a consent form on this journey, was so they could do a biopsy to establish what the pathology of the tumours were.  This would then give the specialists the information they needed to plan my treatment.  It came back as ER+.  This meant that my oestrogen hormones were feeding the lumps as they were oestrogen receptive&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  Luckily, they are able to block those receptors with a drug called Tamoxifen and halt the cancer.  I’ll be taking this for 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;her2&quot;&gt;HER2+&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing they learned from the pathology was that I’m HER2+.  This means that the cancer cells have a higher than normal level of the HER2 protein which causes it to grow&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  Between 1 in 4, and 1 in 5 of breast cancer cases are HER2+&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. However, in recent years, a drug called Herceptin has become more readily available.  It used to be a postcode lottery as to whether the local NHS authority would allow it&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but because it works so well, that is no longer the case.  Herceptin works by blocking the HER2 protein receptors telling the cancer cells to stop growing.  I have Herceptin via a drip infusion every 3 weeks over a year.  I had a gap for the surgery, but I’m on course to finish in October/November time - one year after diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chek2&quot;&gt;CHEK2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My young age at diagnosis made us question how this could happen.  There is no family history apart from a distant cousin, so we were confused.  Was I a freak of nature, or a genetic freak?  When the Oncologist brought up the idea of genetic testing we thought it would give us answers to some of these questions.  And it did to an extent.  We expected to be told that I had an abnormality in the BRCA1/2 gene, which is the gene that increases the risk of breast cancer the most.  But I don’t. (See, lucky!)  On the NHS this would have been the only abnormality they check for.  However, as we had the test done privately, a whole range of other genes were tested which they know can have links to breast and other types of cancer.  This brought back a problem with the CHEK2 gene which increases chances of breast cancer occurring two or three times&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  Obviously, I already have a Breast Cancer diagnosis, so this faulty gene gives us a reason as to why this has all happened.  It also meant that I could put up a reasonable argument to the surgeon as to why I thought I should have a Bilateral Mastectomy, rather than just removing the cancerous breast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, this has implications for Imogen and Felix, but we’ll cross that bridge later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;support-team&quot;&gt;Support Team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Ross and I moved to Baldock, we took a punt.  It was a decision based on train times and costs into central London where we were both working, and the fact that it had countryside and trees around it.  We didn’t know anyone. It was a gamble and luckily for us, it paid off.  When we had Imogen I met a wonderful group of Ladies who had all had babies at around the same time and are now what we refer to as The Gin Club.  Not much Gin gets consumed, more tea and biscuits really, and wine on a night out.  I’ve known these ladies for nearly 8 years now, and they have proved their mettle. We would not have been able to do this without their support - day in, day out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad and Julie have also been fantastic.  Coming to stay for weeks at a time to look after the bairns so that I can rest, and Ross can work.
Here’s also a shout out to all my Internet Weirdy friends.  People that I don’t necessarily see very often in real life, but give a lot of positivity through the wonders of the World Wide Web. Everytime you click that ‘Like’ button, it reminds me, I’m not doing this on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;not-always-up&quot;&gt;Not Always Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post may make it sound like I’m skipping around shouting, “Look at me, I’m so lucky to have breast cancer”.  It’s not like that, I’d prefer that I hadn’t been diagnosed.  We’ve had a really tough 8 months, with still quite a way to go.  I have cried, I have wondered “Why Me?”, I’ve thought “But I don’t want to die!”.  But my point is that whilst the whole situation is a bit crap, and I wouldn’t wish it upon anyone, there’s been things that have happened that have made my cancer treatable and the situation manageable.  And for that I am truly thankful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much Love&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pancreaticcanceraction.org/community/blog/hard-hitting-advertising-campaign-launched-encourage-increase-early-diagnosis-pancreatic-cancer/&quot;&gt;Pancreatic Cancer Action - Survival Rates&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.breastcancercampaign.org/about-breast-cancer/breast-cancer-statistics&quot;&gt;Breast Cancer Campaign - Survival Rates&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cancerresearchuk.org/cancer-help/type/breast-cancer/treatment/tnm-breast-cancer-staging&quot;&gt;Cancer Research UK - Breast Cancer Staging&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breastcancercare.org.uk/breast-cancer-information/about-breast-cancer/diagnosis/cancer-size-grade&quot;&gt;Breast Cancer Care - Cancer Size and Grade&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cancerresearchuk.org/cancer-help/type/breast-cancer/treatment/hormone/types-of-breast-cancer-hormone-therapy&quot;&gt;Cancer Research UK - Hormone Therapy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breastcancercare.org.uk/breast-cancer-information/about-breast-cancer/her-2&quot;&gt;Breast Cancer  Care - HER2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cancerresearchuk.org/cancer-help/type/breast-cancer/treatment/biological-therapy-for-breast-cancer&quot;&gt;Cancer Research UK - Biological Treatments&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/society/2006/apr/10/cancercare.health&quot;&gt;The Guardian - Postcode lottery&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cancer.gov/cancertopics/genetics/breast/CHEK2gene&quot;&gt;National Cancer Institute - CHEK2 and Breast Cancer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Reasons-to-be-lucky&quot;&gt;Reasons I'm Lucky&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 16, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Closing a Chapter]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Closing-a-chapter" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Closing-a-chapter</id>
  <published>2014-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Sometimes things happen that make you re-evaluate what is important to you.&lt;p&gt;Being diagnosed with Cancer at 36 years old is one of those things.  We’d just moved into our forever house, Ross was really enjoying work, I was working 4 days a weeks as a Software Development Team Leader and we were comfortable.  Things had started to be less of a struggle.  And then, Bam!, everything gets spun around and we, as are family, are left reeling and wondering which way is up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued to work throughout the initial operations and Chemotherapy, mainly working from home.  Unfortunately this left me extremely fatigued and as a result my energy levels for spending with the bairns and Ross were depleted.  They weren’t getting anything from me, nevermind the best of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our break to Center Parcs, I had my big operation, and I haven’t been back to work since.  I found I was still suffering with fatigue, and the Oncologist assured me that this was perfectly understandable after all the treatments I’ve been through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the May half term I was able to have some great days with the bairns and just enjoy being a Mummy.  Generally followed by a long nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work had been going through a lot of changes as a result of a joint venture between two big European companies.  As a result of this there was some restructuring and I was given the opportunity to take Voluntary Redundancy.  Ross and I decided that it was something I should go for.  My priority needs to be my family.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for me, my application was successful, and yesterday was officially my last day at work.  I have mixed feelings about it, I worked there for four years, and met some really interesting people.  I also learned a lot, and hopefully I’ll be able to transfer that to any new job I get in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are going to be tight for us until I start working again, but you can’t put a price on being here, being with my family.  We’ll manage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll pop in and collect my photo’s of the bairns once I’ve finished my radiotherapy and say goodbye to everyone properly.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Closing-a-chapter&quot;&gt;Closing a Chapter&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 14, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Change Of Plan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/change-of-plans" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/change-of-plans</id>
  <published>2014-06-08T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-06-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">After saying I wasn&#39;t going to go out last night, I changed my mind.&lt;p&gt;I’m very glad I did.  At about 7:30pm after discussing it with Ross we decided it would do me good to go out.  So after a mad rush to get changed and put my makeup on, I met the Gin Club at the George for cocktails.  It was a good night, with a lot of laughter, and some much needed distraction form the current treatment.  It’s good to be reminded that life goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, upon my return home, I had a bad nights sleep, with a recurring theme of decapitated LEGO men.  Imogen was up with the pain from her ear infection and Ross didn’t have a great night either.  Felix has taken to sleeping with swords, NERF guns and shields so he can fight the monsters in his bad dreams.  (I can’t even begin to imagine how scared he must be.)  Luckily, he seemed to be ok last night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we had to go to the pet shop to get some Worming tablets for the cats.  Merlin has become quite the hunter, and after leaving a baby crow on the lawn yesterday morning, Ross was greeted with a rat and a decapitated magpie today. As the sun was shining, we decided to walk and let the bairns go on their bikes.  We also had a quick peek at bikes for Ross and I in Halfords.  Maybe in the next month or two we can think about getting them as it’ll be great to take the kids out on country rides once I’m starting to feel more human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the sun is shining, and we’re keeping on, keeping on.  As is standard for us Lawley’s, (Baldock Branch).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/change-of-plans&quot;&gt;Change Of Plan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 08, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glowing Slightly Green]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/glowing-green" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/glowing-green</id>
  <published>2014-06-07T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-06-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;ve finished the first week of radiotherapy.  Only two weeks to go.&lt;p&gt;I’m finding the breath holding technique to be getting easier as the week’s gone on.  The Radiographers, who are lovely, keep telling me to relax, but it’s not the most relaxing of environments, so it’s quite a challenge.  It’s quite tiring having a two hour round trip for a 20 minute appointment everyday, but luckily, I don’t have to drive myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been a minor spanner in the works with my surgery wound.  I had been getting it drained every week and a half, but my Oncologist asked me not to have it done once I’d had my radiography planning appointment.  This had been fine, and the wound seemed to have stabilised.  Then on Tuesday night, it seemed to fill with fluid.  I told the Radiographers on Wednesday and in the pre treatment scan, they were able to see that every day since then, it’s filled more.  After discussing it with the Oncologist, it was decided that I should be drained again, as it coud affect the treatment.  Luckily I was able to see the surgeon yesterday, and he drained away 50ml.  Unfortunately it’s still swollen and quite sore.  Meh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for how I’m doing “in myself”, I’m ok.  I’m not 100% great, I’m quite tired, and I’m finding that I’m avoiding social situations where I’d normally be first at the bar.  I think the problem comes with the stress of the anticipation.  Impromptu events cause less of a problem, but I missed my really good friends Rachel’s birthday drinks, because I couldn’t face it. (Sorry Rach x). I’m going to miss Anna’s drinks tonight too. Just thinking about trying to find something to wear, getting to the bar and then chatting is making me quite tearful.  I’ll just stay in, wearing my comfies, and drink a sparkling water.  Sorry Anna x.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news this week, Imogen has been suffering with an ear infection.  She’s been in quite a lot of pain.  So after a dash to the GP’s on Monday she’s been taking antibiotics since.  Unfortunately they haven’t worked so Ross had to take her to the out of hours GP today to get her some more and this time they’ll hopefully work!  Apparently it tastes disgusting, so she’s less than impressed.  Poor Lamb.  :-(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It now 5 weeks until the Race For Life.  The Gin Club are all upping the ante and my Facebook feed is full of posts stating how much training is going on, admittedly, some are more positive than others. It makes me smile, and very humbled and proud to be able to call them friends.  Thanks to them we’ve passed our fundraising target of £500, but there’s still time if anyone has a few quid they can spare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justgiving.com/the-gin-club&quot;&gt;http://www.justgiving.com/the-gin-club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/glowing-green&quot;&gt;Glowing Slightly Green&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 07, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lanes]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/lanes" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/lanes</id>
  <published>2014-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;m a big fan of xkcd, its a geek thing.&lt;p&gt;Xkcd is webcomic of romance, sarcasm, math, and language - if you haven’t seen
it before then you should check it out: &lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/&quot;&gt;xkcd.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a few strips about breast cancer as his fiancé contracted it a few years
ago and as I was surfing today and happened upon his lanes strip and it seemed
apt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/lanes.png&quot; alt=&quot;lanes&quot; title=&quot;Each quarter of the lanes from left to right correspond loosely to breast cancer stages one through four (at diagnosis).&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh - I’ve also added one to Julia’s last post as it was relevant ;)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/lanes&quot;&gt;Lanes&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 24, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tattoos and Scans]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/tattoos-and-scans" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/tattoos-and-scans</id>
  <published>2014-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;m aware that I haven&#39;t been writing much on the blog recently, but that&#39;s because not much has been happening, and that&#39;s a good thing.&lt;p&gt;We’re on a pretty even keel at the minute.  I’ve been spending time with the bairns and enjoying feeling relatively normal.  I’m still getting tired easily, and have to make allowances for myself.  I’m also feeling a bit vulnerable.  I took the bairns to Tesco the other day, and it seemed everyone was staring at me.  Even Imogen noticed and said “Mummy, that lady is really staring at you”. What can I say to that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also a few people in the school yard who seem to be blatantly ignoring me.  People who I’ve spoken to at length in the past.  I don’t know whether they are doing it because they don’t know what to say, whether they think I’ll start crying, or that I’ll just talk about Cancer at length.  Fact is, if someone says hello to me, I generally smile, and say “Hi” back.  If someone asks me how I’m doing, I’ll probably respond with a “Fine”, (this annoys Ross when I say it to the surgeon, or the oncologist, but that’s another story).  Ignoring me feels cruel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, things are about to go a bit mental again when I start radiotherapy on the 2nd June.  I had a 2 hour planning appointment yesterday where I had everything explained to me.  From what to expect during treatment, to what toiletries I’m allowed to use.  I also had to get to grips with some breathing equipment and googles.  Basically, because the radiotherapy is focused on my left chest near my heart, they use technology whereby I use a mouthpiece and software to control my breathing so that my heart is moved away from my chest walls so they can aim the beams to miss it and protect it.  I have to practice holding my breath for 36 seconds.  Yikes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for them to set the radiotherapy up, I had to have 5 tattoo dots and then a CT scan to allow them to plan the best path for the beams to hit the bits they need to.  I’m a bit disappointed with the dot tattoos if I’m honest.  Once all this is over, I’ll get a proper one to cover the scars.  I might as well, I’ve already had the first ink, and I didn’t really have a choice in it.  If I’m honest, I’ve never really thought tattoos were for me.  But, the cancer has taken so much from me, I’m looking at it as a way of reclaiming my body as mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ll be gearing myself up for 3 weeks of treatment.  In the meantime, it’s half term, and I get some quality time with my bairns.  I imagine they’ll be out on their bikes, at the park and generally having fun.  Just what we all need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/tattoo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tattoo&quot; title=&quot;I calculate that the electrons in radiation therapy hit you at 99.8% of the speed of light, and the beam used in a 90-second gamma ray therapy session could, if fired with less precision, kill a horse (they did not let me test this).&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/tattoos-and-scans&quot;&gt;Tattoos and Scans&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 20, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Springtime]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/springtime" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/springtime</id>
  <published>2014-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“No winter lasts forever, no spring skips it’s turn.”
&lt;br /&gt;Hal Borland (1900-1978)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a harsh winter and Julia nobly dealt with cocktails of drugs. They made her hair fall out and drove her to bone crushing depths of fatigue but I’m so immensely proud of her courage, dignity and tenacity in coping with it all.  The kids also make me so proud, they’ve shown resilience, understanding and acceptance throughout and have lived the last 8 months with cheerful courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring has truly arrived and it just seems the good news keeps rolling in. After being declared cancer free - thanks to heady cocktail of drugs and a quick flick of the surgeons knife, we went back to the chemotherapy doctor.  He was so pleased with the pathology results and really questioned if there was any need for a second round of chemotherapy.  Seems the long term implications outweighed the possible benefits, especially as they couldn’t find any cancer under the microscope for it to treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s still a long road and to cover all bases Julia is now scheduled for 12 more rounds of Herceptin, which has much fewer side effects than chemotherapy and is super effective against Julia’s type of cancer.  She’ll also be on other meds for 10 years but all in all it was better than we hoped and a great result!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happily, there was the Baldock beer festival over the weekend and Uncle Max came over for it especially. I even volunteered to work behind the bar for a couple of hours, having never worked behind a bar before I found it a baptism of fire. It certainly was manic but I think I enjoyed it :) I’m up for doing a stint next year to see if I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The combination of good news and a beer festival certainly gave me a fuzzy head and the optimism of spring has really hit home this year.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/springtime&quot;&gt;Springtime&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 09, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemical Wednesday]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/chemical-wednesday" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/chemical-wednesday</id>
  <published>2014-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s been just over 5 weeks since my surgery, and things are returning to normal. The new normal.&lt;p&gt;Uncle Max came to visit at the weekend, and we had a couple of lovely afternoons in the sun with friends at the Baldock Beer Festival.  Ross even did a stint volunteering behind the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been seeing the surgeon every week and a half to drain my wounds, and last week I saw the Oncologist again to discuss the next part of my treatment.  The good (GREAT) news is that I won’t be having any more chemotherapy. Yippee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general terms, there are two paths to treating cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chemotherapy (2 types over 4-5 month period), surgery, radiotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surgery, chemotherapy as above and radiotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also biological and hormonal treatments that are offered depending on the pathology of the cancer.  In my case Herceptin as I’m her+, and tamoxifen for er+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my lumps were big and nasty, they decided to give my the second lot of chemo first, they then decided to delay the second lot until after surgery and just get that out the way.  When they examined the tissue they removed in surgery under the microscope, they found no evidence of cancer at all.  After some deliberation the oncologist decided that the cons outweighed the pros for having the second lot of chemotherapy, and to carry on without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve restarted the Herceptin treatment again which is given via a drip every three weeks.  Today, it’s being administered more slowly than it been and I also had to stay in for observation for four hours afterwards in case of allergic reaction.  This is because there’d been a break in the 3 week cycle, so they have to reload me.  Next time it’ll not take as long, and even less after that.  Hopefully I’ll be finished by Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got scans and radiotherapy planning appointments over the next few weeks, and the treatment itself will start in June.  Basically I’ll have radiation fired at me everyday for 3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, it’s all really positive.  I’m still very tired, but I’m trying to up my mobility.  My hair is also coming back nicely!  No more hats or bandanas or wigs for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross has been great, and continues to be at my side at all my appointments.  I’m so lucky to have him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bairns are fantastic and make me proud every day.  They also make me laugh every day.  I hope they look back on this in the future and see not a horrible, dark time, but a part of a journey to making them more compassionate and thoughtful adults.  They are certainly wonderful children.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/chemical-wednesday&quot;&gt;Chemical Wednesday&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 07, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family Time]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/family-time" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/family-time</id>
  <published>2014-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The Easter weekend has been and gone, and we&#39;ve had a great time as a family.&lt;p&gt;We’ve played board games, done Easter Egg hunts, the kids have been on there bikes, we’ve been on walk, we’ve met up with friends, we’ve planted some seeds, Imogen’s moved up a swimming stage, we’ve got the kids some summer clothes, and we’ve laughed and smiled. A lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m truly lucky to gave such amazing bairns and such a brilliant husband.  They encourage me to get involved with things, but don’t give me a hard time, or get grumpy if I can’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still in a bit of pain, and had to go back to surgeon today to drain my wounds. He drained 260ml from the side which had the nodes removed.  We also found out that I’ve had 19 nodes removed in total.  8 in the initial op back in November, and 11 a few weeks ago.  The upshot of this is that I’m now at increased risk of infection in my left hand and arm as well as lymphoedema.  Basically swelling in my arm that doesn’t go down.  Which is nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also not sleeping particularly well due to the pain, so I’m quite tired during the day.  I’m glad Ross works from home as he encourages me to get up otherwise I’d be in bed all day, and that’s not going to help much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep on taking the painkillers for now and gear myself up for talking to the Oncologist for chemo round 2 which we expect to kick off in May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/family-time&quot;&gt;Family Time&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 22, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happiness and Sadness]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happiness-and-sadness" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happiness-and-sadness</id>
  <published>2014-04-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This week has passed in a haze with the bairns and my Dad being around whilst I&#39;ve been convalescing.  They&#39;ve pottered around, in and out and it&#39;s been great.&lt;p&gt;On Friday we went to see the consultant to have a review.  I’ve been in quite a lot of pain, not surprising when he drained over 400ml of fluid from my wounds.  Ouchie!
However, despite that, we came away delighted.  After they’d done the surgery, the tissue which was removed was sent to be analysed to see if there was any cancer remaining after the initial round of chemotherapy.  We’d know that it could be an option, but we hadn’t dared hope.  We also knew that regardless of whether there was or not, the surgery was always going to happen.  Trials have proven that even with a total pathological reaction to chemo, the cancer is very likely to come back.  My odds have always with this cancer sucked, so not having surgery was never an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here we are, Cancer free.  Woo hoo!  It’s not quite the end of the road yet.  I’ve still got another round of chemo to go, as well radiotherapy, and biological treatments.  I’ll be on medication for 5-10 years, but we’re over half way through.  I think the next lot of chemo will be tough as it is different to the last round, and will make me very sick.  I’ll lose my newly grown sprouts of hair again, but that doesn’t matter.  I’m here, and the treatment is working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve added a few things to my to do list: sort the garden, stain/paint some furniture, do a 10k run, do a Race for life Pretty Muddy, and do a triathlon.  What’s to stop me?  Only my own mental attitude.  At least that’s on my side!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dad has gone home now, and we’ll miss him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another sadness has been a shadow of family politics hanging over us since I first started chemo.  It keeps Ross awake at night, it causes arguments between us and ultimately it’s not helping us on our road to getting my little family through this awful time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All it will take is a simple “I’m sorry”, but it seems that is too much to ask.  Ross and I are going through the worst part of our lives together and to have to deal with this anxiety too, is exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in order to keep the peace, I’m going to have to accept that I am not going to get the apology.  My feelings are going to have to take a back seat for the Greater Good of a happy family.  I can’t watch Ross be torn in two over this, and he means more to me than my pride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happiness-and-sadness&quot;&gt;Happiness and Sadness&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 12, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pathology]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/pathology" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/pathology</id>
  <published>2014-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today we made the journey back to see the consultant surgeon today&lt;p&gt;The pathology is in and guess what? The chemotherapy worked!  There was no trace of cancer in the nodes and no cancer in the breast.  This is called a complete pathological response and is &lt;em&gt;really really&lt;/em&gt; good news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment won’t change, the mastectomy was still required and the current plan for another round of chemotherapy and radiotherapy still stand.  They are the belt and braces to ensure Julia’s healthy future. So we have some rocky days ahead but this the best news!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/pathology&quot;&gt;Pathology&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 11, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impasse]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/impasse" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/impasse</id>
  <published>2014-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This post has been such a long time coming but before I start I want to revisit the reason for this blog.&lt;p&gt;This blog was setup to act as a form of writing therapy, to help Julia and I through our emotions and to deal with the situation head on. All in the hope that one day when Julia is cancer free and cancer treatment has finished that we will come out of it stronger. The idea is that any issues will have been tackled head on, so that we can move on and enjoy the rest of lives in freedom. Freedom from the fear of cancer and freedom from any hangover of the truama of the treatment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, Imogen and Felix will be old enough to read this blog and I hope it will help give them perspective and understand their place in a journey they unwittingly went through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been one large emission from the blog, which because of family politics, I’ve kept it silent and bottled it up. It is the reason I am so often awake in the dark of the night and I can’t sleep because my mind whirls. I now realise it does this because I haven’t written about it and I haven’t given it a place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in November, after I spent a day in A&amp;amp;E with Julia who was having heart pains (the day after starting chemotherapy and herceptin), I was stressed. I reacted badly to some comments from my mum and then blogged about it. The post was supposed to be about how there’s no guidebook on how to handle someone going through Cancer treatment and how people react differently. I hurt my mum writing that post and I got an angry email telling me so. I apologised, redacted the post and wrote a new post apologising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The angry email back also took a swipe at Julia and I can understand lashing out when angry, we all do it. What I don’t understand is that after pointing out that it hurt Julia repeatedly, there has been no apology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Months have rolled by and communication has been in fits and starts but there’s always been an underlying tension. Any emails about the argument have fallen on deaf ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I had a call from my Dad asking if he and mum can come and visit to see Julia after her surgery. I had to tell him at present they aren’t welcome and saying that breaks my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a night of no sleep, wrestling with the futility of the situation, when I needed support the most, the stupidity of words spoken in anger have got in the way.  We have been stuck at an impasse for too long and we may not be able to control if Julia gets her apology but we can control how we deal with this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have to put it behind us, it’s damaging rather than healing. There are bigger things to deal with and a we deserve a positive future ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/impasse&quot;&gt;Impasse&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 09, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Makeup Selfies]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/no-makeup-selfies" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/no-makeup-selfies</id>
  <published>2014-04-06T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s 3am and I can&#39;t sleep.&lt;p&gt;I’ve had trippy dreams and have been sleepwalking.  In an effort to try and wait until the painkillers work, I’ve been reading a few articles on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found one retweeted by The Cancer Survivors Club (@cancer_buzz) and it made me a bit cross.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-2595450/These-selfies-make-livid-Why-cancer-survivor-JENNI-MURRAY-angry-stars-helped-raise-millions-posting-photos-no-make-up.html&quot;&gt;These selfies make me livid: Why cancer survivor JENNI MURRAY is angry with the stars who have helped raise millions by posting photos of themselves with no make-up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upshot is, that the author is a breast cancer survivor who thinks that the whole No makeup selfie thing is all about self promotion first, charity second, and that it in no way relates to how women who are going through breast cancer are feeling about their situation and their looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what?  I don’t care.  I don’t care if someone took 24 pictures of themselves with no make up on before they found one that didn’t look as bad as the others.  I don’t care if they had special lighting, or specially tousled hair.  Did they donate to a cancer charity?  That’s the bit I care about.  Because that part matters to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posting a picture of yourself on social media with no makeup on in no way compares with someone having no hair, looking grey from chemo.  Or with someone who has had life saving surgery but been left physically altered.  Does anyone really think it does?  I don’t think people are that ignorant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends and family have seen me at rock bottom looks wise.  Not just after getting up early and being all puffy eyed from lack of sleep on a camping trip. Or hungover to high heaven. I’m talking after months of relentless chemo.  Days after surgery.  And they’ll see me there again before I come out the other side.  Do they think the No Makeup Selfie equates to what I’ve been going through?  I doubt it.  They’re not stupid.  But some of them have done it.  Why?  So they can raise awareness of Breast Cancer and do something to feel useful.  Others have simply, quietly donated something.  Others still, have shared a link on how to check yourself for Breast Cancer.  All really useful stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my perspective, the No Makeup selfie has been a good thing.  It’s raised awareness and money.  I don’t see who the losers are here.  It’s not me.  I’ve got a great team behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/no-makeup-selfies&quot;&gt;No Makeup Selfies&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 06, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Worry, woes and welcome homes]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/worry-woes-and-welcome-homes" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/worry-woes-and-welcome-homes</id>
  <published>2014-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Last Sunday was mothers day and this year it felt that it had felt like it had extra special meaning.&lt;p&gt;The kids and I tried to spoil Mummy and make her day as best we could. This was quite tricky as the shadow of Mondays pending surgery was heavy and at times overwhelming. The Sunday night feeling was terrible!  However,  Grandad Mikes arrival was most welcome and helped brighten the mood. It was great to have him over and know that I can focus on Julia’s needs this week as the kids would be covered.  Thank you Grandad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surgery day inevitably arrives even though sleep was fleeting and all to soon it’s up and at them. Julia &amp;amp; Mike take the kids to school while I try and do some work. Its hard to concentrate so I focus on easy housekeeping type work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Text messages come in during the morning from friends and these help keep spirits up.  Julia’s facebook has exploded with well wishes and its hard to quantify how much these help and spur us on but thank you all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrive at the hospital on time and after the obligatory wait (we are in a hospital after all!) things happen quickly enough and I walk Julia to the operating theatre. The next few hours drag and I fret, work is out of the question as I can’t focus on anything, so I watch netflix. Four hours later Julia is wheeled back into her room. She’s a nauseous shade of grey, cold and clammy and still high from the anesthetic and the morphine. After a while she’s sick and slowly colour returns. Mr Crane the surgeon pops by and tells us everything went perfectly and he was also able to work round Julia’s Chemotherapy port. After a while I head off home to get some food and let people know that surgery went well and Julia is on the mend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its fantastic to think that Julia is now Cancer free! The rest of the treatment is belt and braces and that will take another 6 months to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the week, I’m generally at the hospital for 9am and spend the day there working and keeping Julia company. Julia brightens to see the kids Tuesday evening and friends visit on Wednesday. However, for some reason Julia is still very nauseous and struggles to eat - there’s not much I can do about it but it makes me anxious. The anti-sickness medication keeps going up but Julia still struggles to eat and keep food down. She’s also suffering from extreme headaches also making her feel nauseous and what’s hardest for me is theres no apparent cause of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday is a low day, I take Mike over in the morning but Julia is too ill to see friends in the afternoon and is struggling. I worry that she won’t make it home on Friday as she wants. Her drains from the surgery especially the one from the node clearance side are still filling full of fluid. There has to be 50 ml or less in a day to be ok for release. Extra painkillers, and anti sickness get her through the day. By this point I’m exhausted and really hope for some good news friday morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huzzah! 52ml in the drain - all good Julia can come home! She looks happier and taking bucket loads of anti sickness medication is helping, choosing the mushroom and bacon soup for lunch was not though! The drains are removed and the Mr Crane pops by and is happy that things are healing well and Julia can go home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huzzah! We get home and that night after we get the kids to bed, I take Mike for a couple of beers at the Orange Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/worry-woes-and-welcome-homes&quot;&gt;Worry, woes and welcome homes&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 05, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[55378008]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/55378008" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/55378008</id>
  <published>2014-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;m home after 5 days in hospital.&lt;p&gt;The operation went well but as happened last time, the anaesthetic made me sick.  A theme that has continued since.  I’m still taking anti sickness tablets in an effort to try and eat, but coupled with painkiller induced constipation, my digestive system isn’t my best friend at the minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I came round from the operation, the rest of Monday was spent in a drug induced haze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s funny, as you are supposed to rest in hospital, but I was getting woken at midnight to have my drains emptied (600ml in total for the week), then at 6:30 to have blood pressure, temp and pulse taken and to have drugs, then 7:30 for breakfast, obs taken and drugs given regularly through the day with the last one occurring at 10pm, although the last lot of drugs might come an hour later.  Then you have all the extra visitors of housekeeping, catering, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was a drug induced haze too, but I got to see the physio who gave me exercises to ensure mobility returns to my arms, the consultant who wanted to check I was doing ok, and my bairns!  Ross brought them to see me and I was over the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, I had a few Gin Club visitors, but by Thursday I was starting to feel unwell again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visitors were cancelled on Thursday and I spent the majority of the day throwing up.  It wasn’t pleasant.  Luckily at that point they decided the anti sickness tablets weren’t working very well so I was given an injection which seemed to do the trick for a short time at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Friday, my drains had stopped collecting large amounts of fluid, and it was decided that they could be removed.  Yippee!  After a quick chat with the consultant, and a bagful of drugs I was released, and got home just as the bairns were getting home from school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it all went a bit odd.  The bairns, who had been so good all week, turned into whinging wailing monsters!  It was quite absurd.  There was snot, tears and gnashing of teeth!  Felix didn’t eat all of his dinner so didn’t get a pudding.  End of the world.  After tea, Imogen was sent to get changed for gymnastics, but put her leotard on the wrong way round.  End of the world.  I asked Imogen to put a hoodie on to go to gymnastics.  End if the world.  I asked Felix to stop asking about going on the iPad, as he wasn’t allowed.  End if the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross took Imogen to gymnastics and left my dad and me with Felix.  More wailing, and throwing of his stool around.  Great.  He stewed for a bit, and I told him he could have a cuddle if he wanted after he got his pj’s on.  Five minutes later he was downstairs, in his pj’s and had cuddles.  Nice cuddles.  Careful cuddles.  Like a new boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier Caroline had popped round and we’d mentioned their behaviour, and she said she thought it could be a release of emotions for them.  They’ve been so worried all week, and now I’m home, and everything is ok, they just let it all out.  I think she’s right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got lots of time now to get things back on track.  And we will.  I just need lots of rest as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.s.  55378008 - put it in a calculator and turn it upsidedown.  It’s the current state of affairs.  The new normal.  For now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/55378008&quot;&gt;55378008&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 05, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mother's Day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mothers-day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mothers-day</id>
  <published>2014-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today was lovely, and I felt very spoilt.&lt;p&gt;I was presented with a tray full of cards, plants and a cup of coffee in bed by my wonderful bairns.  No less than 4 from Imogen!  I was allowed to stay in bed a little bit longer before I was told to get up to go to rugby training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was great watching them both run round in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was home to get them bathed and Ross cooked a lovely roast dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix helped me pack my case for hospital and we had lots of cuddles.  It’s going to be hard for them this week with me being away.  Grandad will be holding the fort so that Ross can be with me.  We are lucky to have such support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mothers-day&quot;&gt;Mother's Day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 30, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Anniversary]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happy-anniversary" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happy-anniversary</id>
  <published>2014-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today is our 9th wedding anniversary.&lt;p&gt;Ross has gone into London for work, and I’m looking after the children as there’s a teachers strike.  Hopefully we’ll all meet up later and go for a curry for tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had things gone to plan, I’d be recovering from a mastectomy and Axillary Node Clearance.  As it happens the surgery has been postponed until next Monday as my medical team needed to do some research to decide whether it would be worth doing a risk reducing mastectomy on the other side as well.    We met with him yesterday and he’s agreed to do it.  The surgeon said he would normally send women in my position to a plastic surgeon, a geneticist and a psychologist.  He said none were relevant in my case.  I told him that my boobs have done what they need to do, fed both bairns for over a year each, and as they are now trying to kill me, I’m not interested in trying to save them.  Every year I would be going for a mammogram, and waiting for them to tell me it had come back.  I don’t need that.  I don’t want that.  I can change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now I’ll be going in on Monday, and having a bilateral mastectomy with Node Clearance.  I need to pack my hospital bag and get myself sorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s going to be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happy-anniversary&quot;&gt;Happy Anniversary&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 26, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good to be home]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/good-to-be-home" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/good-to-be-home</id>
  <published>2014-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">We&#39;re back, and the washing machine is earning it&#39;s keep!&lt;p&gt;My overwhelming memory from the holiday is the feeling of pride I have for my little family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen - determined.  She scrambled up the indoor climbing wall easily, and was quickly tackling harder routes.  The Cyclone ride in the pool posed no issue.  Ross and I were screaming but Imogen just grinned and laughed.  Her swimming in the pool was effortless, and she went down all the slides too many times to count.  When bowling she refused any offers of help, and she managed to beat me every time.  With the adventure golf too, she refused help, and tried her best.  The pottery painting was her idea, and she produced a colourful dragon money box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix - strong.  He has only really got to grips with riding his bike in the past few months, but he had plenty opportunities to practice.  And he was amazing.  He cycled everywhere, and when he couldn’t ring his bell to signal he was ok, he’d shout “It’s on the other side.”  It took Ross and I a while to work out why he was shouting this, but it turns out it was because his bell had turned itself round so it was on the other side of the handlebars.  His swimming was great in the pool.  It would have been a very different holiday had he not been able to swim.  But swim he did.  Most of the time he was out of his depth, and he was able to go down all the slides on his own apart from the Cyclone because he was just too short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross - hero.  I’m not quite back up to full energy, so the full itinerary of activities meant there wasn’t much leftover for the normal day to day stuff.  But Ross took up all the slack. He did the cooking and organising and took the kids off by himself so I could rest when necessary.  He is amazing, and I’m lucky to have him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, they all rock, and I love them all very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/good-to-be-home&quot;&gt;Good to be home&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 23, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>