<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2013-12-16T09:37:58+00:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wookiee no more]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wookie-no-more" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wookie-no-more</id>
  <published>2013-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">A quiet week really, work and life are cracking on well.&lt;p&gt;Someone posted a question on an internet forum that showed a bug with my code. It took me two days to fix it and I saw broken behaviour of the language I program in, anyways it was a good puzzle and got my grey matter (and google skills) working at full pace to fix it.  My job really is all about solving puzzles and thats why I love it so much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday night, Julia was restless and fearful because the Chemotherapy was due to start again and this time it’s weekly.  So it took a time to fall asleep but this was all confounded by waking up at 2:30am and Julia hearing voices. Strange. We checked the window and there was no one nattering in the street, the voices were coming from downstairs! Noisy buglars? No the TV was on - we’d turned it off before going to bed, so that was very bizarre. We check all the doors, all locked. We can’t sleep so we watch an episode of Hebburn before trying to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday is chemo day and it goes smoothly. Julia is given 4 pre meds and the piriton knocks her out, so she sleeps through most of it. I spend my time working and a few hours later we head on home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chemo-sleep.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two Baldies&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning I take Imogen out for a run again. She’s great and we do sprints. Imogen decides tag is a better way to do sprints and it makes the run good fun. At one point I tag Imogen turn sharply and then go flying. My foot had found a rabbit hole, luckily I didn’t twist anything but I did fall onto some very sharp branches and cut my leg up a bit. Imogen found it all very amusing and tagged me back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the week we get an email from Little Ruggers, seems they are no longer challenging Felix so Saturdays class will be his last. On Saturday morning we all head out and watch. He comes out beaming at the end with a certificate and medal. He’s a bit nervous about going to the Rugby club but I know once he gets used to it he’ll love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia’s hair looks really thin and patchy now. For the first time she really looks like that she is a chemotherapy patient.  She finds this hard, we knew her hair would most likely fall out and she had prepared for that. However, its no quick process, it’s bit by bit and that makes it all the more traumatic. I think if it was an overnight process it would be easier to handle but its not that way. By Sunday afternoon Julia has had enough and we get the clippers out. She cries, it’s a shock and she briefly mourns her hair before accepting its fate.  Imogen looked shocked and hugs mummy and Felix didn’t know how to react and giggled then asked if mummy could put a wig on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lawleys.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two Baldies&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wookie-no-more&quot;&gt;Wookiee no more&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 16, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's oh so quiet!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/oh-so-quiet" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/oh-so-quiet</id>
  <published>2013-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Since Thursday's chemo and herceptin treatment, it's been quite quiet.&lt;p&gt;All has gone to plan, there’s been no nasty side effects and although I’m tired, I’ve been able to get some more Christmas preparations done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hair was still falling out in clumps, so Ross helped me out and today we shaved it off.  I look like a Star Trek character.  I have to admit I did cry when I first saw it, but it’s only hair, and it’ll grow back.  Ross shaved his too, so we’re a couple of baldy heads together.  The support we’ve received from our friends on Facebook has been great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing to happen over the last few days is that my Wicked Step Mother, Julie, has finished her treatment for breast cancer.  She’s had a full on 5 months with surgery and radiotherapy, and can now get on with her life.  She has been a rock for me over the past few months as she knows exactly what I’m going through.  Big hugs and much love. X&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/two-baldies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two Baldies&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/oh-so-quiet&quot;&gt;It's oh so quiet!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 15, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Up]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/on-the-up" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/on-the-up</id>
  <published>2013-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Monday to Wednesday this week were fairly normal.  I've been splitting my time between work and home. I've lost more hair than I've got left now, and I'm shedding still.  The bathroom seems to be where the majority can be found, much to Ross's dismay.&lt;p&gt;On Monday we went to see Felix’s school Christmas play.  He sang his songs very well, but it was odd seeing him with drawn on goatee beard and sideburns.  All the children did very well.  I’m looking forward to watching Imogen’s on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to go to the hospital for blood tests on Wednesday morning, but all went to plan, and we came home and cracked on with work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday morning I woke up at 2am to hear voices.  I went downstairs to find the tv on. I was sure it got turned off when we went to bed and it definitely wasn’t on the same channel we’d been watching.  After switching it off, we went back to bed, but the pre chemo anxiety meant we couldn’t get back to sleep, so we watched tv in bed for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few hours later, Ross got up to take the bairns to breakfast club, and I got up shortly after to tidy up ready for the cleaners coming.  Then it was off to the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, the nurses were efficient, and I was soon hooked up to a saline drip, followed by 4 pre-med drips including antihistamine, antacid and anti sickness.  Then it was the chemo, Herceptin, and a saline drip and anti-coagulant to finish.  I’m so glad I have a portacath, as it’s so straight forward to administer all the drugs.  The antihistamine knocked me out and I slept for most of the session.  This was very different from the first session, and it seems will be how each session will be on the new regime.  Ross, as always was sat next to me working away on his laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came home, and I went back to bed.   When the bairns came back, Felix announced he had moved up a reading level, and Imogen did a recital of her recorder Christmas tune from memory.  She now wants to learn Jingle Bells so we had a master class and she’s been practicing that.  My bairns make me so proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite calm today.  I like calm days.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/on-the-up&quot;&gt;On the Up&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 12, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Festivities]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/festivities" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/festivities</id>
  <published>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">As we roll into December, we're getting more and more festive.&lt;p&gt;Ross and I have almost finished the Christmas shopping.  Lists are being made in preparation for Christmas Day food shopping, and the cupboards are getting stocked with Goodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had confirmation that my chemo will run weekly starting next Thursday, so we’re trying to get everything done before that starts.  I had a few of the Gin Club ladies round for coffee on Friday morning which was lovely.  I’m not going to have a chance to do that again until all the cycles have finished in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, we went to see Cinderella at the theatre in Stevenage.  It was great fun, and we all enjoyed it very much.  Ross nearly had a close call with an Ugly Sister, but having Felix sat beside him saved him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening it was the Gin Club Christmas dinner at The George in Baldock.  Sadly, Lesley missed it as she had a stomach bug, but everyone else made it, and we had a lovely time.  It wasn’t as rowdy as it’s been in the past, but it was still very nice.  The food was good, and I enjoyed a couple of glasses of wine.  I was one of the first to leave, but I still stayed out later than I thought I would and Ross was starting to get a bit worried by the time I did get in.  (Sorry Ross).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to style my hair carefully for the evening, as it’s coming out in clumps now.  I have some bald patches, but with some careful positioning and some spray wax, I think I got away with it.  I googled how long it would take for my hair to fall out completely, and I didn’t really find a definitive answer, although I did find someone’s rather upsetting hair loss video diary.  Everyone is different.  I’m having to sleep wearing a hat in an effort to try and contain the hair that’s falling out.  It’s not very comfortable, but it’s doing the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next week or so, I’ll probably start wearing the bandanas and scarves I’ve got on standby. I’m a bit worried about that to be honest as it’ll become obvious to the world that I’m a Cancer patient. The school run is becoming a daunting prospect as are the Christmas concerts I’ve got to attend over the next week.  I don’t particularly want to be gossiped about by people who don’t know me on the school playground.  I’m probably being over sensitive, and no one will notice or care, especially if I utilise the trusty wooly hats I’ve got.  Thank goodness it’s winter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday was a rather quiet affair for me, only venturing out to Sainsbury’s for some lunch , and then a long nap on the sofa.  Ross kept the kids entertained by taking them to their swimming lessons, and also for a walk followed by a drink at the Orange Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s still some family politics rumbling on.  Ross and I are under extreme pressure at the minute and if allowances can’t be made for that, then there’s something wrong.  I don’t have the energy to deal with it at the minute.  My priority has to be getting through the next 10 weeks as best I can and making Christmas as normal as we can for Imogen and Felix.  They are and always will be my reason for fighting.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/festivities&quot;&gt;Festivities&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 09, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Busy bee]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/busy-bee" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/busy-bee</id>
  <published>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Another weekend sails by and the Christmas season is gathering pace.&lt;p&gt;Another busy weekend is over and I’m getting into the flow of being über house husband. I’ve taken the kids to the dentist, done five loads of laundry (the whites are still white!), chauffeured the kids to gymnastics and little ruggers. Shouted at villans and nearly abducted by an ugly sister at the pantomime. I cooked a truely awful massaman curry, I didn’t know it was possible to cook bad thai food but thanks to what at the time I thought was an inspired purchase of powered coconut milk, I managed it - bluergh bad times. I did the weekly food shop and took the kids swimming, somehow managed to end up at the supermarket shopping again. By Sunday lunchtime I had collapsed in a heap on the sofa knackered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, an hours swim isn’t enough for the kids to properly knacker them out, so whilst Julia had a sleep, I took the kids and headed out round Ivel Springs with a ball to kick, it’s becoming a Sunday tradition now. I knew that the Gaskells were off round for a walk and then there was a suggestion of a pint in the Orange Tree after.  I was pleased when we bumped into them and Pete at the Springs, the little ones all ran round a bit chasing the football.  A cheeky couple of pints afterwards rounded off the walk nicely. Then it was back home to cook up a roast chicken with all the trimmings.  So another busy but good weekend passed by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia’s hair is still falling out, she’s lucky she started with a lot but I now know how Han Solo must have felt sharing with Chewbacca, there’s hair everywhere!  Julia was pleased that her hair had lasted for her to go out on Saturday night with the Gin Club for their Christmas meal.  Some judicious combing hid the thinner parts well and I could see how relieved she was when getting ready that she’d look ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pleased Julia was good to go out but also I had some conflicting feelings. I was worried she was out late and would tire herself out but more than that I was jealous. It took me a time to realise it but I was jealous of the Gin Club, they’d get my Julia on good form for a few hours. It’s selfish of me but I knew I’d get a tired and exhausted Julia back and on Sunday she was and rested most the day. She missed the family stuff - swimming and the afternoon walk to recover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this picking up the slack and stepping up whilst Julia is ill makes me realise how amazing single parents must be. My hat iss off to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chemotherapy starts again this week and it’s all change, no longer will it be once every 3 weeks but for the next 9 weeks we’ll be at the Hospital once a week for chemotherapy.  I’d be lieing if I didn’t say we are nervous of what the effects of the new chemotherapy drug will be. But whatever the costs of getting better, we’ll knuckle down and get through it. I’m just really pleased Christmas is coming, with all its associated distractions. It gives team Lawley a place to focus on during for a couple of weeks at least.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/busy-bee&quot;&gt;Busy bee&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 09, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hair Today...Gone Tomorrow]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hair-today-gone-tomorrow" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hair-today-gone-tomorrow</id>
  <published>2013-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Two weeks after my first chemotherapy, my hair has started to fall out.&lt;p&gt;I thought I’d deal with it better than I am to be honest.  It’s only hair.  It’ll grow back as soon as the treatment finishes in February.  But I’m feeling a bit sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into the office yesterday, which I found ridiculously tiring.  Just getting up, getting the kids to breakfast club and then driving to Bedford took it out of me.  I was shattered.  It was good to see everyone, but it’s clear that if I’m going to be much more productive working at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working at home today, as is Ross and there’s men putting a new garage roof on.  The old one had holes in it and wouldn’t have kept the contents of the garage dry over the winter, so the last of the moving house fund has gone on getting it replaced.  I’ll have to wait until I’m better before we can start saving towards the other things we want to do, including getting a new fire put in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m sat here, more hair is falling out and I’ve got quite a pile next to me now.  I wonder how long it’ll be before I decide enough is enough, and I shave it off?  I’ve got a wig and some bandana’s all ready, it’s just harder than I thought it would be, and I’m a bit disappointed with myself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hair-today-gone-tomorrow&quot;&gt;Hair Today...Gone Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 04, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/thanksgiving" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/thanksgiving</id>
  <published>2013-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Life is settling a little now, there's been no shocks, hospital visits, mild peril or panics for over a week! I like this.&lt;p&gt;On Thanksgiving Thursday Julia and I do an epic christmas shop, we will be well fed and watered in the Lawley house this year! On Friday, Imogen has her school play, it’s fantastic, she rocks. On Friday evening Greg has arranged a head wetting to celebrate the arrival of Joni Martin. I’m glad to say my thirst returned and the Gin Club dads were all on good form. During the night I was getting text updates from Julia making sure she was ok. After a couple of beers and a tour of Baldock’s lesser pubs I head on home.  Julia is still up when I get home and has been through a whole packet of Halls for a sore throat. I find this out a few days later but it explains Julia’s texts and highlights that where sickness is involved, we are are on an amber alert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday I awake with a headache (must have had a dodgy pint) and after paracetomal and water fail me, I decide to go for a run. Felix heads downstairs for a session of Lego Star Wars on the playstation (a highly addictive (as in crack) game for 5 year olds). Imogen on the other hand decides to tag along and we head off for a run.  She’s great company and even wins 2 of the 3 mini sprint races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before I head off to take Felix to little ruggers Michelle drops off some frozen dinners which is a massive help - thank you! I head off to little ruggers only to find its not on as it’s the schools Christmas fair. So I head to the supermarket and Felix is placeted by a getting a chocolate Freddo. Anna comes round to take Imogen to her dance class - thanks again Anna. As I’m now a fully fledged Laundry Master I crack on with the weeks laundry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That afternoon we head off to Petes 40th Birthday do, I drive as Julia isn’t up for walking. We have a great time - Pete and Lesely’s curries are awesome and the chilli lime pickle was burnylicious.  We had a great time and headed home when I saw that Julia looking tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday came round and I marshalled the bairns for their swimming lessons, whilst Julia had a lie in.  Imogen managed to get some new goggles out of me, seems she’s been growing. Felix has his lesson first, whilst Imogen and I splash round and practise diving in. Imogen has a talent of starting to dive, then falling horizontally into the water, it’s impressive. Not nearly as impressive as my splash when I dive in apparently. Soon its Imogen’s lesson and Felix and I splash around. He’d been complaining that the Green caps are too hard, well that seems to have been forgotten and he swims wonderfully and even shows me his dolphin legs and butterfly stroke. I get told I’m doing mine wrong by lifting my head out the water. He’s a chip off the old block, one lesson on butterfly and he’s a master!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That afternoon Regan, Lorna, Elsie and Oscar arrive and we head to the Orange Tree for lunch. Its great to see them and the afternoon flies. I even found time to make mince pies (it was that or fall asleep). They don’t look like any mince pies you can buy but tasted about right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday night comes all too quickly, as Julia is feeling ok I sign up for a conference in London for Monday and Tuesday.  The conference is great and Michelle’s frozen meals save the day. On Monday night Christmas arrives to the Lawley house, all decorations are up. We are signalling our intent that Santa should stop at the Lawley house this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its Tuesday now and I’m back in the conference, Julia headed to work this morning. I feel low when I get a text from her telling me her hair has started to fall out. I call her and she’s ok - it was inevitable and it’s not falling out in clumps. She rocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My overriding thoughts from the last few days have been our friends are great abd we are lucky to have them.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/thanksgiving&quot;&gt;Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 03, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Christmas]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-christmas" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-christmas</id>
  <published>2013-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I worked at home today.  I slept badly again last night, so rather than spending energy driving to work, I thought it was the best use of the energy I do have.&lt;p&gt;Ross went into London for a geek meet, so I was home alone.  At lunchtime, I pulled the boxes of Christmas decorations out, and put up a few festive ornaments.  When Ross got home, I supervised him putting up some more lights, the tree and when the bairns came home they helped me decorate it.  The problem we have us that we don’t have enough decorations for the new house!  The front room looks great, but there is nothing in the kitchen/dining room.  This obviously needs to be rectified.  Especially as we’re having Christmas at home this year.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-christmas&quot;&gt;It's Christmas&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 02, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Side Effects]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/side-effects" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/side-effects</id>
  <published>2013-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It's been 5 and a half weeks since my diagnosis with Stage 2 breast cancer.  It's been quite an eventful time.  Our support network has been fantastic and we really do know who we can rely on in a crisis.&lt;p&gt;It’s been 5 and a half weeks since I started to take Tamoxifen which blocks the hormone receptors in the tumours to stop them growing, and a week and a half since I started my chemo and Herceptin to kill and shrink the cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there’s been some side effects.  Not the the chest pains that took us to A&amp;amp;E, and the fatigue which I was expecting, but headaches, nausea, sore mouth and the most annoying, night sweats.  I don’t have a temperature, but I wake in the night drenched.  A few minutes later, I cool down, fall back to sleep, pull the covers back up, and shortly after, I’m over heating again, in a cruel vicious circle.  Of course this is affecting my sleep, and I’m having crazy dreams.  Last night’s involved making a Mary Berry, Great British Bake Off Christmas Yule Log which I saw her make on the tv yesterday.  Felix expressed an interest in it, and I told him we’d try and make it.  So my dream involved buying the ingredients, and equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another side effect is I’m off alcohol.  We went to a friends birthday party yesterday, and all I could manage was two glasses of sparkley.  This is almost unheard of.  Still, it’ll mean the Christmas wine will go further…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At midday, my brother Regan, his wife Lorna, and Elsie and Oscar arrived.  It was great to see them, and they were a delight.  Again, I am reminded how wonderful my family is.  We went to the Orange Tree for a magnificent pub lunch (best in a Baldock in my opinion), and I managed a couple of halves of Buntingford Silent Night ale.  Lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got back, Regan helped Ross get some lights up in the tree in the front garden.  It’s very festive.  Not sure what the neighbours think though, we seem to be the first in the street to put any lights up indoor or outdoor!  Oh well, start as we mean to go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sad when it was time for them to leave, but I’m so glad they came.  I’m very tired now, do it’ll be bath and bed for me.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/side-effects&quot;&gt;Side Effects&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 01, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yuck]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/yuck" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/yuck</id>
  <published>2013-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Despite the chest pains and tiredness, I thought I was doing pretty well with the side effects of the chemotherapy.&lt;p&gt;It’s odd, because even after just a week after the treatment I think I can feel a change in Big Lump.  This is obviously great news.  What I didn’t expect was sickness to hit me like a train in the middle of the night.  It was too late to take the anti sickness tablets so the inevitable happened.  This then meant that I was tired today so I’ve spent it in bed.  The bairns dispensed their usual healing hugs before Ross took them to breakfast club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another weird side effect is the inside of my mouth feels funny.  Like I’ve eaten too many sherbet lemons and that makes my lips feels cracked and dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a visit from Ally yesterday which was lovely.  He’s been in the States so hasn’t seen us since the news broke.  More hugs, more offers of help.  It’s good to know we have such good friends around.  Friends who will cut us a bit of slack, allow us to use them as a sounding board, and just understand that we need TLC and not pull us up on our shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re starting to think more about Christmas.  Ross has ordered the turkey crown from the butchers and lists are being made.  We’re thinking about putting the Christmas decorations up at the weekend and then put the tree up the week afterwards.  I’m not feeling massively festive, but now that I’ve got a follow from the Official Santa on Twitter, I’m hoping to tap into some of the big man’s magic.   My Dad and Julie are going to be here for Christmas, as is Uncle Max, so I’m sure it’ll be great.  It’s the Gin Club Christmas do the weekend after next, and I’m hoping to feel well enough for that.  They’ll have to forgive me if I recycle a previous Christmas dress, I can’t be bothered to go clothes shopping.  Although I have noticed Tesco have got a wonderful range of Christmas jumpers in…  I wonder…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This evening was a bit of a logistical feat to get the bairns from Clair’s, to Catherine and Toms with keys so they could be taken back to ours later whilst we went to the hospital to see the Oncologist.  It turns out the things that have been going on have been a reaction to the chemo.  The doctor agreed that the tumour has shrunk substantially already which is very reassuring to know, but it’s that which caused the chest pains. The doctor is going to change the drug and cycle so instead of another 3 cycles every 3 weeks, I’ll be starting weekly cycles for 9 weeks.    This’ll kick off in 2-3 weeks.  I’ve got more steroids to take and more instructions to keep taking the anti sickness drugs.  I’m annoyed that I wasn’t able to take the side effects from the first lot of chemo but equally, I don’t fancy feeling like this for long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got back home and the kids were in bed having their story read by Catherine.  They bounced down the stairs when we got in and gave me some fantastic hugs.  We ushered them back to bed, all listened to the story and then it was more hugs and bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is another day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/yuck&quot;&gt;Yuck&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 27, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[All change]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/all-change" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/all-change</id>
  <published>2013-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I'm starting to think that late appointments are just a conspiracy to make you pay more parking.&lt;h2 id=&quot;tuesday&quot;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia had two appointments today and we had to hang round for both. In the morning they took bloods to see how she’s doing now after the weekends visit to A&amp;amp;E. In the afternoon they reviewed the bloods and saw that they were still good.  The doctor advised that it was most likely a side effect of chemotherapy and that we should do regular check ins with the GP every to make sure we get a holistic view of Julia’s health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night I woke when Julia rushed out the room and was sick. It reminded me of Julia’s morning sickness but the situation is much less happy. I went and fetched the nausea tablets. Unfortunately, no sooner than they went down, Julia got to see them again :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia wasn’t sick again but certainly looked green gilled in the morning. After a call to the nurse I was able to give Julia more tablets to help settle things.  She was wiped out though and didn’t manage to get out of bed until it was nearly time to go to see the clinical oncologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The oncologist is super nice, he is happy that the chemotherapy is working but he’s not happy about its impact on Julia.  He notes there has been an extreme tumor reaction and its shrunk. This may also have counted for some of the chest pains Julia is suffering from. He plans to move Julia onto a sister drug, which will mean weekly chemotherapy with hopefully a level impact. In the meantime whilst this round of chemotherapy is still in her system Julia is given steroids to help counter the fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get home and the kids are already for bed, thanks Tom and Catherine for looking after them.  Imogen is still buzzing from her assembly which she had
practised during the day - Julia and I are looking forward to seeing it on Friday.  I read some more of the brilliant Famous Five to everyone and then its hugs and bed.  I forgot to cook early on, so I make Julia some soup and I get a take away curry.  Julia’s taste buds have been changed, she struggles with the soup but the allure of curry wins and she tucks into some more food :)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/all-change&quot;&gt;All change&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 27, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life is a Rollercoaster]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/z-life-is-a-rollercoaster" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/z-life-is-a-rollercoaster</id>
  <published>2013-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">In the immortal words of one Ronan Keating &quot;Life is a Rollercoaster, just got to ride it.&quot;&lt;p&gt;Ross and I are very much stuck in the moment at the minute.  We are keeping our heads down and dealing with the immediate things that need to be dealt with.  With everything that is going on we can only ask for patience and understanding.  We may not get everything right all the time, but hey, being diagnosed with cancer pretty much means all bets are off and normal rules don’t apply.  We are trying our best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the weekends adventures we had to have a bit of a debrief from those overseeing my care.  So, I’ve spoken to two nurses, two doctors and a ward sister so far today.  Just a regular day in the Lawley house.  I’m still having chest pains,  but I’m still taking the painkillers and the Oncologist has asked me to get a prescription from my GP to try something else too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross and I are both working at home today.  My Immune system is probably at it’s weakest, so it’s best to stay away from the great unwashed at the minute.  I’m glad that I have the option to work at home as it means I feel like I’m being useful and I’m not rotting my brain by watching daytime tv.  (My colleagues may not actually agree with that though…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bairns were lovely this morning.  Both came in and gave me a lovely hug before they went off to breakfast club.  I love my kids, I am so proud of them and they amaze me every single day with their resilience and ability to plough on.  I am truly lucky to be their mum.  Yes, they get shouted out every so often, but who cares.  They don’t.  They know they are loved and are confident and secure in themselves and our little family unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pinky dropped off a very kind and thoughtful set of gifts.  I’m looking forward to opening them all later with the kids.  Thank you Pinky. x&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/z-life-is-a-rollercoaster&quot;&gt;Life is a Rollercoaster&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 25, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Putting my foot in it.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/putting-my-foot-in-it" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/putting-my-foot-in-it</id>
  <published>2013-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Julia has slept relatively well but looks tired, so as planned I get up and get the kids ready for their swimming lessons.&lt;p&gt;My mum comes with me as she wants to watch the kids, we get to the pool but the lessons are cancelled as there had been a power outage overnight resulting in the pool temperature being too low.  We head to Letchworth leisure centre instead and I take the kids for a swim whilst granny watches from the cafe and has a coffee.  The kids are good little fishes and enjoy a splashing around and swimming in the deep end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head home via the supermarket and I stock up on food for the week. I’m off beer whilst Julia is poorly and although it’s missed, it’s absence will do me some good. After lunch my parents help return Imogens room back to normal and then head home to Newbury. It’s been good having them here and we do appreciate their help this week. It hasn’t all been smooth, feathers have been ruffled on both sides but it is a time of stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For dinner I cook up a roast, I see it all as practice for christmas. A roast chicken with new potatoes, yorkshire pudding and 4 different vegetables. Team Lawley wolf it down and then start getting ready for the coming week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening I catch up on the blog and put my foot in it big time with my Mum, it seems I’ve lost my
tact button and am unwittingly thoughtless. After a terse email telling me I upset her and detailing some of our shortcomings this week, I quickly remove the offending text from the post and email an apology back. I am sorry for upsetting her, I didn’t mean to and now Julia is also upset (nice one Ross). I can’t sleep because of it but after a few hours stewing on it I have to put in proper perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have the mental bandwidth to deal with this all now as well as Julia’s cancer and I have to prioritise her first. This is a traumatic time in our lives and at times I will be bad company, self absorbed, thoughtless, tactless, feckless and other adjectives ending in less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only apologise and ask for forgiveness in advance. I will try to be a better person but when I fail do call me up on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry mum x&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/putting-my-foot-in-it&quot;&gt;Putting my foot in it.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 25, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accident and Emergency]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/accident-and-emergency" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/accident-and-emergency</id>
  <published>2013-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Strange things happened in the night last night and Julia casually mentions some mild chest pain.&lt;p&gt;I awake at 3:30 for some reason, Grandad is in the loo and I need to spend
a penny.  I head downstairs and just as I’m turning off a light I hear a pop
upstairs and the lamp downstairs switches off.  Then Julia is shouting and I
rush upstairs it seems the iPad charger has exploded and tripped all the sockets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plug is covered in soot and the charger is in two parts - wowzers on later
inspection the charger is a counterfeit apple charger :( The good news is that Julia’s temp is good
but she mentions some chest tightness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning I’m happy that Julia’s temperature is back to normal and she heads
off to have her wig cut. Grandad and I take Felix to little ruggers and read the
paper whilst Felix charges about with a huge grin - he loves little ruggers.
When I get home Julia tells me the car lights on for a flat - so I head to Tescos
to fill it up and find one very low tire, a slow puncture just what I need and I
plan on getting it sorted asap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get home and Julia is more concerned about her chest. We try and phone the
nurse and the on-call mobile seems to have gone off line.  A couple of calls to
the hopsital and we get through and Julia is ordered to A&amp;amp;E.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen is devistated that we can’t take her to dancing but I’m focused on the one
with chest pains so when asked, I decline to draw a map to dance studio - I’ve got
places to be, sorry Grandparents you’re in charge of the 7 year old howler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get to A&amp;amp;E, Julia signs in and I head off to get the car in the proper car
park. When I come back, there’s no Julia so I get directed to her.  They’ve done her
blood pressure and temp and decided she should be put in a side room on her own and not
with the rest of the sick plebs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia has an ECG, they take blood and order an x-ray.  They don’t tell us the
results of the ECG and that concerns me.  We sit and wait for someone to tell
us what’s going on.  It’s a well known fact that Hospital time breaks all known
rules of the universe. Each second drags, a minute lasts a eon but hours happily
roll by. I think it’s an elaborate illusion by your brain to protect you from the mind
numbing teadiousness of it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen a consultant and lots of things have been ruled out, so they need to do
more blood tests.  The A&amp;amp;E sister has had enough of us hogging the side room
and we are moved back with the great unwashed to a new waiting room in the CDU.  There’s
some family there with a lad my age who has a swollen face, seems it’s a big day
out for them all.  The quick blood tests take hours and eventually Julia tactfully complains
that we’ve been there 7 hours and she has &lt;strong&gt;cancer&lt;/strong&gt;, someone takes the hint
and a Nurse offers her food five minutes later - No luck for me they’ve just
run out.  I snag some ginger snaps from Julia’s handbag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consultant comes back, hes a good bloke but is happy lots of bad things have
been ruled out but also concerned nothing has been ruled in.  Possibly a side
effect or the start of an infection. He wants her to stay overnight for
observations, Julia pleads her case to be sent home and we are given strict
instructions - &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; new symptons or &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; worsening then come back in.  He
also refers us for an ambulatory review for Monday / Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head home, Julia is too shaky to walk to the carpark, so I run round to fetch
the car.  I’m starving so dive into the chippy for some lunch / tea.  I get home
and Julia takes her meds and goes to bed. My mum and dad have been great and had
the kids all day no problems, they tell us they are a credit to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no rule book or even guide book on how to cope with a loved one having
cancer. It impacts us all - family and friends, all in very different ways. We
have to remember that and accept that no one’s perfect and keep working and helping
each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s great we are now getting Julia better but, my, it’s still an emotional
rollercoaster. The tears that were so effective at being a pressure valve when
the initial shock of the diagnosis have long gone. I need to find a replacement,
I tried meditating, exercise and even a good session in the pub. All help but none
so quick a fix as a good cry, lets hope writing this all down also works well.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/accident-and-emergency&quot;&gt;Accident and Emergency&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 24, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spanner in the works]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/spanner-in-the-works" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/spanner-in-the-works</id>
  <published>2013-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today didn't quite go as planned.  It started at the hairdressers and ended at home after a 9 hour stint in A&amp;E.&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was fairly chilled.  I went to Michelle’s for a coffee and a chat and then came home and relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a list of symptoms to keep an eye out for which could indicate a reaction to treatments.  It’s quite a long list and we keep having to look at it to make sure nothing is happening that shouldn’t.  Into the evening, Ross noticed I was looking a bit flushed, so took my temperature.  Anything over 37.5’ he has to call the nurse.  It was over, so he called her.  I hate making a fuss, but was told to get over it and take a couple of paracetamol and call again if anything changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably about this time, I was starting to get chest pains.  I knew this was a big red flag and should mention it to Ross but I didn’t.  Ross woke up at 3am in the morning and went to get a glass of water.  Whilst he was gone the iPad charger which was plugged in behind my bedside table exploded.  Literally.  It went pop!  It tripped the sockets, but luckily apart from the charger and cable, and a slightly singed socket, all was fine.  I thought it prudent to mention the pains this point.  I played it down, and we went back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, I went to see Izzy my hairdresser so she could work some magic on the wig I’d bought.  She did a great job.  It doesn’t scream wig, and I think it’ll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chest pains were still there, so when Ross came home from taking Felix to Ruggers, I thought it best to ‘fess up.  He was straight onto the nurse and we were told in no uncertain terms to get to A&amp;amp;E.  This unfortunately meant Imogen missing her dance class.  I’ll have to make it up to her.  She was very upset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then we entered the time vortex of the Lister hospital.  I had all sorted of tests thrown at me and they all came back clear.  They kept me in to see if anything changed but it didn’t.  Eventually, I put up a convincing enough argument to be allowed home.  I have strict instructions to take the painkillers, and to go back if anything changes.  Anything at all.  I need to go back early next week for a review just to make sure though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m now in my own bed, still in pain, but home.  Maybe tomorrow will be better.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/spanner-in-the-works&quot;&gt;Spanner in the works&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 23, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitals - waiting and warm radiators]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hospitals-waiting-and-warm-radiators" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hospitals-waiting-and-warm-radiators</id>
  <published>2013-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It's been a stupendously busy week and I've been busy but have started feeling guilty I haven't put pen to paper or finger to ipad to update those following Julia's journey.&lt;p&gt;My lump in my mouth gotthe all clear on Tuesday night, it’s a benign bone growth
and can be removed if it causes any issue in the future. Julia and I come out
relieved and now I can focus on her properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday was a scary day the first chemotherapy session - a daunting prospect.
Julia slept terribly the night before and so did I. She woke me by crashing round
like the rolling waves of a storm. I’d had enough and suggested that we watch
something instead of huffing and puffing about not being asleep. So, it’s 4am and we
are watching Hebbern, it’s funny, we laugh and then I fall asleep. Julia is not
so lucky and wrestles with things for a while longer before sleep claims her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning we head off for the chemotherapy and it surprises us. It all
seems so ordinary, they plug Julia into the machine via her port (it reminds me
of the matrix) and after a couple hours of flushing the port, chemotherapy drugs
and flushing again we head home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s back to hospital for a round of a complimentary drug called Herceptin.
It’s a biological therapy that specifically targets the HER2 positive cancer
that Julia has. As Julia kept the needle in her port overnight the treatment
quickly starts. Once administered we have to hang round for 5 hours to make
sure there are no side effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia passes the time watching day time tv and on the Gin Club photo challenge - sorting
out the Gin Club photo albumn into date order.  Julia writes an email to my work
thanking them for being ace - I’m truly lucky to work for such a great and
understanding company. I spend the time baking next to the radiator and escaping
into my computer by watching another round of lectures and coding for the
course I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before we leave Julia gets a course in injecting herself with a booster
and then graduates by doing it. She’s a gutsy lady my Mrs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get home tired, the kids all play up and get a shouting at. Unfortunately, my mum
copped a shouting too when she complained about all the noise! Talk about
timing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening I head to the pub for a few beers with my Dad and Neil, we
talk cancer for a while as I update Neil and answer his questions and then we
dive into the normal pub talk - absolute rot and covering all subjects.  It’s
great to escape for a while and be normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a slight headache! Nothing too bad and my parents deliver the kids to
school whilst I work. They’ve been great this week and it’s been good to have
them on hand. They then head off for the day to see some friends nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia looks flushed today and I worry why that might be and she has a
slight temperature. She brushes it off and heads for coffee with Ginnies. She
still looks flushed when I get home, I take her tempurature and it’s up a little
so I’m now watching that. She rests up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia has a chemotherapy book recording her treatment that she has to have on
hand at all times.  In it there are certain directives about what you should do
if you feel ill or have a temperature or aches etc. It’s serious stuff the
medicines they give you today are strong and targetted. They stop all cells from
splitting and reproducing, leaving your immune system highly vulnerable to
infection, so vigulance is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have pizza for tea and then it’s Imogen’s gymnastics. She does great and
impresses granny by being able to do the splits. I drink a coffee and then pay
for it later when I can’t sleep. Julia heads to bed early, I take her temperature
again and it now is over 37.5C her book says I should call the nurse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia thinks I’m fussing but the nurse says she’ll speak to consultant and
comes back to me. As it’s so early on in treatment paracetamol is advised and
we’ll review tomorrow morning, if it’s still up they’ll have her in for blood tests.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hospitals-waiting-and-warm-radiators&quot;&gt;Hospitals - waiting and warm radiators&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 23, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Herceptin treatment starts]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/herceptin-treatment-starts" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/herceptin-treatment-starts</id>
  <published>2013-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I slept much better last night.  And I'm so relieved.  I suppose it's because I'd already done everything yesterday, same again today, just different drugs.&lt;p&gt;The drugs are administered, and it’s all fine.  Once I’m finished they need to keep an eye on me as I could have a reaction to the Herceptin, so we wait for a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this time, I’m given more steroids to take to reduce the chances of sickness over the next 3 days. I also have a lesson in injecting myself with an immunity boosting syringe.  That was quite odd.  All the times I’ve had needles stuck in me over the past 6 weeks or so, it’s always been someone else doing it, so I can look away and let them get on with it.  Not so this one, I have to actually stick it in myself.  I had a practice run with a dummy needle and a stress ball, then it was time for the main show.  There was an awkward pause whilst I took a deep breath, steeled myself and went for it.  Luckily it was fine.  The nurse was happy with my attempt and I’ll be trusted to do it unsupervised in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have my port site checked and they are also pleased that’s healed sufficiently so it looks like I’ll be able to have a bath tonight. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the designated time we were told they were happy, and we could go.  Before long we are home sitting down to lasagna with the bairns and grandparents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After tea, and a catch up on Pointless, I have my aforementioned bath, and then it’s off to bed.  It’s been a long couple of days, and I need to make sure I rest.  Ross goes to the pub.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/herceptin-treatment-starts&quot;&gt;Herceptin treatment starts&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 21, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The chemo starts]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/z-the-chemo-starts" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/z-the-chemo-starts</id>
  <published>2013-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I managed another hour of sleep before I needed to get up and get ready to leave for the hospital.&lt;p&gt;Luckily, granny and grandad were on hand to get the bairns organised and to breakfast club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There had been an accident on the A1, so the trusty sat nav sent us different way to the hospital.  We get stuck in a bit of traffic around Hitchin, which makes us nervous, but we arrive in time and are soon settled into our room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurses are very efficient and before long I’m hooked up to a drip, being pumped with saline, anti sickness drugs, and then the main feature, the chemo drugs.  Note to self, go to the loo before being hooked up to the machine.  It’s a Faff otherwise.  A few hours later, I’m detached, and sent on my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way home we pop to Argos and pick up a few Christmas presents.  It’s good to feel like we’re doing something positive for Christmas.  The timing of the treatments suck, but needs must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home, we have lunch and then I try for a nap to catch up on some sleep.  I manage about 45 mins but then the bairns come in from school and want to check I’m ok after my treatment.  I’ve still got a line attached to my port as I’m back to the hospital tomorrow to start my Herceptin treatment, so they were interested in having a look at it.  I’m looking forward to having it taken out tomorrow and also the steri strips removed and dressing changed so that I can have a proper shower and bath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be having an early night tonight and trying to actually sleep through most of it.  Last night was no fun.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/z-the-chemo-starts&quot;&gt;The chemo starts&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 20, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who needs sleep?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/who-needs-sleep" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/who-needs-sleep</id>
  <published>2013-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">5:45am and I've been awake since before 2am.  After tossing and turning for ages, Ross woke up and suggested that I give up on sleep and read or watch something.&lt;p&gt;He was fully awake by this point, so he watched last nights episode of Hebburn with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then talked about how grossly unfair this all was.  I can’t understand why the Cancer decided to have a go at me.  I realise I’m in danger of wallowing in self pity or worse slipping into depression, but I can’t help thinking ‘why me?’  What did I do to deserve this?  I also know that it’s just an unfortunate situation that is a result of chance and bad luck. Unfortunately the former is winning over the latter at the moment despite my stoicism and pragmatism, and until I learn to accept it, I will struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross managed to go back to sleep.  He needs as much sleep as he can get too.  Luckily as Ross’s parents are here, they are able to pick up the slack with things like cooking and looking after the bairns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen has told me she’s a little bit worried about my first chemo treatment and she is going to tell her teacher so they can offer her some support. I’m so glad she’s confident enough to do that, she is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix asked if my hair would fall out straight away.  I think he was disappointed when I said no.  Felix doesn’t really understand what’s going on, so he focuses on the bits he does understand.  Bald heads he can relate to.  Ross has one after all!  If he sees tangible evidence like dressings, or scars, he can relate to that. He’s had and got those himself!  He’s asked to feel the Big Lump and the implanted port catheter, they are real and physical, but he doesn’t understand the implications of them all.  To be honest, no 5 year old, or 7 year old for that matter, should have to watch a parent fight this battle.  It’s not fair on them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On hair loss related news, I had a wig delivered.  I don’t like it.  I’m going to have to go to a wig shop and try some on.  The problem I have is, I have quite a small head, small forehead and a widow’s peak.  So to get a wig that sits right will prove tricky.  My wonderful hairdresser is going to see if there’s anything she can do with the internet wig, so at least I have a backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to try for another hour of sleep now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shall return.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/who-needs-sleep&quot;&gt;Who needs sleep?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 20, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perfect Heart]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/perfect-heart" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/perfect-heart</id>
  <published>2013-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">According to the ECG today, not only do I have a heart, (in your face doubters), I've got a perfect one.&lt;p&gt;Woot.  In fact, despite having cancer, all the various health checks I’ve had recently tell me I’m actually in pretty good shape.  This is good news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it’s all go for the chemo and herceptin on Wednesday and Thursday.  I’m feeling quite calm about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was driving to work this this morning, David Guetta’s Titanium came on.  “Shoot me down, but I won’t fall, I am Titanium”.  That’s me!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/perfect-heart&quot;&gt;Perfect Heart&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 18, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>