<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2014-04-12T18:03:37+01:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happiness and Sadness]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happiness-and-sadness" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happiness-and-sadness</id>
  <published>2014-04-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This week has passed in a haze with the bairns and my Dad being around whilst I've been convalescing.  They've pottered around, in and out and it's been great.&lt;p&gt;On Friday we went to see the consultant to have a review.  I’ve been in quite a lot of pain, not surprising when he drained over 400ml of fluid from my wounds.  Ouchie!
However, despite that, we came away delighted.  After they’d done the surgery, the tissue which was removed was sent to be analysed to see if there was any cancer remaining after the initial round of chemotherapy.  We’d know that it could be an option, but we hadn’t dared hope.  We also knew that regardless of whether there was or not, the surgery was always going to happen.  Trials have proven that even with a total pathological reaction to chemo, the cancer is very likely to come back.  My odds have always with this cancer sucked, so not having surgery was never an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here we are, Cancer free.  Woo hoo!  It’s not quite the end of the road yet.  I’ve still got another round of chemo to go, as well radiotherapy, and biological treatments.  I’ll be on medication for 5-10 years, but we’re over half way through.  I think the next lot of chemo will be tough as it is different to the last round, and will make me very sick.  I’ll lose my newly grown sprouts of hair again, but that doesn’t matter.  I’m here, and the treatment is working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve added a few things to my to do list: sort the garden, stain/paint some furniture, do a 10k run, do a Race for life Pretty Muddy, and do a triathlon.  What’s to stop me?  Only my own mental attitude.  At least that’s on my side!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dad has gone home now, and we’ll miss him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another sadness has been a shadow of family politics hanging over us since I first started chemo.  It keeps Ross awake at night, it causes arguments between us and ultimately it’s not helping us on our road to getting my little family through this awful time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All it will take is a simple “I’m sorry”, but it seems that is too much to ask.  Ross and I are going through the worst part of our lives together and to have to deal with this anxiety too, is exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in order to keep the peace, I’m going to have to accept that I am not going to get the apology.  My feelings are going to have to take a back seat for the Greater Good of a happy family.  I can’t watch Ross be torn in two over this, and he means more to me than my pride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happiness-and-sadness&quot;&gt;Happiness and Sadness&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 12, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pathology]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/pathology" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/pathology</id>
  <published>2014-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today we made the journey back to see the Oncologist today&lt;p&gt;The pathology is in and guess what? The chemotherapy worked!  There was no trace of cancer in the nodes and no cancer in the breast.  This is called a complete pathological response and is &lt;em&gt;really really&lt;/em&gt; good news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment won’t change, the mastectomy was still required and the current plan for another round of chemotherapy and radiotherapy still stand.  They are the belt and braces to ensure Julia’s healthy future. So we have some rocky days ahead but this the best news!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/pathology&quot;&gt;Pathology&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 11, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impasse]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/impasse" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/impasse</id>
  <published>2014-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This post has been such a long time coming but before I start I want to revisit the reason for this blog.&lt;p&gt;This blog was setup to act as a form of writing therapy, to help Julia and I through our emotions and to deal with the situation head on. All in the hope that one day when Julia is cancer free and cancer treatment has finished that we will come out of it stronger. The idea is that any issues will have been tackled head on, so that we can move on and enjoy the rest of lives in freedom. Freedom from the fear of cancer and freedom from any hangover of the truama of the treatment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, Imogen and Felix will be old enough to read this blog and I hope it will help give them perspective and understand their place in a journey they unwittingly went through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been one large emission from the blog, which because of family politics, I’ve kept it silent and bottled it up. It is the reason I am so often awake in the dark of the night and I can’t sleep because my mind whirls. I now realise it does this because I haven’t written about it and I haven’t given it a place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in November, after I spent a day in A&amp;amp;E with Julia who was having heart pains (the day after starting chemotherapy and herceptin), I was stressed. I reacted badly to some comments from my mum and then blogged about it. The post was supposed to be about how there’s no guidebook on how to handle someone going through Cancer treatment and how people react differently. I hurt my mum writing that post and I got an angry email telling me so. I apologised, redacted the post and wrote a new post apologising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The angry email back also took a swipe at Julia and I can understand lashing out when angry, we all do it. What I don’t understand is that after pointing out that it hurt Julia repeatedly, there has been no apology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Months have rolled by and communication has been in fits and starts but there’s always been an underlying tension. Any emails about the argument have fallen on deaf ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I had a call from my Dad asking if he and mum can come and visit to see Julia after her surgery. I had to tell him at present they aren’t welcome and saying that breaks my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a night of no sleep, wrestling with the futility of the situation, when I needed support the most, the stupidity of words spoken in anger have got in the way.  We have been stuck at an impasse for too long and we may not be able to control if Julia gets her apology but we can control how we deal with this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have to put it behind us, it’s damaging rather than healing. There are bigger things to deal with and a we deserve a positive future ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/impasse&quot;&gt;Impasse&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 09, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Makeup Selfies]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/no-makeup-selfies" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/no-makeup-selfies</id>
  <published>2014-04-06T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It's 3am and I can't sleep.&lt;p&gt;I’ve had trippy dreams and have been sleepwalking.  In an effort to try and wait until the painkillers work, I’ve been reading a few articles on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found one retweeted by The Cancer Survivors Club (@cancer_buzz) and it made me a bit cross.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-2595450/These-selfies-make-livid-Why-cancer-survivor-JENNI-MURRAY-angry-stars-helped-raise-millions-posting-photos-no-make-up.html&quot;&gt;These selfies make me livid: Why cancer survivor JENNI MURRAY is angry with the stars who have helped raise millions by posting photos of themselves with no make-up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upshot is, that the author is a breast cancer survivor who thinks that the whole No makeup selfie thing is all about self promotion first, charity second, and that it in no way relates to how women who are going through breast cancer are feeling about their situation and their looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what?  I don’t care.  I don’t care if someone took 24 pictures of themselves with no make up on before they found one that didn’t look as bad as the others.  I don’t care if they had special lighting, or specially tousled hair.  Did they donate to a cancer charity?  That’s the bit I care about.  Because that part matters to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posting a picture of yourself on social media with no makeup on in no way compares with someone having no hair, looking grey from chemo.  Or with someone who has had life saving surgery but been left physically altered.  Does anyone really think it does?  I don’t think people are that ignorant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends and family have seen me at rock bottom looks wise.  Not just after getting up early and being all puffy eyed from lack of sleep on a camping trip. Or hungover to high heaven. I’m talking after months of relentless chemo.  Days after surgery.  And they’ll see me there again before I come out the other side.  Do they think the No Makeup Selfie equates to what I’ve been going through?  I doubt it.  They’re not stupid.  But some of them have done it.  Why?  So they can raise awareness of Breast Cancer and do something to feel useful.  Others have simply, quietly donated something.  Others still, have shared a link on how to check yourself for Breast Cancer.  All really useful stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my perspective, the No Makeup selfie has been a good thing.  It’s raised awareness and money.  I don’t see who the losers are here.  It’s not me.  I’ve got a great team behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/no-makeup-selfies&quot;&gt;No Makeup Selfies&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 06, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Worry, woes and welcome homes]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/worry-woes-and-welcome-homes" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/worry-woes-and-welcome-homes</id>
  <published>2014-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Last Sunday was mothers day and this year it felt that it had felt like it had extra special meaning.&lt;p&gt;The kids and I tried to spoil Mummy and make her day as best we could. This was quite tricky as the shadow of Mondays pending surgery was heavy and at times overwhelming. The Sunday night feeling was terrible!  However,  Grandad Mikes arrival was most welcome and helped brighten the mood. It was great to have him over and know that I can focus on Julia’s needs this week as the kids would be covered.  Thank you Grandad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surgery day inevitably arrives even though sleep was fleeting and all to soon it’s up and at them. Julia &amp;amp; Mike take the kids to school while I try and do some work. Its hard to concentrate so I focus on easy housekeeping type work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Text messages come in during the morning from friends and these help keep spirits up.  Julia’s facebook has exploded with well wishes and its hard to quantify how much these help and spur us on but thank you all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrive at the hospital on time and after the obligatory wait (we are in a hospital after all!) things happen quickly enough and I walk Julia to the operating theatre. The next few hours drag and I fret, work is out of the question as I can’t focus on anything, so I watch netflix. Four hours later Julia is wheeled back into her room. She’s a nauseous shade of grey, cold and clammy and still high from the anesthetic and the morphine. After a while she’s sick and slowly colour returns. Mr Crane the surgeon pops by and tells us everything went perfectly and he was also able to work round Julia’s Chemotherapy port. After a while I head off home to get some food and let people know that surgery went well and Julia is on the mend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its fantastic to think that Julia is now Cancer free! The rest of the treatment is belt and braces and that will take another 6 months to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the week, I’m generally at the hospital for 9am and spend the day there working and keeping Julia company. Julia brightens to see the kids Tuesday evening and friends visit on Wednesday. However, for some reason Julia is still very nauseous and struggles to eat - there’s not much I can do about it but it makes me anxious. The anti-sickness medication keeps going up but Julia still struggles to eat and keep food down. She’s also suffering from extreme headaches also making her feel nauseous and what’s hardest for me is theres no apparent cause of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday is a low day, I take Mike over in the morning but Julia is too ill to see friends in the afternoon and is struggling. I worry that she won’t make it home on Friday as she wants. Her drains from the surgery especially the one from the node clearance side are still filling full of fluid. There has to be 50 ml or less in a day to be ok for release. Extra painkillers, and anti sickness get her through the day. By this point I’m exhausted and really hope for some good news friday morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huzzah! 52ml in the drain - all good Julia can come home! She looks happier and taking bucket loads of anti sickness medication is helping, choosing the mushroom and bacon soup for lunch was not though! The drains are removed and the Mr Crane pops by and is happy that things are healing well and Julia can go home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huzzah! We get home and that night after we get the kids to bed, I take Mike for a couple of beers at the Orange Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/worry-woes-and-welcome-homes&quot;&gt;Worry, woes and welcome homes&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 05, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[55378008]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/55378008" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/55378008</id>
  <published>2014-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I'm home after 5 days in hospital.&lt;p&gt;The operation went well but as happened last time, the anaesthetic made me sick.  A theme that has continued since.  I’m still taking anti sickness tablets in an effort to try and eat, but coupled with painkiller induced constipation, my digestive system isn’t my best friend at the minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I came round from the operation, the rest of Monday was spent in a drug induced haze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s funny, as you are supposed to rest in hospital, but I was getting woken at midnight to have my drains emptied (600ml in total for the week), then at 6:30 to have blood pressure, temp and pulse taken and to have drugs, then 7:30 for breakfast, obs taken and drugs given regularly through the day with the last one occurring at 10pm, although the last lot of drugs might come an hour later.  Then you have all the extra visitors of housekeeping, catering, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was a drug induced haze too, but I got to see the physio who gave me exercises to ensure mobility returns to my arms, the consultant who wanted to check I was doing ok, and my bairns!  Ross brought them to see me and I was over the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, I had a few Gin Club visitors, but by Thursday I was starting to feel unwell again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visitors were cancelled on Thursday and I spent the majority of the day throwing up.  It wasn’t pleasant.  Luckily at that point they decided the anti sickness tablets weren’t working very well so I was given an injection which seemed to do the trick for a short time at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Friday, my drains had stopped collecting large amounts of fluid, and it was decided that they could be removed.  Yippee!  After a quick chat with the consultant, and a bagful of drugs I was released, and got home just as the bairns were getting home from school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it all went a bit odd.  The bairns, who had been so good all week, turned into whinging wailing monsters!  It was quite absurd.  There was snot, tears and gnashing of teeth!  Felix didn’t eat all of his dinner so didn’t get a pudding.  End of the world.  After tea, Imogen was sent to get changed for gymnastics, but put her leotard on the wrong way round.  End of the world.  I asked Imogen to put a hoodie on to go to gymnastics.  End if the world.  I asked Felix to stop asking about going on the iPad, as he wasn’t allowed.  End if the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross took Imogen to gymnastics and left my dad and me with Felix.  More wailing, and throwing of his stool around.  Great.  He stewed for a bit, and I told him he could have a cuddle if he wanted after he got his pj’s on.  Five minutes later he was downstairs, in his pj’s and had cuddles.  Nice cuddles.  Careful cuddles.  Like a new boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier Caroline had popped round and we’d mentioned their behaviour, and she said she thought it could be a release of emotions for them.  They’ve been so worried all week, and now I’m home, and everything is ok, they just let it all out.  I think she’s right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got lots of time now to get things back on track.  And we will.  I just need lots of rest as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.s.  55378008 - put it in a calculator and turn it upsidedown.  It’s the current state of affairs.  The new normal.  For now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/55378008&quot;&gt;55378008&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on April 05, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mother's Day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mothers-day" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mothers-day</id>
  <published>2014-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today was lovely, and I felt very spoilt.&lt;p&gt;I was presented with a tray full of cards, plants and a cup of coffee in bed by my wonderful bairns.  No less than 4 from Imogen!  I was allowed to stay in bed a little bit longer before I was told to get up to go to rugby training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was great watching them both run round in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was home to get them bathed and Ross cooked a lovely roast dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix helped me pack my case for hospital and we had lots of cuddles.  It’s going to be hard for them this week with me being away.  Grandad will be holding the fort so that Ross can be with me.  We are lucky to have such support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/mothers-day&quot;&gt;Mother's Day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 30, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Anniversary]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happy-anniversary" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happy-anniversary</id>
  <published>2014-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Today is our 9th wedding anniversary.&lt;p&gt;Ross has gone into London for work, and I’m looking after the children as there’s a teachers strike.  Hopefully we’ll all meet up later and go for a curry for tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had things gone to plan, I’d be recovering from a mastectomy and Axillary Node Clearance.  As it happens the surgery has been postponed until next Monday as my medical team needed to do some research to decide whether it would be worth doing a risk reducing mastectomy on the other side as well.    We met with him yesterday and he’s agreed to do it.  The surgeon said he would normally send women in my position to a plastic surgeon, a geneticist and a psychologist.  He said none were relevant in my case.  I told him that my boobs have done what they need to do, fed both bairns for over a year each, and as they are now trying to kill me, I’m not interested in trying to save them.  Every year I would be going for a mammogram, and waiting for them to tell me it had come back.  I don’t need that.  I don’t want that.  I can change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now I’ll be going in on Monday, and having a bilateral mastectomy with Node Clearance.  I need to pack my hospital bag and get myself sorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s going to be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happy-anniversary&quot;&gt;Happy Anniversary&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 26, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good to be home]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/good-to-be-home" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/good-to-be-home</id>
  <published>2014-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">We're back, and the washing machine is earning it's keep!&lt;p&gt;My overwhelming memory from the holiday is the feeling of pride I have for my little family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen - determined.  She scrambled up the indoor climbing wall easily, and was quickly tackling harder routes.  The Cyclone ride in the pool posed no issue.  Ross and I were screaming but Imogen just grinned and laughed.  Her swimming in the pool was effortless, and she went down all the slides too many times to count.  When bowling she refused any offers of help, and she managed to beat me every time.  With the adventure golf too, she refused help, and tried her best.  The pottery painting was her idea, and she produced a colourful dragon money box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix - strong.  He has only really got to grips with riding his bike in the past few months, but he had plenty opportunities to practice.  And he was amazing.  He cycled everywhere, and when he couldn’t ring his bell to signal he was ok, he’d shout “It’s on the other side.”  It took Ross and I a while to work out why he was shouting this, but it turns out it was because his bell had turned itself round so it was on the other side of the handlebars.  His swimming was great in the pool.  It would have been a very different holiday had he not been able to swim.  But swim he did.  Most of the time he was out of his depth, and he was able to go down all the slides on his own apart from the Cyclone because he was just too short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross - hero.  I’m not quite back up to full energy, so the full itinerary of activities meant there wasn’t much leftover for the normal day to day stuff.  But Ross took up all the slack. He did the cooking and organising and took the kids off by himself so I could rest when necessary.  He is amazing, and I’m lucky to have him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, they all rock, and I love them all very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/good-to-be-home&quot;&gt;Good to be home&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 23, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magical Memories]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/magical-memories" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/magical-memories</id>
  <published>2014-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">We've been at Center Parcs for four days now, and we've had a superb time.&lt;p&gt;We’ve cycled everywhere and been swimming every day.  The kids have been on the indoor climbing wall, and as a family we’ve been bowling twice, eaten out a few times, spent a fortune at the amusements, played ping pong and pool, painted pottery, played crazy golf and went on an aerial tree adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s our first holiday here, and I can safely say, we’ll be back.  It’s been so wonderful, and we’ve laughed and smiled pretty much permanently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve managed to keep going most of the time, but I think I’ll need to catch up on some sleep when I get back.  I wouldn’t change it for the world.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/magical-memories&quot;&gt;Magical Memories&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 20, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holidays]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/holidays" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/holidays</id>
  <published>2014-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It's been a while&lt;p&gt;I’ve been busy steering good ship Lawley and whilst I’ve been meaning to write a post I haven’t found the time.  Happily, today I woke at 3:33am after not sleeping well at all, so rather than fight it I thought I’d get up and do something until tireness comes back and I can sleep some more.  The good things are a) that’s not normal, I usually sleep well and b) we’re all going on holiday to Center Parcs in a few hours. The Lawley family are ridiculously excited about this! Before that though, I think it’s high time to digest whats been happening over the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia has been off the chemotherapy for a while now and she is bouncing back.  She’s been getting frustrated, as with less fatigue comes the will to do more and then she tires herself out and feels bad about it. What she doesn’t realise is how much more she is doing now compared to a month ago. It’s encouraging but this is a long haul journey and the fact there is another round of chemo on the horizon isn’t too far from our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big news of the week has been the genetic test. It came back with a hit and I wasn’t surprised, it helps explains what before was unexplainable - why Julia? The operation will now be bigger, but there are upsides, we won’t be living in fear that the cancer will appear in the other breast and when reconstruction happens Julia will have a matching pair of new knockers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia took the news hard and saw it as another bad thing to happen to her. Which is understandable, especially as it might have repercussions for the children but the future is a way away and we must live in the present and deal with the here and now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to highlight some of the positives to come out of this all (you have to choose your moments for doing this as part of being supportive is just listening but part of being a man is trying to fix all the things™).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big positive is there is treatment, drugs, therapies and years of experience in this field. It is accounting for something and that collective medical expertise will kill Julia’s cancer.  In just a couple of weeks time Julia should be cancer free the rest of the treatment will be the final clean up operation to ensure that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second chances. Not everyone gets one but in a way Julia has. It’s awful whats happened and I can’t deny that but as awful and traumatic as it has been the treatment will finish and a new normal will occur. That’s the second chance.  I’ve been encouraging Julia to focus on what she wants to get out of life and then to go for it.  The future isn’t written and no one knows how long their own might be so&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose your future, choose life, fuck cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/holidays&quot;&gt;Holidays&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 17, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm oh so tired]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/oh-so-tired" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/oh-so-tired</id>
  <published>2014-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I didn't make it to Anna's on Friday night.  I had a bath and was asleep by 9pm.&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I went to watch the kids have their swimming lesson.  Imogen’s teacher came to  wish us a lovely holiday and gave us a few handy hints on what to do whilst we are at Center Parcs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she’d gone the woman who was sat beside me said, “I couldn’t help overhearing, is it the Easter holidays you are going?” When I said, no it was Monday she asked if my daughter was at school.  I responded by saying both my children were at school, and she asked, rather incredulously, “and the school are ok with that?”.  Now, the swimming pool is hot, and I was sat with my baldy head out.  She clearly hadn’t joined the dots.  I turned to look at her and said, “I’m having treatment for breast cancer.  We’ve had precious little quality time as a family since my diagnosis, and thankfully the school has agreed that these are exceptional circumstances.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest I was a bit stunned by this exchange.  This woman was judging me for taking my kids out of school.  Believe me, it wasn’t a decision that we took lightly, but the children have been under a lot of stress recently.  It manifests itself in a few different ways.  Tantrums, bed wetting, nightmares, etc.  Imogen and Felix deserve a few days away with their parents to make some magical memories before having more treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I crashed on the sofa for the rest of the day.  I hope I have more energy for the holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was spent watching rugby training, and then getting organised for holiday.  I can’t wait.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/oh-so-tired&quot;&gt;I'm oh so tired&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 16, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Normal?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/normal" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/normal</id>
  <published>2014-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I'm back at the leisure centre where I've written a few of these blog posts.&lt;p&gt;It’s been an odd week.  After getting the genetic test results and then speaking to the oncologist we’ve had a lot to think about.  The CHEK2 gene mutation has been known about in the genetic circles for over ten years but it’s not routinely tested for and as a result there’s no clear guidelines as to how to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke to my surgeon and he needs to discuss with the multidisciplinary team to decide the best way forward.  It’s not unreasonable in these circumstances to have a risk reducing mastectomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ve been trying to gauge how I feel about the double.  To be honest, if it’s going to mean I’ve a better chance keeping this horrible disease at bay, then I’ll have it.  It’s a no brainer really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s been as normal a day as I’ve had in a while.  I took the bairns to school.  I went to a gin club coffee morning at Lesley’s, then Ross and I did a supermarket shop.  I had a nap, and the did the school run, and made tea.  We’ve come to the leisure centre to watch Imogen do gymnastics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m supposed to be going to my Gin Club friend, Anna’s house tonight for drinks, but I’m not sure I’ll make it.  I’m tired.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/normal&quot;&gt;Normal?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 14, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curve Ball]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/curve-ball" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/curve-ball</id>
  <published>2014-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">They say bad things come in three's.  Well, I've just heard what the third one is.&lt;p&gt;When I first found Big Lump, it wasn’t supposed to be cancer.  I’m too young to get cancer.  Unfortunately, it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, we had the Sentinal Node Biopsy, to establish whether it had spread.  Everything indicated to it being contained.  It hadn’t, it had spread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up, the genetic test.  Was I just a one off freak, or a genetic freak who could pass this horrible disease to my children, and also have implications for my close family.  Sadly, the latter is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a mutation in the CHEK2. It’s not even the normal breast cancer gene that everyone is talking about at the minute with the Carol Jackson story in Eastenders, BRCA 1/2.  (I’m not watching it though, I can’t deal with someone else’s fictional drama at the minute).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gene mutation is classed as medium risk.  The BRCA gene is classed as high risk, so I can be thankful for some things.  It’s been shown to increase the risk of breast cancer, as well as colon cancer and prostate cancer in men.   The reason I was checked for this gene, is that it was done privately on Ross’s works health insurance.  The nhs would only have checked for the BRCA one, and even then they may not have agreed to carry out the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I had the test, it’s thrown up an issue, now to deal with it.  In the short term, this may be the difference between a single or double mastectomy.  My Oncologist says that given the results, it’s not a case if they remove the other side, but when.  I need to see my surgeon this week before we go on holiday and see if he’ll agree to do it all together.  We then need to see if the insurance company will agree to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the longer term, its going to mean things get shaken up a bit.  It’s going to be time to grab life by the balls and live it.  No more stagnating.  No more treading water.  And the first thing I’m going to do once I’m able to, is start singing again.  Join a choir and gain back some confidence I lost a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cancer, I’m not going to fight you, I’m not a warrior, I’m just little me.  But I’m going to have every treatment they offer me so I can get rid of you, so I can have my life back.  A life with my husband and bairns that you think I don’t deserve.  Back off.   I’m prepared to sacrifice all sorts here, starting with, but not limited to my hair and both boobs.  Don’t think you’ve won because I’ve said I won’t fight, you haven’t, the outcome will be the same for you.   I suppose it’s just semantics.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/curve-ball&quot;&gt;Curve Ball&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 10, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tired]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/tired" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/tired</id>
  <published>2014-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It's been two weeks since my last chemo.&lt;p&gt;Things have been slowly getting back to normal.  I’ve watched the bairns swimming lessons and Imogen’s gymnastics for the first time in months.  I’ve watched them play rugby in the freezing cold at the rugby club.  I’ve driven to the office.  I’ve had the Gin Club round for birthday drinks, and it’s been great.  But I’ve noticed that the fatigue is still hanging around.  If I have a busy day, the next day will normally involve a nap.  I’m still not sleeping well, so that’s having an impact.  But it’s going I the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been getting lots of messages of support.  They really do mean a lot to Ross and I.  I have to admit being disappointed in some people, but have to accept everyone will react in different ways to this sort of thing.  We are relying on a lot of support at the minute, and in the words of Billy Ocean, “When the going gets tough, the tough get going.”  Thank you to everyone who has helped out, in any way, shape or form.  It’s very much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in other news, it’s my Dad’s birthday today.  Happy birthday Dad. X&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/tired&quot;&gt;Tired&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 02, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm frightened]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-fear" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-fear</id>
  <published>2014-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I've spent so long trying to be strong and positive, I've surprised myself a little bit today by giving in to The Fear.&lt;p&gt;The Fear that I’ll not beat this Cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear that if I beat it this time around that it’ll come back, and I won’t be able to fight it a second time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear that I could die and not watch my bairns grow up into the fantastic people I know they will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear of leaving Ross to handle things without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent today in bed again today, too exhausted to do much except watch tv and read and I don’t doubt that The Fear is related to this exhaustion.  There’s been lots of tears.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-fear&quot;&gt;I'm frightened&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 17, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of Round One]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/end-of-round-one" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/end-of-round-one</id>
  <published>2014-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I finished my first lot of chemotherapy today.  Yay!&lt;p&gt;I started my chemotherapy journey on November 20th with a drug called Docetaxel which I was supposed to have 4 times on a three week cycle.  4 days after having it for the first time, I was in A&amp;amp;E with undiagnosed chest pains.  My oncologist changed it to a drug called Paclitaxel which I was to have weekly for 9 weeks which finished today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so pleased, as I’m so tired.  I’m looking forward to having some energy back again.  I’m looking forward to being able to watch the bairns swimming lessons and their rugby practice.  I’m looking forward to Gin Club coffee mornings.  And I’m looking forward to going away as a family and spending some quality time together before Round Two starts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Round Two is the surgery which will take 4-6 weeks to recover from.  I had a good chat today with the Breast Care Nurse at the hospital and she gave me a lot of information about Post Surgery bras, prothesis, and how I can expect to to look and feel afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Round Three is more chemotherapy.  This time a treatment called FEC which is three different drugs.  I’ll have 3 or 4 of these treatments on a three week cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Round Four will be 15-18 daily sessions of radiotherapy at a hospital in North West London.  We don’t have a hospital which is convenient for this treatment which is a bit of a pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timeline of all of this is taking us to July/August time.  It’s quite epic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still need to have my Herceptin treatment every three weeks, so I’ll have another one of those on March 7th.  A slightly longer gap after surgery, with a break for FEC and starting again afterwards for another 7-10 treatments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point I need to restart my 5-10 year course of Hormone therapy which has been stopped in the interim.  I’m quite glad as it causes horrid hot flushes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, none of this is actually set in stone.  What I know for sure is that all the rounds are happening, and in which order.  What we don’t know is exactly when.  The results of the genetic screening could dictate more radical surgery, and that may not happen on March 24th which is when it’s provisionally booked for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross and I have come to realise that having control of your life and having the ability to make plans is just an illusion.  We’ve had the rug pulled out from underneath us and we can’t really see more than 5 weeks ahead.  In fact, I can’t make plans for next week as I don’t know how tired this last lot of chemo will make me.  The illusion has been shattered and you can never tell what is round the corner to throw you off balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we’ve got to be positive and be glad that we’ve got each other in our little family.  Imogen and a Felix got glowing reports from their teachers at parents evening and Ross and I are so proud.  With everything that is going in, they still manage to be normal kids, doing normal things at school.  I love them to the moon and back.  Their resilience awes me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are lucky to have the support of good friends who understand how even the simplest  things can make all the difference.  And Creme Eggs.  They really do make a difference (although my waistline isn’t thanking me!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s looking forward to a brief return to normality. And my birthday which is on Tuesday.  And a Gin a Club a Girls Night In.  I’m really looking forward to that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/end-of-round-one&quot;&gt;End of Round One&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 14, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY Dad]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/diy-dad" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/diy-dad</id>
  <published>2014-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I would have written this post before now, but the chemo session I had on Friday has had me pretty much bed bound for 4 days.&lt;p&gt;Ross went to Dublin on Monday 2nd Feb, and at lunchtime my Dad arrived to steer the Lawley ship in his absence.  He did a super job of making sure the kids, cats and I  were fed and watered, the bairns got to and from school and after school groups on time, and kept the litter tray tidy.  He also found time to do a few DIY jobs round the house and garden.  I was chauffeured to my hospital appointments and he sat with me when I had my chemo.  I wasn’t much company, as soon as they give me the Piriton, I fell asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, Ross hopped over the Atlantic to New York for a couple of days, and late Friday I had word he was on his way home.  He arrived back to us just as Dad was taking the bairns to their swimming lesson on Saturday morning.  I was sad when Dad left on Saturday afternoon, but realise Julie needs him too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so lucky to have two utterly dependable men in my life.  Thank you Dad, thank you Ross.  (And thank you Julie for letting me borrow him for a short while.)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/diy-dad&quot;&gt;DIY Dad&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 12, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A tale of two cities]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-tale-of-two-cities" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-tale-of-two-cities</id>
  <published>2014-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Dublin and New York in a week.&lt;p&gt;Its been a week, lots of travel and catching up with people from work. Its been great, its been tough, its been fun and at times it sucked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dublin&quot;&gt;Dublin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good to see folks in the office - last time I was there was before the bump turned out to be cancer. There was lots of “how’s Julia?” which was a double edged sword, describing what has happening in the last few months again and again took its toll but equally it was good as showed that people care. I wasn’t overly in a drinking mood so I ducked out of the big drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On tuesday it was the european company meeting, which was both fun and informative.  In the afternoon there was a Casino Royale social - brilliantly cheesy and fun. I played blackjack for hours, made and lost millions and somehow I still managed to sneak onto the final winners table and ended up coming third.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was some chance that a snow storm would disrupt travel to New York, it did but only by an hour.  Julia and I were secretly hoping that my flight would be cancelled and I could come home…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-york&quot;&gt;New York&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New York was cold, a snow storm had hit earlier in the week it was still snowy.  I enjoyed a walk round central park Thursday morning before a day of meetings. Time went quickly and it was soon time to head on home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the taxi to the airport, I suddenly realised I had left my passport in the hotel safe. PANIC. I’m such an idiot. Luckily, I always leave loads of time to get to the airport and we had time to turn round and head back to the hotel.  Friday evening in Manhattan isn’t the best time for traffic, so it took what felt like an age. At one point I left the taxi with all my bags in it and ran a couple of blocks to the hotel to get my passport.  By the time I got it, the taxi was out front of the hotel and we headed off to the airport. All in all it cost me an extra hour but I made it to the airport with time to spare and once through security I had a beer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning and I finally made it back home! Thanks to Mike for looking after Julia.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-tale-of-two-cities&quot;&gt;A tale of two cities&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 07, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tears and tantrums]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/tears-and-tantrums" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/tears-and-tantrums</id>
  <published>2014-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This week has had both good and bad parts - rollercoaster does it justice.&lt;p&gt;I’m sitting in Terminal 1 at Heathrow waiting for a flight to Dublin for a couple of days of meetings and then I’m off to New York for a couple more. I’m ridiculously early for my flight as I managed to get a lift from Dan rather than fighting through 3 different trains during rush hour.  Thanks Dan, your knowledge of the eddies and flow of the M25 traffic is impressive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I’ve aged a lot in the last week and yesterday there were tears. The difference a week off chemo has made is huge, Julia has had some energy this last week and that’s been great. We’ve needed it mind as she’s been to see 4 different consultants.  Julia has been stressing about not knowing what’s happening after chemo, which was initially due to finish this week but as she missed one its next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s next?  That has been the question and is seems not even the consultants knew. The thing is there is no road map, no 12 steps, no single way of killing cancer. The chemo doctor was pondering if we should do more chemo -&amp;gt; surgery -&amp;gt; radiotherapy and hormone therapy or surgery -&amp;gt; radiotherapy -&amp;gt; more chemo and hormone therapy. So to help decide he arranged Julia to have a scan and then meet the surgeon to see what he thinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre surgery chemo is the exception rather than the rule. Julia also had her chemo drugs in a different order than the “normal way”. We found out why, it was because Julia’s cancer was growing fast and the position of it that meant that she had to have chemo first and the big drugs first.  When Julia had her scan when we heard that the original size of the cancer was 8cm and has shrunk to 1cm. We both agree that we’re bloody glad we didn’t find out that nugget earlier on, it would have scared the bejebus out of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a train to London (to Harley street no less) to see the genetics doctor. His office was bigger than my front room - epic. The upshot of it is Julia is being tested but the results won’t necessarily be conclusive or provide a boolean yes or no about what to do in the future. It raised a few questions but we’ll look at them more when and if we have to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The surgeon saw Julia and really wanted to take a lead from what she wanted. Julia joked that she just wants to be told when to turn up.  There was some discussion about what to do. Julia has had a great response to chemo and there may even be a complete pathological response and all cancer cells killed. The surgeon discussed a 1990’s clinical trial where people who had such responses didn’t have a mastectomy and all were clear after 5 years.  Julia and I both sat there not wanting to be told that there would be no surgery - as we’d just live with a cloud of fear over our heads. Anyway, no need as the surgeon went on to say that none made a 10 year clear, which confirmed his belief in cutting out the problem. A date is booked for surgery - 24th March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we’ve had such an amount of information this week, that its been mentally tough. Tension levels have been up as away this week.  I enjoyed a well earned pint on Saturday but could have done without the hangover on Sunday.  Julia cried Sunday morning not wanting me to go and then later apologised for crying.  Imogen blew up when asked to write out her times tables and then when I tried to get her to calm down I lost it after she started pushing me in the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so ashamed of scaring her when I shouted at her that I started sobbing. The dam broke and the powerlessness of it all struck home hard. I had a five minute breakdown and just sobbed. I had just realised that for all the hoping and belief that I could somehow help my children through this unscathed. I now know I can’t and this horrible disease is hurting my children also. It’s a hard realisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing probably is not to set unrealistic expectations but emotions and beliefs aren’t known for being rational.  Although, my emotions are still a little raw (the last paragraph was incredibly difficult to write) I think the good thing is the realisation.  My next steps will be working out how to minimise the impact and help ensure the kids are rounded. The only thing is I’m not sure how best to do that… Once I return home from Dublin and New York I’ll look into it more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s going to be a long week, so please keep an eye on Julia whilst I’m away and thanks Grandad Mikey for stopping over for the week.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/tears-and-tantrums&quot;&gt;Tears and tantrums&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on February 02, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>