<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2014-01-26T16:03:16+00:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflection]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/reflection" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/reflection</id>
  <published>2014-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I thought rather than the normal diary approach I'd step back and reflect.&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve been finding myself reflecting on things.  It could just be the time of the year - a new year and all that, or it could just be my brain trying to make sense of the madness of it all.  Either way, I hope it helps and in the future when memories have faded, it will shine a light on thoughts in the eye of the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;julia&quot;&gt;Julia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia is a star. She’s generally been dealing with a weekly dose of poison with such amazing courage and stoicism to it.  However, it has been so hard to observe the bone crushing fatigue that it brings.  Chemotherapy, each week takes a higher toll on her. It’s probably the wrong way round, the toll is the same but the acculation of it means it’s been taking longer and longer to recover.  So much so, this week they postponed her weekly chemotherapy, to give her a chance to recover before starting again next week.  The result was Julia was able to get out of bed and do things with the kids by herself on Saturday. Something, that hasn’t happened for months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both are looking forward to the end of chemotherapy but it’s also scary, there’s the next stage of the journey to go and we aren’t even 100% of what that will fully entail. It’s probably best not to know - too much information and all that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-kids&quot;&gt;The kids&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both kids are doing well but unsurprisingly Imogen has been hit the hardest.  There’s been tears and tantrums from them both, but with Imogen there’s just more. More anger, more bitterness, more shouting and more tears.  She has woken scared, wanting to read the Mummys Lump book, which helps reassure her of the future. She’s become terratorial of her room and once she feels aggrieved, it takes time and space for her to calm down.  It’s difficult if she decides to do that just before the school run and all stress levels rise.  Felix, for the most part seems to be taking it all in his stride, he’s had a couple of moments mind. Felix is having nightmares and there have been a couple of nighttime accidents, so even though he might not understand exactly whats happening it still is impacting him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;me&quot;&gt;Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still scared about the future, there have been times I’ve woken in the middle of the night for no real reason, but I’m not the type of person who dwells on things too much. Although, I’ve come to absolutely &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt; fridays. It’s the worst day of the week by far and it impacts me alot. I have a trifecta of pressure that simmers throughout the day - getting the kids to and from school, trying to get my work done and watching Julia go from being the best she has been for a week to being floored. It really is the crappest of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to say I’m handling being chief laundry man well - mind I haven’t done any ironing this year but as there’s only two items in the ironing pile who cares!  I’m generally very busy, but I’m now used to it. I can get grumpy when I don’t get much time to sit and chill at weekends but on the whole I’m busy and happy to be so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Janathon and Dryathlon have been fun and are a good distraction. The only downside is the month feels soo long! How can it &lt;strong&gt;still&lt;/strong&gt; be Janurary?!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 26, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Week Off]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-week-off" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-week-off</id>
  <published>2014-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">My chemotherapy has had a holiday this week.&lt;p&gt;Things seemed to be going ok.  Granted the extreme fatigue I’ve been feeling has been quite frustrating and I’ve had a headache which I’ve been unable to shift, but it was ‘Fine’.  Unfortunately things weren’t to stay on an even keel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d managed to deploy some new functionality for work which had been playing on my mind.  This was a relief.  Small wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go to the hospital every Thursday to have blood tests to check I’m fit enough to have my chemo on Fridays.  It doesn’t take long and I’m normally dealt with quickly and efficiently allowing me to get back to work.  This Thursday, however, I woke up feeling distinctly under par, and whilst Ross was taking the bairns to breakfast club, I was subsequently sick.  Not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing about having chemotherapy, is everything is taken very seriously.  So when I mentioned I’d been sick and had a headache, things started happening.  I had additional blood tests taken, blood pressure, temperature, the doctor came in and had a look at me, and then we waited for the blood test results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking we wouldn’t be there for long, Ross hadn’t taken his laptop, so was unable to do any work.  I, however, made good use of the situation, and went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few of hours, the blood tests results came back, and then we had to wait for my Consultant to make a decision.  He was eventually tracked down, and decided that given how exhausted I was, I’d have a week off my chemotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this decision made, we went off home with some anti sickness tablets, and I went to bed and went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the break in chemo, it coincided with a week I was due my Herceptin, so we still had to go back for that on Friday morning.  Luckily this is a quick 30 min drip, so we were out quite quickly.  I was also instructed to see the GP about my headache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back home, back to bed, and although I was tempted to go to the drs in my PJs, I did manage to get dressed to attend my appointment.  I was given some stronger painkillers and told to return if things didn’t improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning comes, and Ross does the usual round of ferrying the bairns to their swimming lessons and dancing for Imogen.  I’d managed to change Felix’s lesson, so he was back with his old teacher and as a result didn’t go into melt down when it was time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some gorgeous flowers delivered whilst the family were out from my Dad and Julie, and like all flowers which are sent, they are very well received and much appreciated.  Flowers make me smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I’ve developed a slight case of Chemo induced agrophobia.  I just don’t want to go out unless I really have to.  I had planned to go for a walk to the knitting shop, but I got sidetracked baking with Imogen, and have to say, I wasn’t too disappointed.  We made fruit burst muffins and banana bread, and although the oven proved a bit tricky to decipher, they were lovely. (http://www.bbcgoodfood.com/recipes/1273/fruitburst-muffins)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the painkillers kicking in, and a bit of respite from the chemo, I felt well enough to have a glass of Sparkly from my Gin Club supply.  I did worry that Ross would feel like I wasn’t supporting him with Dryathlon, but he understood that it was one glass, and I probably wouldn’t feel like having anymore until I finish my chemo in 4 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday morning, the bairns go to their second rugby training session, and Ross gets them signed up as members of the rugby club.  I stay at home, and make sure there’s plenty of hot water on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headache persists, but I’m trying to stay on top of it with the painkillers.  I’m hoping that with a break in treatment, the fatigue is going to release it’s holds me so that I can become a facsimile of a fully functioning human being.  Temporarily at least.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-week-off&quot;&gt;A Week Off&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 26, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Post from Imogen]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Imogen" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Imogen</id>
  <published>2014-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Imogen decided she would like to put a post on the blog so we can see things from her perspective&lt;p&gt;I’m worried about Mummy because she having horrible medicine.  She needs to have this to make her better from the Cancer.  I’m angry and cross and sometimes sad.  Mummy keeps reading Mummy’s Lump to me and it makes me feel a bit happier because it tells us what is happening in words I can understand.  It’s helping me understand what is going to happen to Mummy and it makes me feel less scared.  It’s hard to understand everything that is happening at the minute, but the book helps me a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mummy has no hair because she has strong medicine called Chemotherapy.  I went to the hospital to see Mummy have her Chemotherapy over the Christmas holidays, and I thought it was going to be scary, but it wasn’t.  All it was, was bags of medicine which looked like water, going through a tube, into Mummy.  It didn’t hurt Mummy, but she did fall asleep.  I read a Hello Kitty book and Felix and Daddy made a Lego object.  Then we watched Gangster Granny on Daddy’s iPad. Then we watched Katie Morag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week after that, we went to Katy’s house whilst Mummy had her Chemotherapy.  I was much happier with this because it was less boring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mummy doesn’t go swimming anymore because the Chemotherapy makes her tired and she just wants to go to sleep.  I’m looking forward to her finishing it, so we can have more time with Mummy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m scared about the operation Mummy is going to have but it’s a while away.  After the operation, Mummy might have to have Radiotherapy that kills any little bits of Lump that are left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to be doing the Race For Life in July for Cancer Research, and I am looking forward to it.  A lot of my friends are going to do it with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mummy still loves her cuddles with me and Felix.  And I love them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imogen&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/Imogen&quot;&gt;A Post from Imogen&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 26, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ups and Downs]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/ups-and-downs" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/ups-and-downs</id>
  <published>2014-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">We always knew this journey was going to have it's ups and downs, but I think we've been quite lucky with it so far.&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say that there’s not a lot going on, because we’ve still had the weekly blood tests, followed by chemo, but there’s been less high adrenaline activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, feeling like I had fair wind behind me, I decided that on Tuesday I’d drive the 22 miles to the office to show my face.  Although I’ve been working my normal four days a week, they’ve been at home, with my laptop.  If I need a nap, I can have one, and the commute is as involved as walking to the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completely underestimated how much the normal morning routine would take out of me.  Getting the bairns up and dressed, getting my breakfast and lunch sorted, getting the bairns to breakfast club, driving to work.  By the time I was sat at my desk, I was shattered.  It was great to see people, and I appreciate some times a face to face conversation can save a lot of emails, but I certainly paid for it.
By 3pm, I was struggling to keep my eyes open, so at 4pm I left.  Once home, I had a bath and went to bed.  Unfortunately, despite being tired to the bottom of my boots, I found it very difficult to sleep.  The result being that come Wednesday morning, I was completely unable to get out of bed.  I thought after an hour or so’s extra rest, I’d be able to get the laptop out and start working again, but no.  I just couldn’t do it.  I felt so low and useless and miserable.  I admit, I had a little cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a pep talk from The Gin Club and a cuddle from Ross, I felt better but still spent the rest of the day in bed, only getting up to find sustenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday nights sleep was much better, and on Thursday morning, we tipped off to the hospital for my Pre-Chemo blood tests.  On the way, I checked my phone, and found I had won a pair of earrings in a Facebook competition.  This was just the boost I needed.  It was going to be a good day.  And it was.  I was glad to get back to work once we got back from the hospital, and put in a good solid block of time getting lots of ticks on my to do list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesley, kindly provided a home made pie for tea (thank you Lesley), and it was time to spend some time with my bairns,  I do feel like they haven’t been getting the best of me of late. I don’t think there is a best of me to have at the moment, but once the chemo is over with, I’m hoping to get fighting fit again so I can remind them what it’s like to have a normal mummy, before I get hit with the surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/ups-and-downs&quot;&gt;Ups and Downs&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 16, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping on, keeping on.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/keeping-on-keeping-on" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/keeping-on-keeping-on</id>
  <published>2014-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">On Wednesday, we were at two different hospitals.&lt;p&gt;I saw the Oncologist in the morning to have a review of my treatment.    Despite my cold he was happy to continue.  I mentioned my chest was tight and was feeling a bit breathless so it was decided that I’d have a CT scan to rule out the possibility of a blood clot on my lung.  This is a risk of having the port which I have fitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the afternoon we went to another hospital for the CT scan.  This is the downside of going private.  Things aren’t all in one place.  Still, we’ve been given fantastic care, wherever we’ve been treated.  We later hear, that it’s not a blood clot, and we are relieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, we return for my Chemo, and I sleep for the duration of the treatment.  Once home, I sleep some more, only getting up once the bairns are home from school so Ross can attend some work meetings online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekend was quiet for me.  I got lots of rest and only ventured out to see if Felix could remember how to ride his bike.  He hadn’t. It was frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the level of Chemo induced fatigue has surprised me and Ross.  I feel wiped out for most of the time.  I find it frustrating, so Ross must too.  I’m so lucky to have him and think he’s wonderful.  I’ve said it before, and will say it again, he rocks, and is my Rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s signed up for Dryathlon &amp;amp; Janathlon and I know he’s finding it tough, but he’s raised a lot of money for Cancer Research, which is a cause very important to us at the moment.  Stay Strong Ross.  You can do it. X&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/keeping-on-keeping-on&quot;&gt;Keeping on, keeping on.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 12, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A hard week]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-hard-week" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-hard-week</id>
  <published>2014-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It's been a tough old week that's left me physically and emotionally drained.&lt;p&gt;Work started and I’ve missed it! I’m lucky that I love programming and get paid to do it. After a while of being away from keyboard I start to get twitchy, so I managed to get back into it quickly. I have a new monitor that is epic and also makes working from home much easier. I’ve now ordered a new IKEA Lack coffee table and shelf and soon my standing desk will be complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed into the office on Tuesday and got a keyboard and trackpad for home. It was good to catch up with people, some which I haven’t seen since Julia’s diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday, we had an appointment to see the chemo doctor. We have been on tender hooks since New Years about illness, Julia has had a sore throat and we are worried it will head to her chest. The dr wasn’t happy that Julia was reporting some breathing and chest pains so he booked her in for a ct scan just to rule out a blood clot caused by her port. He was 80% sure it was just a viral infection but it was best to rule it out. We headed off to Spire in the afternoon and had the scan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think we slept well on Thursday night, pre chemo nights cause Julia to be restless. Friday comes and we’re both knackered, we get the kids to school and head off to the hospital again. Julia’s bloods are ok, red cells are still low so more beef and greens next week! Julia sleeps for most of the chemo as the piriton knocks her out and I work away. Time soon passes and we head home. Julia sleeps a lot on chemo days and I stress about getting work done, picking the kids up, cooking tea and getting Imogen to gymnastics. By bedtime I’m knackered stressed and feeling low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding to the stress is doing Janathon and Dryathlon, finding time to exercise and sort everything can be hard also there have been times I could kill a beer! There is still time to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justgiving.com/Ross-Lawley-dryathlete&quot;&gt;sponsor me&lt;/a&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning I take the kids swimming, Imogen has her lesson first, then Felix and once done we have to hot foot it to Imogen’s dance class in Letchworth. Imogen does her part but after 30 mins of swimming with Felix he suddenly decides he’s not doing his lesson. No warning just point blank refused, arms crossed and face set. I argue that he has to but he screams when I pick him up to get him nearer to the class. It’s not like he won’t enjoy it once he gets in… Then when the teacher (Amy) picks him up and brings him over to the class he screams again. I leave him so he can join in, but after 15 mins after the lesson was supposed to start he’s still standing there I collect him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not best pleased about things and the waste of money, I tell Felix he’s lost lego Star Wars rights and he won’t go to rugby until he does a swimming lesson. I’m fuming and it takes me a while to cool down. That afternoon, we decide Felix can go to rugby if he rides his bike. Disaster! We head to the park and Felix refuses to pedal. Both Julia and I try to coax him and we both nearly binned his bike. The mission for Felix to be able to win back rugby failed miserably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cook a beef Wellington for tea to keep Julia’s bloods healthy. We’ve started doing meal plans for the week and click and collect at the super market in a bid to reduce the waste and save money. Everyone enjoys it and I’m told I’ll be cooking it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night Imogen wobbles at bedtime, she’s worried about mummy’s cancer and wants to read Mummy’s Lump, the book we were given to explain things to the children. Felix goes to bed much more quietly than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m worn out but can’t sleep, the fallout from my old blog post still goes on. Julia isn’t happy about being drawn into it and doesn’t want to ignore that and I support her. My parents ask about coming over in April to support after the surgery, and I’ve been putting off responding because as things stand it would be too stressful, it’s heartbreaking. Its been a shitty week but tomorrow is another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday is bright and crisp, Felix had an accident in the night so first order of duty is to shower him and wash the kids bedding. Then I head to the gym and feel much better after. I love fresh frosty bright days. After breakfast Imogen decides she wants to make mini cheesecakes. We head out to the shops, then she makes them, she rocks and makes awesome lime cheesecakes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch I take the kids out on bikes again, Felix is up for it today. I don’t let him walk with his bike to the park but get him to pedal whilst I push him. He wants to walk a couple of times but I don’t let him. We have fun and get to the park quickly. Felix is a different person today, he finds peddling hard but tries and succeeds. Lots of praise. He has a great time and I find a little grass ramp for Imogen to cycle down, she’s a dare devil and is brilliant. She falls off the ramp but gets straight back on. Felix has a go at cycling on the path and finds it easier. He’s nearly self sufficient, mission successful, he is going to rugby next week. Some good headology has got him past the finish line and he’s pleased as punch and  tells Julia when he gets home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week will be a better week.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/a-hard-week&quot;&gt;A hard week&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 12, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy new year!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happy-new-year" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happy-new-year</id>
  <published>2014-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Well a brief hiatus is always going to be a good sign on this blog!&lt;p&gt;Christmas has been bloody fantastic! I’ve feasted and drank with family and friends it’s been great. I went out for drinks with the Gin Club Dads (the Gin Club is the nick name for my wife’s friends, it’s a long story but basically they all had bairns (babies) at about the same time and used to have coffee mornings. One of the dad’s glibly said they just sit and drink gin and the Gin Club name stuck) it was a messy night for some reason we attacked the spirits and had all manner of evil shots. I could hardly function the next day and started to feel decidedly ropey whilst swimming with the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grandad Mickey and grandma Julie were great company over Christmas. Grandma was almost annoyed he kids didn’t wake early enough on Christmas morning! I cooked my first Christmas dinner, it was a little late as we decided to have a quick Christmas pint at The Orange Tree but that helped reduce the stress of it and it was a great feast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Friday after Christmas (27th) the kids came with us for Julia’s chemo, it was good for them to see the process and see it’s not scary. It was slightly manic as it was blood tests in the morning then chemo in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, I took the bairns for a long walk round Weston Hills, we took a pack lunch as 7.5km is a trek for a 5 &amp;amp; 7 year old. Half way round we got shot at, as we stumbled upon a pheasant shoot. We had lunch whilst we waited for the all clear whistle and watched as some birds made it and others showered us in feathers and landed with a thud. Once the whistle sounded we spoke to some of the beaters as I showed the kids the birds, Felix is up for pheasant and Imogen turned vegetarian!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday Julia was feeling well enough to meet for a Gin Club walk round Ivel Springs.  It was good to see everyone and get some fresh air, afterwards, we all went to The Orange Tree to see the steam rally that was there, there were some fantastic machines steaming and chuffing away. The pub session lasted much longer than the walk and we left well oiled. The Martins and the Kings came back for some SingStar and pizza, the kids played together brilliantly and it was a late one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On New Year’s Eve we had a few friends over for a curry, I had planned the meals whilst hungover and seemed to go over the top, chicken tikka drumsticks, chicken korma, lamb kofta curry, golden saag potatoes and cauliflower, saffron rice and homemade naans. By the time the guests arrived I was knackered but it was a good night! And all the food evaporated - a good sign. I also ended up with loads of beer which is ironic as I’m going dry for January!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Year’s Day it was the start of Janathon (doing exercise every day in January). I took Imogen out for a 20 minute run, she did brilliantly and although the wind and rain gave her an ice cream headache we soldiered on and diverted attention from that by jumping in all the puddles!  Julia had to rest up a lot for that afternoon as we were round a friends for the best beef dinner I will have in 2014. Amazing. Good food and great company as always. When Julia looked knackered and was zoning out we said our goodbyes and headed home. The kids wanted to stay longer but we have been pushing our luck with our recent excursions and we have to make sure Julia stays fit and well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking Julia for her blood test we have a quiet day, the kids are tired and boy child manages to flood the downstairs loo by leaving taps on. Amazing considering a few hours before girl child got a rollicking for leaving the tap on and nearly doing the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are back at the hospital now, the nurse wasn’t happy with Julia and a doctor was called. No temp but a sore throat, after checking her chest she gets the all clear for chemo. As I say we have been pushing our luck recently and Julia is on strict instructions to rest up extra this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy new year all!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happy-new-year&quot;&gt;Happy new year!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 03, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Merry Christmas!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/merry-christmas" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/merry-christmas</id>
  <published>2013-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It's the most wonderful time of the year. &lt;p&gt;My Dad, Wicked Step Mother Julie, and brother Max all arrived on Monday afternoon for Christmas.  At 12:30 on Christmas Eve, I finished work, packed the laptop away and the festivities started.  The bairns loved their Christmas Eve box which contained The Night Before Christmas book, new pj’s, hot chocolate, marshmallows and reindeer dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bairns woke at 7:30am on Christmas Day, much to Grandma Julie’s disappointment, as she’d been awake since 4am!  Stockings from Father Christmas were opened first, and then after breakfast, the rest of the presents started to be opened.  Ross likes to make sure the presents aren’t opened in one go, and that they are spread out over the day, so it was 4pm by the time we’d opened them all.  Thank you to all those generous people who gave lovely gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a quick trip to The a Orange Tree for a cheeky drink at lunchtime  It’s just as well we live so close, as Ross kept darting off to keep an eye the Christmas dinner.  The Strong’s joined us for a quick one, and before long we were sat down in front of a feast!  Thank you Ross, for a lovely meal.  It was epic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/christmas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Merry Christmas&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boxing Day was a rather sedate affair with my Dad using the leftovers to good effect with Christmas Chelsea Buns.  Yummy!  Uncle Max left us in the morning and it was with a heavy heart as I waved him off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Grandad and Grandma left to visit the rest of the family on their Christmas and New Year road trip.  We were then off to the hospital to have my bloods checked ahead of the afternoons Chemo.  We decided that the bairns should come along so they can see what happens, and they don’t need to be worried or scared of the Chemo.  We’re in a private room so they only saw what was happening to me and we could control what was going on.  They were great.  They watched what happened, made some Lego, watched some stuff on the iPad, and were stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we returned home, we just chilled, and had some family time.  The antihistamines made me drowsy so it was bath and early bed for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve still got lots of Christmas wine left, which is mainly because I don’t fancy it.  I had a couple of glasses of wine on Christmas Day, but it was just really going through the motions.  Bring on next Christmas when I WILL be free of cancer and this year will just be a memory.  Oh how we’ll laugh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/merry-christmas&quot;&gt;Merry Christmas!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 26, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Christmas spirit]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/christmas-spirit" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/christmas-spirit</id>
  <published>2013-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Christmas is coming, we are in the quiet before the storm.&lt;p&gt;The kids are with the childminder and the relatives are incoming and I’ve got a few more hours work before I’m on hols too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last week has been pretty normal with its highs and lows.  I finished my reactive programming course and scored 100% in all the assignments! Woot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw the doctor about Julia’s chemotherapy on Wednesday and the difference between this visit and the last one was marked. He was happy with Julia’s progress and mentioned that as the tumour is shrinking so much that he thinks they should put a pin in it, to mark its location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday we nip to the hospital so they can take bloods and Friday morning it’s round two of the weekly chemo.  I work away whilst Julia gets hooked up to the matrix, I look up and Julia is fast asleep, the piriton knocked her out again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rush back, get the bairns and then there’s a birthday party to take Imogen to. I have a standup meeting - a short video conference with the rest of the team. I have to cut it short to rush back to pick up Imogen, she had a great time! I quickly make tea and then take Imogen to gymnastics. I’m a bit stressed and grumpy all day and Julia tells me off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday, was quite quiet with no little ruggers or dance lessons for the kids.  Imogen and I do a christmas shop - Tescos was rammed and it was a lesson in passive aggressive trolley wrangling. I heard one person threating violence because it was so busy and it was doing his head in - the big wuss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the shopping done, we head on home and that evening the Gin Club Dads come round for burittos and beer before we head off to the pub.  It was a good night, not sure who ordered the snowball drinks but they were followed by various shots of liqueir.  I have to sleep with one foot on the floor to stop the room spinning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday was a day of misery! We go swimming in the morning which helps clear the head. Julia was designated driver and got to see Imogen get her 200m swimming badge. I come home have a nap and then head out to collect the christmas turkey. I nap some more and become human again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia with impeccible timing forwards me a dryathlon link - so I sign up:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justgiving.com/Ross-Lawley-dryathlete&quot;&gt;Ross’s Dryathlon Page&lt;/a&gt; donations welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas all!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/christmas-spirit&quot;&gt;Christmas spirit&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 23, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drip, drip, drip]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/drip-drip-drip" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/drip-drip-drip</id>
  <published>2013-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The blood test results came back and it was all system's go for the Chemotherapy today. &lt;p&gt;It was a bit more stressful than we intended as all my appointments so far have been at 10am. However, as the bairns had a short day at school and finished at 12, we’d made the appointment for 9:30.  We realised at 8:35, and mild panic ensued.  It’s a 40 min drive to Harpenden!  Thankfully, Michelle hadn’t left, and we were able to get the bairns to her so she could take them to school.  Phew!  Thank you Michelle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the hospital right on time and I was hooked up to the drip, given saline to flush the tube, anti sickness, antacid, steroids, antihistamine, the chemo drugs, more saline and some anticoagulants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ross grassed me up to the nurse who told her last night I came over a bit sick and felt faint.  She took my blood pressure and heart rate, which were both fine, but after looking at my blood test results again decided it was probably because my haemoglobin was a touch low.  Not low enough to give me iron tablets, but enough to warrant steak, dark chocolate and spinach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two hours and a nap later, I’m all done, detached, and sent on my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clair had picked the bairns up from school for us (Thanks Clair), and we arrived just as they got back.  We decided a McDonalds was in order so off we went and I sat in Baldock Services with my baldy head out again.  Get me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got back home, I put a film on for the bairns and I promptly fell asleep on the sofa.  Then, Ross took Imogen off to a party, and Felix to the barbers for his Christmas haircut.  The rest of the day was fairly quiet with Ross taking Imogen to gymnastics and Felix watching the Crystal Maze.  After tea, the bairns and I went to bed whilst Ross stayed up for the Christmas food shop delivery from Sainsburys.  There’s a whole lot of food, and a lot that’s been forgotten!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/drip-drip-drip&quot;&gt;Drip, drip, drip&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 20, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genetics]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/genetics" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/genetics</id>
  <published>2013-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">We went to see the Oncologist, Dr Shah, today to see how I was getting on with new Chemotherapy regime.&lt;p&gt;The side effects have been massively reduced, and the fact I haven’t had any trips to A&amp;amp;E are all great steps forward.  Big Lump has massively reduced in size as well, so we are on the right road.  It’s a good job Ross was with me in the appointment, as I was rubbish answering some of the questions.  I just couldn’t remember what’s been going on. Everything is blurring into one big chemotherapy haze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision was made to carry on with this regime, and also to book in a minor procedure to mark where the tumours are with clips so that when they come to do the pathology on it, they know where they are looking.  I’m not sure when this will happen, but hopefully it’ll be in the New Year now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan is still to do a mastectomy in  March when the chemotherapy has finished as well as more lymph node clearance.  I had hoped that I wouldn’t have to have any more nodes removed, but I suppose it’s for the best.  I don’t particularly want any cancer seeds being left hanging around to cause chaos later on down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oncologist also reminded me that I had to fill in the questionnaire to convince the local centre to run a genetic test on on me to see if I’ve got faulty BRCA1 or BRCA2 gene.  The fact that I’ve been diagnosed with breast cancer before I’m 40 indicates I have a slightly higher than normal chance and it could dictate whether I have a more surgery to reduce my risk further.  It also would be good to know as it’ll have implications for Imogen and Felix.  The questionnaire has now been sent off so fingers crossed I’ve given them enough information to convince them to test me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s back to the hospital for blood tests tomorrow, and hopefully the next lots of Chemotherapy on Friday if those blood tests come back clear.  There’s no reason to think they won’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onwards we go on this journey we never thought we’d be on.  Thank you to all who are keeping us company along the way.  We really do appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/genetics&quot;&gt;Genetics&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 18, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wookiee no more]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wookie-no-more" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wookie-no-more</id>
  <published>2013-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">A quiet week really, work and life are cracking on well.&lt;p&gt;Someone posted a question on an internet forum that showed a bug with my code. It took me two days to fix it and I saw broken behaviour of the language I program in, anyways it was a good puzzle and got my grey matter (and google skills) working at full pace to fix it.  My job really is all about solving puzzles and thats why I love it so much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday night, Julia was restless and fearful because the Chemotherapy was due to start again and this time it’s weekly.  So it took a time to fall asleep but this was all confounded by waking up at 2:30am and Julia hearing voices. Strange. We checked the window and there was no one nattering in the street, the voices were coming from downstairs! Noisy buglars? No the TV was on - we’d turned it off before going to bed, so that was very bizarre. We check all the doors, all locked. We can’t sleep so we watch an episode of Hebburn before trying to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday is chemo day and it goes smoothly. Julia is given 4 pre meds and the piriton knocks her out, so she sleeps through most of it. I spend my time working and a few hours later we head on home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chemo-sleep.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two Baldies&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning I take Imogen out for a run again. She’s great and we do sprints. Imogen decides tag is a better way to do sprints and it makes the run good fun. At one point I tag Imogen turn sharply and then go flying. My foot had found a rabbit hole, luckily I didn’t twist anything but I did fall onto some very sharp branches and cut my leg up a bit. Imogen found it all very amusing and tagged me back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the week we get an email from Little Ruggers, seems they are no longer challenging Felix so Saturdays class will be his last. On Saturday morning we all head out and watch. He comes out beaming at the end with a certificate and medal. He’s a bit nervous about going to the Rugby club but I know once he gets used to it he’ll love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia’s hair looks really thin and patchy now. For the first time she really looks like that she is a chemotherapy patient.  She finds this hard, we knew her hair would most likely fall out and she had prepared for that. However, its no quick process, it’s bit by bit and that makes it all the more traumatic. I think if it was an overnight process it would be easier to handle but its not that way. By Sunday afternoon Julia has had enough and we get the clippers out. She cries, it’s a shock and she briefly mourns her hair before accepting its fate.  Imogen looked shocked and hugs mummy and Felix didn’t know how to react and giggled then asked if mummy could put a wig on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lawleys.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two Baldies&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/wookie-no-more&quot;&gt;Wookiee no more&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 16, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's oh so quiet!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/oh-so-quiet" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/oh-so-quiet</id>
  <published>2013-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Since Thursday's chemo and herceptin treatment, it's been quite quiet.&lt;p&gt;All has gone to plan, there’s been no nasty side effects and although I’m tired, I’ve been able to get some more Christmas preparations done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hair was still falling out in clumps, so Ross helped me out and today we shaved it off.  I look like a Star Trek character.  I have to admit I did cry when I first saw it, but it’s only hair, and it’ll grow back.  Ross shaved his too, so we’re a couple of baldy heads together.  The support we’ve received from our friends on Facebook has been great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing to happen over the last few days is that my Wicked Step Mother, Julie, has finished her treatment for breast cancer.  She’s had a full on 5 months with surgery and radiotherapy, and can now get on with her life.  She has been a rock for me over the past few months as she knows exactly what I’m going through.  Big hugs and much love. X&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/two-baldies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two Baldies&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/oh-so-quiet&quot;&gt;It's oh so quiet!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 15, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Up]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/on-the-up" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/on-the-up</id>
  <published>2013-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Monday to Wednesday this week were fairly normal.&lt;p&gt;I’ve been splitting my time between work and home. I’ve lost more hair than I’ve got left now, and I’m shedding still.  The bathroom seems to be where the majority can be found, much to Ross’s dismay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday we went to see Felix’s school Christmas play.  He sang his songs very well, but it was odd seeing him with drawn on goatee beard and sideburns.  All the children did very well.  I’m looking forward to watching Imogen’s on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to go to the hospital for blood tests on Wednesday morning, but all went to plan, and we came home and cracked on with work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday morning I woke up at 2am to hear voices.  I went downstairs to find the tv on. I was sure it got turned off when we went to bed and it definitely wasn’t on the same channel we’d been watching.  After switching it off, we went back to bed, but the pre chemo anxiety meant we couldn’t get back to sleep, so we watched tv in bed for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few hours later, Ross got up to take the bairns to breakfast club, and I got up shortly after to tidy up ready for the cleaners coming.  Then it was off to the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, the nurses were efficient, and I was soon hooked up to a saline drip, followed by 4 pre-med drips including antihistamine, antacid and anti sickness.  Then it was the chemo, Herceptin, and a saline drip and anti-coagulant to finish.  I’m so glad I have a portacath, as it’s so straight forward to administer all the drugs.  The antihistamine knocked me out and I slept for most of the session.  This was very different from the first session, and it seems will be how each session will be on the new regime.  Ross, as always was sat next to me working away on his laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came home, and I went back to bed.   When the bairns came back, Felix announced he had moved up a reading level, and Imogen did a recital of her recorder Christmas tune from memory.  She now wants to learn Jingle Bells so we had a master class and she’s been practicing that.  My bairns make me so proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite calm today.  I like calm days.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/on-the-up&quot;&gt;On the Up&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 12, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Festivities]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/festivities" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/festivities</id>
  <published>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">As we roll into December, we're getting more and more festive.&lt;p&gt;Ross and I have almost finished the Christmas shopping.  Lists are being made in preparation for Christmas Day food shopping, and the cupboards are getting stocked with Goodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had confirmation that my chemo will run weekly starting next Thursday, so we’re trying to get everything done before that starts.  I had a few of the Gin Club ladies round for coffee on Friday morning which was lovely.  I’m not going to have a chance to do that again until all the cycles have finished in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, we went to see Cinderella at the theatre in Stevenage.  It was great fun, and we all enjoyed it very much.  Ross nearly had a close call with an Ugly Sister, but having Felix sat beside him saved him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening it was the Gin Club Christmas dinner at The George in Baldock.  Sadly, Lesley missed it as she had a stomach bug, but everyone else made it, and we had a lovely time.  It wasn’t as rowdy as it’s been in the past, but it was still very nice.  The food was good, and I enjoyed a couple of glasses of wine.  I was one of the first to leave, but I still stayed out later than I thought I would and Ross was starting to get a bit worried by the time I did get in.  (Sorry Ross).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to style my hair carefully for the evening, as it’s coming out in clumps now.  I have some bald patches, but with some careful positioning and some spray wax, I think I got away with it.  I googled how long it would take for my hair to fall out completely, and I didn’t really find a definitive answer, although I did find someone’s rather upsetting hair loss video diary.  Everyone is different.  I’m having to sleep wearing a hat in an effort to try and contain the hair that’s falling out.  It’s not very comfortable, but it’s doing the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next week or so, I’ll probably start wearing the bandanas and scarves I’ve got on standby. I’m a bit worried about that to be honest as it’ll become obvious to the world that I’m a Cancer patient. The school run is becoming a daunting prospect as are the Christmas concerts I’ve got to attend over the next week.  I don’t particularly want to be gossiped about by people who don’t know me on the school playground.  I’m probably being over sensitive, and no one will notice or care, especially if I utilise the trusty wooly hats I’ve got.  Thank goodness it’s winter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday was a rather quiet affair for me, only venturing out to Sainsbury’s for some lunch , and then a long nap on the sofa.  Ross kept the kids entertained by taking them to their swimming lessons, and also for a walk followed by a drink at the Orange Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s still some family politics rumbling on.  Ross and I are under extreme pressure at the minute and if allowances can’t be made for that, then there’s something wrong.  I don’t have the energy to deal with it at the minute.  My priority has to be getting through the next 10 weeks as best I can and making Christmas as normal as we can for Imogen and Felix.  They are and always will be my reason for fighting.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/festivities&quot;&gt;Festivities&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 09, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Busy bee]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/busy-bee" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/busy-bee</id>
  <published>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Another weekend sails by and the Christmas season is gathering pace.&lt;p&gt;Another busy weekend is over and I’m getting into the flow of being über house husband. I’ve taken the kids to the dentist, done five loads of laundry (the whites are still white!), chauffeured the kids to gymnastics and little ruggers. Shouted at villans and nearly abducted by an ugly sister at the pantomime. I cooked a truely awful massaman curry, I didn’t know it was possible to cook bad thai food but thanks to what at the time I thought was an inspired purchase of powered coconut milk, I managed it - bluergh bad times. I did the weekly food shop and took the kids swimming, somehow managed to end up at the supermarket shopping again. By Sunday lunchtime I had collapsed in a heap on the sofa knackered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, an hours swim isn’t enough for the kids to properly knacker them out, so whilst Julia had a sleep, I took the kids and headed out round Ivel Springs with a ball to kick, it’s becoming a Sunday tradition now. I knew that the Gaskells were off round for a walk and then there was a suggestion of a pint in the Orange Tree after.  I was pleased when we bumped into them and Pete at the Springs, the little ones all ran round a bit chasing the football.  A cheeky couple of pints afterwards rounded off the walk nicely. Then it was back home to cook up a roast chicken with all the trimmings.  So another busy but good weekend passed by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia’s hair is still falling out, she’s lucky she started with a lot but I now know how Han Solo must have felt sharing with Chewbacca, there’s hair everywhere!  Julia was pleased that her hair had lasted for her to go out on Saturday night with the Gin Club for their Christmas meal.  Some judicious combing hid the thinner parts well and I could see how relieved she was when getting ready that she’d look ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pleased Julia was good to go out but also I had some conflicting feelings. I was worried she was out late and would tire herself out but more than that I was jealous. It took me a time to realise it but I was jealous of the Gin Club, they’d get my Julia on good form for a few hours. It’s selfish of me but I knew I’d get a tired and exhausted Julia back and on Sunday she was and rested most the day. She missed the family stuff - swimming and the afternoon walk to recover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this picking up the slack and stepping up whilst Julia is ill makes me realise how amazing single parents must be. My hat iss off to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chemotherapy starts again this week and it’s all change, no longer will it be once every 3 weeks but for the next 9 weeks we’ll be at the Hospital once a week for chemotherapy.  I’d be lieing if I didn’t say we are nervous of what the effects of the new chemotherapy drug will be. But whatever the costs of getting better, we’ll knuckle down and get through it. I’m just really pleased Christmas is coming, with all its associated distractions. It gives team Lawley a place to focus on during for a couple of weeks at least.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/busy-bee&quot;&gt;Busy bee&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 09, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hair Today...Gone Tomorrow]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hair-today-gone-tomorrow" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hair-today-gone-tomorrow</id>
  <published>2013-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Two weeks after my first chemotherapy, my hair has started to fall out.&lt;p&gt;I thought I’d deal with it better than I am to be honest.  It’s only hair.  It’ll grow back as soon as the treatment finishes in February.  But I’m feeling a bit sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into the office yesterday, which I found ridiculously tiring.  Just getting up, getting the kids to breakfast club and then driving to Bedford took it out of me.  I was shattered.  It was good to see everyone, but it’s clear that if I’m going to be much more productive working at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working at home today, as is Ross and there’s men putting a new garage roof on.  The old one had holes in it and wouldn’t have kept the contents of the garage dry over the winter, so the last of the moving house fund has gone on getting it replaced.  I’ll have to wait until I’m better before we can start saving towards the other things we want to do, including getting a new fire put in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m sat here, more hair is falling out and I’ve got quite a pile next to me now.  I wonder how long it’ll be before I decide enough is enough, and I shave it off?  I’ve got a wig and some bandana’s all ready, it’s just harder than I thought it would be, and I’m a bit disappointed with myself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/hair-today-gone-tomorrow&quot;&gt;Hair Today...Gone Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 04, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/thanksgiving" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/thanksgiving</id>
  <published>2013-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Life is settling a little now, there's been no shocks, hospital visits, mild peril or panics for over a week! I like this.&lt;p&gt;On Thanksgiving Thursday Julia and I do an epic christmas shop, we will be well fed and watered in the Lawley house this year! On Friday, Imogen has her school play, it’s fantastic, she rocks. On Friday evening Greg has arranged a head wetting to celebrate the arrival of Joni Martin. I’m glad to say my thirst returned and the Gin Club dads were all on good form. During the night I was getting text updates from Julia making sure she was ok. After a couple of beers and a tour of Baldock’s lesser pubs I head on home.  Julia is still up when I get home and has been through a whole packet of Halls for a sore throat. I find this out a few days later but it explains Julia’s texts and highlights that where sickness is involved, we are are on an amber alert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday I awake with a headache (must have had a dodgy pint) and after paracetomal and water fail me, I decide to go for a run. Felix heads downstairs for a session of Lego Star Wars on the playstation (a highly addictive (as in crack) game for 5 year olds). Imogen on the other hand decides to tag along and we head off for a run.  She’s great company and even wins 2 of the 3 mini sprint races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before I head off to take Felix to little ruggers Michelle drops off some frozen dinners which is a massive help - thank you! I head off to little ruggers only to find its not on as it’s the schools Christmas fair. So I head to the supermarket and Felix is placeted by a getting a chocolate Freddo. Anna comes round to take Imogen to her dance class - thanks again Anna. As I’m now a fully fledged Laundry Master I crack on with the weeks laundry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That afternoon we head off to Petes 40th Birthday do, I drive as Julia isn’t up for walking. We have a great time - Pete and Lesely’s curries are awesome and the chilli lime pickle was burnylicious.  We had a great time and headed home when I saw that Julia looking tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday came round and I marshalled the bairns for their swimming lessons, whilst Julia had a lie in.  Imogen managed to get some new goggles out of me, seems she’s been growing. Felix has his lesson first, whilst Imogen and I splash round and practise diving in. Imogen has a talent of starting to dive, then falling horizontally into the water, it’s impressive. Not nearly as impressive as my splash when I dive in apparently. Soon its Imogen’s lesson and Felix and I splash around. He’d been complaining that the Green caps are too hard, well that seems to have been forgotten and he swims wonderfully and even shows me his dolphin legs and butterfly stroke. I get told I’m doing mine wrong by lifting my head out the water. He’s a chip off the old block, one lesson on butterfly and he’s a master!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That afternoon Regan, Lorna, Elsie and Oscar arrive and we head to the Orange Tree for lunch. Its great to see them and the afternoon flies. I even found time to make mince pies (it was that or fall asleep). They don’t look like any mince pies you can buy but tasted about right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday night comes all too quickly, as Julia is feeling ok I sign up for a conference in London for Monday and Tuesday.  The conference is great and Michelle’s frozen meals save the day. On Monday night Christmas arrives to the Lawley house, all decorations are up. We are signalling our intent that Santa should stop at the Lawley house this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its Tuesday now and I’m back in the conference, Julia headed to work this morning. I feel low when I get a text from her telling me her hair has started to fall out. I call her and she’s ok - it was inevitable and it’s not falling out in clumps. She rocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My overriding thoughts from the last few days have been our friends are great abd we are lucky to have them.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/thanksgiving&quot;&gt;Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 03, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Christmas]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-christmas" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-christmas</id>
  <published>2013-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I worked at home today.  I slept badly again last night, so rather than spending energy driving to work, I thought it was the best use of the energy I do have.&lt;p&gt;Ross went into London for a geek meet, so I was home alone.  At lunchtime, I pulled the boxes of Christmas decorations out, and put up a few festive ornaments.  When Ross got home, I supervised him putting up some more lights, the tree and when the bairns came home they helped me decorate it.  The problem we have us that we don’t have enough decorations for the new house!  The front room looks great, but there is nothing in the kitchen/dining room.  This obviously needs to be rectified.  Especially as we’re having Christmas at home this year.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/its-christmas&quot;&gt;It's Christmas&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 02, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Side Effects]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/side-effects" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/side-effects</id>
  <published>2013-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It's been 5 and a half weeks since my diagnosis with Stage 2 breast cancer.  It's been quite an eventful time.  Our support network has been fantastic and we really do know who we can rely on in a crisis.&lt;p&gt;It’s been 5 and a half weeks since I started to take Tamoxifen which blocks the hormone receptors in the tumours to stop them growing, and a week and a half since I started my chemo and Herceptin to kill and shrink the cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there’s been some side effects.  Not the the chest pains that took us to A&amp;amp;E, and the fatigue which I was expecting, but headaches, nausea, sore mouth and the most annoying, night sweats.  I don’t have a temperature, but I wake in the night drenched.  A few minutes later, I cool down, fall back to sleep, pull the covers back up, and shortly after, I’m over heating again, in a cruel vicious circle.  Of course this is affecting my sleep, and I’m having crazy dreams.  Last night’s involved making a Mary Berry, Great British Bake Off Christmas Yule Log which I saw her make on the tv yesterday.  Felix expressed an interest in it, and I told him we’d try and make it.  So my dream involved buying the ingredients, and equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another side effect is I’m off alcohol.  We went to a friends birthday party yesterday, and all I could manage was two glasses of sparkley.  This is almost unheard of.  Still, it’ll mean the Christmas wine will go further…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At midday, my brother Regan, his wife Lorna, and Elsie and Oscar arrived.  It was great to see them, and they were a delight.  Again, I am reminded how wonderful my family is.  We went to the Orange Tree for a magnificent pub lunch (best in a Baldock in my opinion), and I managed a couple of halves of Buntingford Silent Night ale.  Lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got back, Regan helped Ross get some lights up in the tree in the front garden.  It’s very festive.  Not sure what the neighbours think though, we seem to be the first in the street to put any lights up indoor or outdoor!  Oh well, start as we mean to go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sad when it was time for them to leave, but I’m so glad they came.  I’m very tired now, do it’ll be bath and bed for me.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/side-effects&quot;&gt;Side Effects&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 01, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>