<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Big lump and the Lawleys</title>
<subtitle type="text">An expressive therapy</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk" />
<updated>2017-01-13T20:12:40+00:00</updated>
<id>http://teamrj.co.uk/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Lawleys</name>
  <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk/</uri>
  <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stage 4 Cancerversary]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-cancerversary" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-cancerversary</id>
  <published>2017-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">The Queen has two birthday&#39;s, I have two Cancerversary&#39;s&lt;p&gt;If I’m honest I’d prefer just the one, but these are the cards I’ve been dealt, so if I have to have two, I might as well acknowledge them both. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On the 1st Cancerversary of my Stage 2 diagnosis in October 2014, I went out for a fancy lunch with my friends.  I was still having Herceptin, and probably had 3 or 4 more treatments to go, but after a year, I felt amazing. The chemo, the surgeries, the radiotherapy were all in the past.  We enjoyed good food, wine and laughs, and I picked up my kids from school feeling a little bit tiddley. And why shouldn’t I? I’d beaten the beast…or so I thought.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fast forward to January 2016.  After a CT scan the day before, I was called in to see my Oncologist to get the results.  Getting results that soon, Ross and I knew something was very wrong.  You don’t get called in that quickly for a slipped disk.  The thing is Ross and I had a copy of the CT scan on a CD and we couldn’t see anything…but how could we?  We didn’t know what to look for.  What was it that was wrong?  The scan picture below gives it away.  The L4 vertebrae was a slightly different shade of grey to the other vertebrae.  That’s it.  Thank goodness for Radiologist’s who know what to look for.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/l4naughtyvertebrae.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Naughty Vertebrae&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read the blog, you’ll know what has happened in the last year, and if I’m honest I didn’t want to acknowledge this Cancerversary in the same way as the Stage 2 1st Cancerversary.  This one is different.  It isn’t a happy occasion.  I’m still having treatment, just like last time, but this time there is no count down to finishing.  This is how it is. Three monthly scans, four weekly hormone inhibitor implant, three weekly Herceptin and Zometa, and daily hormone tablets, and enough painkillers to fell a horse.  The fear that every niggle, every pain, anything unusual will be another tumour raising it’s ugly head. This is my life.  This is the New New New Normal.  And it sucks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Last week I saw the Spine Doctor, and apparently I’m doing incredibly well for someone who has had this operation. It’s a big operation and he had his work cut out. He’s one of the best, and if he hadn’t been so good, things could have been very different.  I could be in a wheelchair, not able to walk at all. You don’t want the work experience kid doing spinal surgery.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Naughty Vertebrae had ended up in pieces after the CyberKnife radiotherapy, and had to be partially removed as well as the remains of a still active tumour which was crushing the nerve to my leg, and then using cement and metal work to reconstruct my spine.  Clever stuff!  The image below shows my broken spine on the left and different views of the metalwork solution on the right.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brokenfixed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spinal Story&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this morning, I few friends came round, for coffee and cake.  I didn’t mention the Cancerversary, I didn’t want it to overshadow a normal morning.  Cancer has taken so much from me, I didn’t want it to take away the few snatches of normality I get.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Right now, things are stable, and I’m hoping it stays that way for a long time yet. I’ll happily count up the Stage 4 Cancerversary’s, because that means things are ok.  But I won’t celebrate it.  That gives it some significance that it doesn’t deserve.  I may have Stage 4 cancer, there may be no cure for it, but I am not terminal.  I am only terminal when there are no treatment options left, and I’m on round one.  I have options.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It is my 40th birthday next month and there are a few events planned so I can celebrate with my friends and family. Birthdays and anniversaries are the things that we need to celebrate.  Not cancerversary’s.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-cancerversary&quot;&gt;Stage 4 Cancerversary&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on January 13, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What A Year!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-a-year" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-a-year</id>
  <published>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">And not in a good way...&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of people have the year 2016 in their Room 101 for a number of reasons.  For the removal of any doubt, the Room I refer to is that of the George Orwell novel , “1984”, whereby any person who enters it, faces their worst fear, nightmare or phobia - essentially a torture chamber.  I’m not referring to the BBC One series where ‘celebrities’ talk about pet hates and grievances, which are then locked away in Room 101 as some sort of detention.
Anyway, back to the reasons:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ‘Great” British public deciding to leave the safety, sanctuary and sanity of The EU.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Great British Bake Off leaves the BBC.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The residents of The Land of The Free voting for a man I can’t come up with a title scathing enough other than, The Idiot that is Donald Trump.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The deaths of so many of those we refer to as Celebrities. A few which made me feel especially sad as they were part of my childhood and formative years: George Michael, Carrie Fisher, Terry Wogan, Victoria Wood, Ronnie Corbett, Alan Rickman and Paul Daniels.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The government has ridden roughshod over our NHS and education system.  (There’s better people out there to comment on this in more detail…but I thought that it should be mentioned.)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my family and I, the year 2016 will be regarded as the Year the Cancer Came Back.  The year things all went a bit weird.  The year I never want to have to go through again.  My Room 101.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started January 2016 filled with optimism.  We saw in the New Year with our very good friends, and then enjoyed a Strong Special on New Year’s Day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015newyearseve.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 58%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016beef.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 38%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

So far, so good!  I made some New Year&#39;s Resolutions which I documented in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/another-new-year/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.  Well, that got messed up quickly. (And I shout as much or even more than I did in 2015...oops).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The kids went back to school on January the 5th, and my back started to give me grief.  But nothing to worry about.  I&#39;d had back pain before.  Extra painkillers, no drama.  I went swimming, I did Pilates and I carried on as normal.  On Sunday the 10th, we trekked down to Hertford for a rugby match with the kids.  Each at different ends of Hertford&#39;s massive grounds.  I got the short straw and had the longest walk to where Felix was playing.  Whilst there, I spoke to Pinky, who suggested that rather than stick to the painkillers, I have a word with my Oncologist.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That Monday morning, I walked the kids to school, and two women I knew by sight but not to talk to, asked if they could walk them rather than me, as I was obviously in pain. I declined, and soldiered on.  I laughed about it to my friends.  It couldn&#39;t possibly be  sinister. All evidence pointed to a slipped disk.  Never has anyone wanted a slipped disk more than me at that point.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So, on Pinky’s advice and listening to the voice in my head that said something wasn’t quite right, I spoke to the Oncologist the Monday, had a scan on the Tuesday and on Wednesday 13th January, he told me I was looking at a 90% chance that the cancer was back, this time in my spine.  This was  most likely a secondary.  No cure.  Only management.  New Year&#39;s Resolutions completely upended.  And also not quite like Craig David’s 7 day’s.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Once the diagnosis was confirmed, in 2016, I had 143 medical appointments, including blood tests, scans, consultations, radiotherapy, infusions, counseling sessions and also reflexology sessions.  That works out at about one every three days. &lt;br /&gt;   
&lt;br /&gt;
I restarted Herceptin and Zometa infusions every three weeks to continue indefinitely.  I woke up in the night screaming as the pain in my leg and back was horrendous. I had to use a walking stick.  I got a Blue Badge.  I have had 3, hour long sessions on consecutive days of Cyberknife radiotherapy. I have had two weeks in a Hospice for pain management. I had a blood transfusion (and associated guilt). I have had a week in the Royal National Orthopedic hospital as the Cyberknife had caused my vertebrae to collapse, so I needed my vertebrae to be reconstructed and another blood transfusion (and associated guilt).  They found active cancer cells which meant the Herceptin hadn’t worked on that particular tumour.  The tumour had wrapped itself around the nerve to my leg and was slowly crushing it.  I had two weeks of daily radiotherapy sessions.  I’ve been on Morphine for the most part of this year.  I was unable to drive due to the Morphine and pain from January until August.  Walking the kids to school became the exception, rather than the rule.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So tomorrow, I will be spending the evening with friends, all with the hope that 2017 will be better than 2016.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-a-year&quot;&gt;What A Year!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Christmas 2016]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/christmas" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/christmas</id>
  <published>2016-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">(This a festive post).&lt;p&gt;This year’s Christmas was very similar to last year’s.  We had my Dad and Julie round a day or two before Christmas and Uncle Max arrived on Christmas Eve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year on Christmas Eve, we Lawley’s always get new pyjamas.  The reason behind this is so that if any photo’s are taken on Christmas Day, before we’ve got dressed, we’ll at least have decent PJ’s and not have worn out, holey abominations on.
For the past 4 or 5 year’s, we’ve also had a Christmas Eve box.  It’s a cardboard box in wrapping paper.  Well it was.  This year I upgraded and got a proper wooden, personalised box from ebay.  The contents are a family secret, but it’s a tradition that we’ve come up with over the years that Ross and I have made together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016christmaseve.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016 Christmas day&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went for the traditional pre-lunch drink to The Orange Tree and got a traditional hug from The Land Lord who has recently returned from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Orange-Tree-Everest-Trek-2016-1113912225351879/&quot;&gt; his intrepid adventures in Nepal to Everest Base Camp.&lt;/a&gt;  We both made it to Christmas 2016!! And we both have Wills thanks to the very clever Robert from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbwlaw.biz/&quot;&gt;BBW.&lt;/a&gt; (At least that’s one thing ticked off the To Do list.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016christmasday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016 Christmas Day&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at home, Uncle Max produced a magnum of Prosecco which went down very well with Ross’s Christmas Dinner which was just as amazing, if not more so than last year’s. I can’t drink as much alcohol these days, so after 2 G&amp;amp;T’s, a prosecco and a Bailey’s, I was done in, and along with everyone else, slipped happily and easily into a Food Coma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, on Boxing Day, Dad and Julie went off to the Kent Hoggs on the next stage of their Christmas Travels. After waving them off, we decided to get some fresh air and went off to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationaltrust.org.uk/wimpole-estate&quot;&gt;Wimpole Hall&lt;/a&gt;.  A lot of other families seemed to have the same idea but we went off the beaten track and  walked the way of the kids ParkRun.  I hadn’t gone that way before and it was fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016boxingdaywalk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016 Boxing Day&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all it was a pretty normal Christmas.  And I like it when things are normal.  When things were quiet.  Normal and quiet are good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/christmas&quot;&gt;Christmas 2016&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 26, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safe Cycles]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/safety-cycles" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/safety-cycles</id>
  <published>2016-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">(This isn&#39;t a festive post).&lt;p&gt;In my last blog post, I spoke about having a two week break in Anastrozole, the daily hormone inhibitor tablet, to see if it made a difference to my tiredness.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It didn’t.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So, back to square one.  I need to go back to have my thyroid levels checked, and then go to discuss the results with the GP.  The last ones have been normal, so I don’t expect these ones to be much different.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So, still no answers.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m still constantly, bone crushingly, tired. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But it’s the type of tiredness that even if I go to bed at 9pm and wake up at 9am, I don’t feel refreshed or rested. I feel like I want to go back to sleep.  Often, despite feeling so tired, it can be impossible to sleep.  This is so frustrating, and when I resort to the prescription sleeping tablets, I feel like I’ve failed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Most recently, I’ve been struggling mentally, with the perpetual cycles of scans and treatment.  When I was having treatment for the Stage II cancer, I had 18 cycles of Herceptin.  One infusion every 3 weeks with a break for surgery, starting on Thursday 21st November 2013, ending on Thursday 8th January 2015.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m up to cycle 16.  At this point last time, I was counting down, ”2 to go”! &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Now, there is no countdown.  I have to get as many treatments under my belt as I can.  Because this treatment is keeping the cancer under control, it needs to keep working for as many cycles as we can.  The longer it works, the more the tumours are kept at bay and the longer I live…it’s as simple as that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Treatment every 3 weeks. Blood tests, one or two days before each treatment. Scans every 3 months.  Daily tablets.  Hormone inhibitor implant every 4 weeks. Constant pain.  Completely random sleep patterns. This is my normal now.  And I hate it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016newnormal.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Normal&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking at me, you’ll see a normal person.  No visible signs of anything untoward going on.  But that’s a facade.  It’s a mask.  The person behind that mask is not the Julia who went into this maelstrom in October 2013.  That person was confident, capable and carefree.  The current one backs away from people and social situations, and gets anxious about the smallest thing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thankfully, I have access to the fantastic support and services from my local hospice, Garden House Hospice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I regularly see a palliative consultant to discuss my overall physical and mental health. In one of my last appointments the subject of Depression was raised along with a potential treatment plan of anti-depressants.  Having taken them in the past when I had Postnatal Depression after Felix, I know how they can help, but I want to try other things first.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Hospice allows me to access reflexology and aromatherapy, which I find helps to relax me.  I also see a Music Therapist.  It’s a new service, but it’s fantastic.  I’m surprised people aren’t banging the door down to book a session.   I love these sessions, as I get to sing in a safe environment, and I love singing.  It can make me cry if a song hits me with it’s lyrics.  Queen’s “Who want’s To Live Forever” is a killer, but I still sing it!  The hour I have is so precious.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Crucially, I also had access to a counsellor.  I saw her earlier in the year when I was coming to terms with my Stage IV diagnosis.  This time though, it’s coming to terms with the fact that this is how my life is now.  Even when I’m well, I still have the same cycles of treatments and scans.  And that’s rubbish.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So, if you see me when I’m out (which isn’t as often as I used to), and you ask me how I am, I’ll probably tell you I’m fine.  I don’t think you are actually interested in what is really going on.  This is less to do with you, and more to do with me.  Don’t be insulted.  Don’t think I need to “get it all out” or “open up”.  I talk about things with my counsellor.  I talk about things to Ross.  I talk about different things to different people.  Don’t be offended if I say “I’m ok” , it’s a safe answer and at the minute, more than anything, I need to feel safe.
&lt;br /&gt;
Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/safety-cycles&quot;&gt;Safe Cycles&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on December 22, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quarterly Scan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/all-clear" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/all-clear</id>
  <published>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Friday 4th November, Ross and I schlepped down to Mount Vernon for my quarterly scan.  The one that I have to have to check that I don’t have any gremlins getting together and having a little party and growing into a tumour.  I don’t like lumps and I don’t like tumours.    We’ve had a lot to deal with this year and if I’m honest 2016 has been pretty awful.  It was supposed to be the year we started living again.  We’d got all the big surgeries, including reconstruction, out the way.  We were going to go on a big abroad holiday, somewhere with a pool, an beach and some sunshine.  We were going to get the house decorated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it wasn’t to be, 2016 was The Lawley’s ‘Annus Horribilis’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We waited for the results of the scan to come through, and a few days later, I got an email from my consultants secretary saying he wanted to see me at his evening clinic.  I think it’s fair to say, Ross and I pretty much freaked out at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phrases including “It’s never good news to get called in this quick”, “Results this fast?  F**k”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after dropping the kids off to a, lets be fair, very worried Michelle, we went to meet the Oncologist.  We waited, we moved to a different part of the hospital, and then we were called in.  “The scan was fine!” he said!  Ross and I came down from the ceiling.  All was fine!!  Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concern now is my continuing tiredness.  As we know I’m cancer free right now,  the plan is for me to come off my daily hormone tablet, (Anastrozole), for two weeks to see if that’s the cause.  It’s been worrying, but as I’ve had a lingering cold for so long, it’s been pushed to the back of my mind.  The two weeks is up on the 28th November, so we’ll see what happens next.  I don’t think it’s made too much of a difference.  Maybe a little bit, but I’ll be put on a sister drug of Anastrolzole which will reduce the amount of Oestrogen in my body.  I won’t be left without a daily hormone restricter.  As my type of cancer is er+ it likes hormones.  It gets bigger by eating hormones (sort of).  And the less Oestrogen in my body the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be back with an update on that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/all-clear&quot;&gt;Quarterly Scan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 13, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Half Term]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/half-term" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/half-term</id>
  <published>2016-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier in October, Ross was scheduled to go away to New York for work.  This was the first time I’d been left on my own without extra help in the form of my Dad and/or Julie.  It was decided that if I felt I needed help, I could ask some of my local friends.  I needed to see if I could cope with the kids on my own.  I only have a finite amount of energy, and I have to work out how to use that energy.  A lady called Christine Miserandino wrote a great post on her blog in which she described &lt;a href=&quot;https://butyoudontlooksick.com/articles/written-by-christine/the-spoon-theory/&quot;&gt;The Spoon Theory.&lt;/a&gt;  It’s very interesting, and explains how it feels to live day to day with a condition which stops you living the kind of life you want to live - stopping you from living it to the full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Ross went to Heathrow to start his long journey to The States on the Monday afternoon, and he was due to get back early Friday morning.  We have to apply for her secondary school place by the end of October, and there was an open day at out local high school which he needed to be at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I walk to school, it’s a mile each way, and doing that twice a day pretty much uses up all my energy, all my spoons.  It means I can’t cook tea, I can’t take them to clubs or lessons.  It was not an option to walk them whilst he was away.  Thankfully, the school have been great and I’m able to park in the school grounds when I take them and drop them off.  Imy likes to walk into school with a friend most of the time, but on Tuesday’s she comes in with us.  So, on Tuesday morning, we all drove to school, and I gave myself a pat on the back for getting there on time.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Wednesday, I was starting to need flag and I had to call in a few favours.  One was to collect them from school, and another to bring Imy home from Street Dance.  I had hoped to go to choir, but despite having a few people offer to look after the kids, there were no spoons left.  I couldn’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got through the week, but I was exhausted.  And that was despite the fact that the kids were at school for most of the day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when Ross was due to go away at half term, we knew I wasn’t going to be able to cope, so we decamped up to my Dad’s and Grandma Julie’s house.  We had a lovely time.  Ross drove us up there on the Saturday, he went to Brussels on Tuesday and then he came back on the Thursday.  My Dad was able to take the strain with the kids, they were able run off their energy on the beach.  Imy and Felix spent time with their cousins Oscar and Elsie, I made my Christmas cake and we spent time with my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/halfterm2016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Half Term Fun&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s.  Sometimes I don’t have time to write a full on blog post, so I’ve set up a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/TeamLawley/&quot;&gt;Facebook page - @TeamLawley Big Lump and The Lawley’s&lt;/a&gt; which the new blog posts will be shared on, as well as other mutterings and musings.  Give it a ‘Thumbs Up’ so you keep up to date with everything.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/half-term&quot;&gt;Half Term&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on November 01, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweet Sounds and Kind Messages]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sweet-sounds" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sweet-sounds</id>
  <published>2016-10-06T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-10-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back in April 2014, whilst I was recovering from my bilateral mastectomy and Axillary node clearance, I decided to write a &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/happiness-and-sadness/&quot;&gt;bucket list.&lt;/a&gt;  I didn’t call it a Bucket List, it was a “To do list”.  Whatever I called it, this is what was on the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sort the garden - I&#39;m not sure what I meant by this, but the garden is now a lot tidier than it was. tick!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Stain/paint some furniture - I&#39;ve painted three bedside tables and a chest of drawers. tick!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Run a 10k - I ran the Standalone 10km in October 2014 with Michelle.  tick!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Race for Life Pretty Muddy - A hardy bunch of Gin Clubbers helped me get round a Muddy 5km in June 2015.  tick!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; do a triathlon - I&#39;ll come back to this in another blog post in the future...there is a plan...sort of!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one thing that I didn’t have written down, but was on the list in my head.  This was to join a choir and start singing again.  I love singing, but for some reason, I lost my confidence and I stopped singing in public when I was about 16.  Prior to that, I’d been in the school choir, school session group, I’d sang as the performing part of my music GCSE (I got a B by the way), my friend, Jenny, and I wrote and performed a song in a local songwriting competition, (we didn’t win, but we had fun).  I’d sung solos in charity concerts, I even sang some big show tunes at a family friend’s wedding - accompanied by my Grandad on the piano.  But something changed in my head, I thought I had an awful voice and no one would want to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2014, whilst still having Herceptin, with a chemo crew cut, and no boobs, I pulled up my Big Girl Pants and I joined a choir.  On the evening I decided to join &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.singingaloud.com/&quot;&gt;Singing Aloud&lt;/a&gt; at Baldock Town Hall, I didn’t know if I’d know anyone there.  I walked in and was enveloped in warmth and kindness and I sang again.  It was lovely.  As it happened, I did know a couple of people.  Tash - I knew from when our boys were a nursery together.  Kerry - a mum from rugby.  It was going to be fine.  I was going to be fine.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to get to choir as much as I can.  I enjoyed the practice and I enjoyed the concerts.  I felt like I belonged in the group, and I wasn’t a bad X-Factor audition.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I haven’t been able to go as often as I would have liked, although I did manage to practice enough so that I could take part in a performance at the Baldock Beer Festival with my friends and family watching.
 I have started to gauge how well I am, based on if I can go to choir practice or not.  Last Wednesday, I made it for the first time since May. Once again, I was enveloped in the warmth and kindness and I sang.  It was lovely.  Unfortunately, I missed it again last night.  Ross is away in New York, and I’m flying solo with the kids.  It’s really stretching my energy levels.  But I’m hoping to be there again soon…it’s a measure of my health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s.  Last week I had a message from someone who reads the blog.  She was very kind telling me how much she enjoys the blog and how informative she finds it.  It was a lovely and unexpected message and really brightened my day.  There are two reasons I write the blog.  The first is as it’s cathartic for me to write down the thoughts to get them out of my head and stop them swirling around getting in the way of me doing other things.  The second is to keep my family and friends up to date with me and my treatment.  If anyone else reads it and finds it helpful, then that’s brilliant. The more the merrier.  Thank you for your message Joe.  It spurred me into writing a couple more posts. xx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/sweet-sounds&quot;&gt;Sweet Sounds and Kind Messages&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on October 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Railway Children]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/railway_children" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/railway_children</id>
  <published>2016-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">On Saturday, Felix and I had an Adventure!&lt;p&gt;Saturday was a very exciting day for Felix and I.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elliesfriends.org/&quot;&gt;Ellie’s Friends&lt;/a&gt;, a charity we have been a grateful recipient for in the past (with a Hotel Chocolat voucher), had given me two complimentary front row seats to see The Railway Children in London! &lt;strong&gt;London!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was slightly anxious about getting the train with just myself and The Boy, but it was fine.  We got into Kings Cross and set about looking for somewhere to grab a quick bite to eat.  We weren’t fussy.  Felix had downloaded Pokemon Go! onto my phone when we were waiting at Baldock Station, so he was more interested in catching Pokemon than eating.  A quick scout round found us an M&amp;amp;S and we each got a sarnie (£5 for a Meal Deal?  Really?  Is that just station prices, or is that how much they actually cost!), and some Percy Pigs for the show.  It was a nice, sunny day, so we plonked ourselves down on a bench and ate our lunch.  Kings Cross has certainly changed since we moved to Baldock and began commuting into work in London.  Back then, you wouldn’t want to stay for any length of time.  Now it’s clean, open and more appealing!  You still get the Wierdies.  I noticed one particular Lady Wierdy who was approaching other ladies asking for something.  Thankfully she didn’t approach me, so we ate our lunch in peace, before making our way to the theatre.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theatre is actually a temporary structure built over the railway tracks and will eventually become the Google offices.  It’s very clever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bar area is set up to look like a turn of the century ticket office, with period luggage.  Even better, they had Fentiman’s Rose Lemonade and Ginger Beer.  Felix was very impressed that we could order drinks at the bar and collect them at the interval without having to queue at the bar.  It was just as well as there were several packs of Brownies there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were sitting down in our seats, the cast of the play came out to interact with the audience.  Caroline Harker spoke to Felix and asked him if he’d seen the film or knew the story.  When he said “no” she was very nice and said she thought he would enjoy the play.  She was right.  It was fantastic.  We had a great time.  We munched our way through the Percy Pigs we’d bought and enjoyed the superb adaptation of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the play was over, we headed back to Kings Cross to head home, but not before making some purchases from Paperchase and Hotel Chocolat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived home exhausted, but I was so pleased I got to spend some one to one time with Felix. That doesn’t happen often. In fact I haven’t spent much time with just Imy recently.  We’ll have to change that!  And soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/railwaychildren.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Railway Children Trip to London&quot; style=&quot;width:auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/railway_children&quot;&gt;Railway Children&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 26, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morphine Moments]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/morphine_moments" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/morphine_moments</id>
  <published>2016-09-08T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Over the summer holidays I had been keen to come off the Morphine.&lt;p&gt;Back in January, when I first waved the flag to get help with the pain in my back, I was given a cocktail of drugs to take.  These were Diazapan (Valium), Naproxen (similar but stronger than Ibuprofen) and Co-codamol.  As soon as it was confirmed the cancer had returned, the Co-codamol was switched to oral Morphine and I was given steroids as well. (Did you know that when you pick up a prescription for Morphine, it can’t go straight to the pharmacy in an electronic prescription, it has to be signed for at the doctors and also at the pharmacy - it’s a Controlled Drug.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point, I was taking 5ml of Oramorph as and when I needed it, but it was becoming very clear that this wasn’t enough, and that was why I ended up in the Garden House Hospice.  I was terrified of the prospect of going to the Hospice.  That’s where people go to die!  How wrong I was.  From the very start I was enveloped by a cloud of calm, welcoming, loving help.  I had my own room looking out onto the beautiful garden.  Even in February it was obvious a lot of time had been spent on it.  The nursing staff, the volunteers, the doctors, and the family support team were all there to get not just me, but my whole family, through what was fast becoming a tough stage in our lives.  Sometimes it felt like I was walking through treacle, unable to see further than the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst at the Hospice, the doctors would  monitor my medication.  Everytime I asked for extra pain relief it was recorded so that I could be given slow release Morphine twice a day, becoming less reliant on the immediate hit of the Oramorph. By the time I left, I was taking 130mg of slow release Morphine, twice a day.  That is a lot.  I was also given a nerve drug called Gabapentin which helped alleviate the nerve pain I was experiencing.  The nerve to my leg had been pressed upon causing me grief.  The hope was that the Cyberknife would kill the cancer, and stop the pain.  For some, having Cyberknife or standard radiotherapy is enough to kill the cancer and stop the pain.  Unfortunately, what happened with me was the cancer had grown into the outside bone of the vertebrae, and had essentially escaped the confines of it’s prison.  What then happened was, some of it had been killed, and as it died, my L4 vertebrae collapsed.  I was essentially walking around with a broken back.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human body is an amazing thing.  When things are broken, it tries to fix it.  So when my vertebrae collapsed, tissue began to grow.  Unfortunately some of this tissue was cancerous and something (I’m not certain if it was malignant or benign) began to grow around the nerve to my leg, slowly crushing it.&lt;br /&gt;
The purpose of my surgery in June was to stabilise my back, as well as removing any rogue tissue, and freeing the leg nerve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this surgery, despite the initial few days when the pain was off the scale, I was put down to 90mg of Morphine, twice a day.  I was able to function on the reduced dose and two months post surgery, I was thinking about reducing my dose again.
I have had great out-patient help from the Hospice and I see a Palliative Consultant regularly.  With his help, we made a plan of reducing my pain medication.  I was able to come off the Diazapan quickly, as well as Zopiclone which is a sleeping tablet.  (I had been in so much pain, I wasn’t sleeping, so I was given some extra help.)  My next challenge was to reduce the Morphine.  Together with my Consultant, we made a plan to reduce the dose by 10mg every three days. Easy!  Or so I thought…
It began well!  90mg down to 80mg down to 70mg…and then I got to 30mg.  I started to feel a bit sore, but I was determined to keep going.  Ross decided I was safe enough to drive the care, which I was over the moon about.  My independence was back!  It was great.  I passed my driving test 6 weeks after I turned 17, and I’ve been driving ever since.  Having spent the whole of 2016 thus far not driving, to start again was a huge deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then I went down to 20mg…bit more pain…10mg…a lot more pain…and then I was down to 0mg.  It was awful!  I was in pain almost constantly.  I couldn’t find a position I was comfortable in.  In bed, I felt like my back was sending shots of pain all over the place and it was impossible for me to sleep.  I was tired, grumpy, shouting at everyone, not nice to be around.  That was it, I went back up to 20mg and I felt so much better.  Except, mentally, I felt like a failure.  I was useless. I couldn’t even stop taking painkillers.  LOSER!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of days after this, I saw the Consultant again, and I told him what had happened.  He said I had done the right thing going back to 20mg, and that I was still only 3 months post spinal surgery.  He told me I’d done ever so well to get to that point!  He also suggested that I start taking the Diazapan at night to relax the muscles around my back, to hopefully get a good night’s sleep.  I was given a good talking to, told to stop catastrophizing, stop being hard on myself, and enjoy life!  Doctor’s Orders!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, despite wanting to be off the Morphine, I’m not.  I’m also still on Naproxen, Gabapentin and Diazapan. (The Gabapentin is still used for the nerve pain in my leg, as despite being free, it still remembers the crushing, and it likes to remind me that it remembers.  Nice!) This is in addition to the tablets I have to take to alleviate the side effects of these drugs: sickness; constipation; itchiness. Oh, and not forgetting the hormone suppressant tablets, that are supposed to keep any new hormone receptive positive tumours at bay, and put me into an early menopause to boot. :-/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may not be off the drugs, but I have to live for the day.  My old school motto -  Carpe Diem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/morphine_moments&quot;&gt;Morphine Moments&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 08, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back To School 2016]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-school-2016" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-school-2016</id>
  <published>2016-09-07T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">We roll into September and I have time to catch up with myself.&lt;p&gt;The bairns went back to school on Monday, and I achieved my objective by walking them there on their first day.  Back in January, the last time I walked them to school before the rug was pulled out from under us, I had two people, who I didn’t know to speak to, ask if they could talk Imy and Felix to school for me as I was obviously struggling with pain.  When I got the kids to school, I actually joked with my friends that I’d diagnosed myself with tumours in my back, and then laughed, I couldn’t be that unlucky!  How little I knew.  Even at that point, I don’t think I really understood how cancer could manifest itself in the spine.  I thought the tumours would be on the outside, attached to the vertebrae.  I hadn’t realised that the cancer could grow inside a vertebrae.  Little did Ross and I know we’d be on a very steep learning curve.  Walking the kids to school has always been an indication of my “Normal”.  It’s something I’ve missed doing.  That and driving.  My “Normal” indicators.  If I can’t do either of them, something is not right.  At the minute, I need to be kind to myself and build up my stamina.  I managed two school runs on Monday, but only one on Tuesday, as I also had to do a Tesco shop.  That left me shattered, and I was aching everywhere.  Thankfully Ross was around to pick up the slack.  I’ll try again tomorrow, but I think I was unrealistic in thinking I could do 5 days of school runs from a standing start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kids_backtoschool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Back To School 2016 Collage&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last blog post was written halfway through my two week radiotherapy course.  I had been suffering terribly with sickness.  It was awful, however, it was acute, and only lasted for that first week, and was controlled by the medication prescribed by my Oncologist.  The second week, unfortunately, the problem changed direction and I was hit with a bout of diarrhoea.  Immodium was advised and I had to just crack on.  My course was due to finish on a Monday as I’d had a day off for Herceptin. Unfortunately, this looked to be in jeopardy when Big Bertha the radiotherapy machine was declared out of action on the Friday.  Thankfully, a new part was fitted, and I was called in on the Saturday morning to catch up.  Ross had never been with me to the Radiotherapy Centre in Elstree, despite going there every week day for thee weeks back in 2014, and everyday for two weeks this time.  I’ve always been taken by a taxi.  As I had to go for an extra session on a Saturday, he was able to see where I had been going.  Once I’d caught up, and then had the last session on the Monday, we were ready to go on holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/seaside.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norfolk seaside&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were very excited to be going up to North Norfolk’s coast to stay in our friend Tracey’s holiday home.  The weather was great, and that week we swam in the sea, went crabbing from Cromer Pier, ate some fabulous food, blew glass, chilled out, cycled around Holkham estate, played in the arcade, and generally spent some quality family time together.  I was able to take things easy if I needed to, and the kids could mess about in the garden. It was a great holiday.  Just what the doctor ordered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/norfolk_collage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norfolk holiday 2016&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst on holiday we implemented a technical device ban, and the kids were absolutely brilliant.  They occupied themselves playing with the Snap Circuits Felix got for his birthday, or playing football in the garden, or drawing.  I was the one who broke the rule, checking my email and Facebook every so often.  As it turns out, in amongst the nonsense emails from Next, IKEA, Marks and Spencer and John Lewis, was one we’d been waiting for from the Oncologist.  It was the pathology results from the sample taken during my spinal surgery in June.  We already knew that they’d found active cancer cells, but we were waiting for further analysis to see if it was HER2+.  The email confirmed that it was HER2+.  This means that despite me starting Herceptin in January and having 7 infusions, on top of Cyberknife, and hormone suppressant therapy, the cancer had continued to grow. This shouldn’t have been the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got back home I had a catch up with my Oncologist. He wanted to see how I was after the radiotherapy.  He explained that the dark coloured square of skin on my back may well become thickened and that I may get a darkened square of my front as well due to the way the radiotherapy works.  I also wanted to question why I wasn’t being given chemotherapy.  One of the things we had been led to believe was that if cancerous cells were found to be active in my spine when I had the surgery, then I’d have chemo.  It was explained to us, that the existing regime is keeping any new tumours in check, and if I were to have chemo now, there would be no way of measuring it’s effectiveness.  So, it’s being kept in reserve for future use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final two weeks of the holiday were taken up with rugby camp, new uniform shopping, getting haircuts, etc.  On the very last day of the holiday with only the weekend before starting school, we went to the Harry Potter tour in North West London.  This had very kindly been given to us by our former colleagues at MediaTel.  What a day!  I first read Philosopher’s Stone when I was working at MediaTel and went to see the first film with the ladies on the J-ET team.  The tour did not disappoint.  It gave us an insight into how the film was made, the detail that was created, even things that were made, only to be on screen for a split second!  The model castle at he end of the tour was stunning.  We certainly won’t forget the day, and will be proudly wearing our Hogwart’s T-Shirt or Hoodie whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/harrypotter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Harry Potter&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so we begin the new school year with Imy in Year 6 and Felix in Year 4 and the knowledge that in the next two months, we have to apply for Imogen’s senior school place.  I’m not sure I’m ready for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/back-to-school-2016&quot;&gt;Back To School 2016&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on September 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radio Ga Ga]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/radiotherapy" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/radiotherapy</id>
  <published>2016-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I&#39;m 5 into a course of 10 radiotherapy sessions.&lt;p&gt;I think it’s fair to say I completely underestimated how the radiotherapy would affect me.  I had 15 sessions two years ago for the breast cancer, and I was lucky with the side effects. I had been told to expect skin soreness, swelling, redness and tiredness.  I was warned that I could end up with an open wound that would take ages to heal.  I ended up with a square tan on my chest, and a little bit tired, but not enough to stop me doing what I wanted to do.  In fact after the last session, we went off camping for the weekend and had a great time.  Admittedly, I stayed at the campsite for a nap when the rest of the campers went off for a forest adventure taking Imy and Felix with them.  Ross stayed to keep an eye on me…and the beer.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial session of this course of 10, had been delayed from 13:30 until 16:30 as the Cyberknife I had in February had complicated things.  They needed to make sure that any further radiotherapy would not cause me any damage in the future.  When the taxi picked me up to take me to the radiotherapy centre, the approval still had not been received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all this palava, I was starting to get a bit nervous, and it was causing my tummy to feel a bit jittery.  Eventually, approval was given, and I had my first zap at about 5pm.  The taxi took me home and I got there just as Ross was serving up the tea I’d made earlier from the slow cooker.  Just one whiff of the food sent me over the top, and I had to run to the loo to be sick.  After that, I sat very pale on my new chair* until it was time to go to bed, hoping that the next day would be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second session was at the usual time of 13:30, and the same happened.  I got home, was sick and fell asleep.  It was still a bug as far as I was concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/radiotherapy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Big Bertha&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Wednesday, I had a day off, as I was due to have a heart scan, see the cardiologist, and then the usual infusions of Herceptin and Zometa.  Fortunately, I kept my stomach contents to myself!  Yay!  (Although some day off!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Thursday, it was back to being zapped, getting home, being sick and sleeping.  At this point, enough was enough and I contacted the radiographers on the Friday morning to tell them about the sickness.  They contacted my consultant, and by Friday afternoon I was in possession of some tablets to stop me feeling and being sick.  It was like magic.  One of those babies, and the sickness was gone.  The relief!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing it didn’t sort out for me, was the fatigue and tiredness.  Completely different to the last time.  If last time, it was mild, this time it’s severe.  I don’t feel like I’m a particularly useful human being at the minute. Although I did feel a bit brighter this morning when this arrived from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hotelchocolat.com/uk/&quot;&gt;Hotel Chocolat&lt;/a&gt;.  I was lucky enough to receive a gift card from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elliesfriends.org/&quot;&gt;Ellie’s Friend&lt;/a&gt; who’s aim “is to give adults living with cancer the opportunity to enjoy life, not just survive it!”.  Champagne truffle’s?  Guilty as charged!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chocolate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hotel Chocolat&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 more sessions to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*After a recent trip to IKEA, I got a chair that would support my back better than our sofa’s do.  Our fat cat Mog, however, seems to think it’s hers, so we have daily stand off as to who is going to have it.  Pesky Cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/fatcat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fat Cat&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/radiotherapy&quot;&gt;Radio Ga Ga&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on August 08, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Birthdays, Races and other stuff...]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/birthdays-races" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/birthdays-races</id>
  <published>2016-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Writing the blog this time round isn&#39;t as easy as it was when I had a primary diagnosis.&lt;p&gt;I would write a blog post when anything interesting happened.  Whether it be medical or personal.  I found it quite easy to just sit down and write.  This time round, I’m finding it hard.  I don’t know if it’s the constant fatigue or a case of Cantbearseditis, but it’s difficult.  (This post has taken about 4 hours to write…ridiculous!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I find myself in a position where it’s nearly two months after the last post and so much has happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we had Imy’s birthday.  It was quite interesting. As soon as she had opened her presents, her and Ross went to IKEA to get furniture for her bedroom that had been talked about, but we hadn’t got round to.  They came home with lots of boxes and then we went to Pizza Express for dinner.  A bit of a bonkers birthday if you ask me, but she was happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was Ross’s birthday. Unfortunately it was sandwiched between an MRI the day before and Herceptin the day after, so we were rather stuck in terms of what we could do. Fortunately, his parents’s were in the country so they came over for the day to make it a bit special for him and we had a great take out curry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/birthdays.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imy and Ross birthday&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In between the two birthdays, we had the Race for Life.  Thanks to a reconfigured RfL Gin Club team for 2016, Imy and Felix were able to run without me, much to their delight!  (I had been told that I hold them back…)
The week before the Race, I was contacted by the event organiser and asked if I would speak to a local newspaper about what had happened to me, and how the Race was so important to try and get more ladies to sign up. She also asked if I would go onto the stage at the event and do the same to encourage and thank the ladies involved. I even got to honk the horn to start it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imy and Felix raised over £1100, and as a team the total was well over £3000. Much needed money for a very good cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rfl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Race for Life&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to my back being so hurty after my op, Ross took this as an opportunity to replace the car.  Our car had sports suspension and I could feel every pot hole and fault in the road, (and there’s more than you know!).  We were due to replace it this year anyway, so it wasn’t long before he was going round local showrooms and reading up on cars.  Finally he decided upon a Mazda SUV and after signing on the dotted line, it was just a matter of time before it was delivered.  I hadn’t driven our old car since January, so I took it for a slow crawl around our close before we handed it over, bye bye old car.  I have yet to drive the new car, but I am looking forward to it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/newcar_oldcar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old car, new car&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few other events to mention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imy passed her grade 2 flute exam with merit.  Ross and I are so proud of her for sticking in and getting on with it, despite the tough times.  We are also very thankful to Heather&#39;s Mum, Shenna, for accompanying Imy on two of the pieces she had to play, and helping her along with the sight reading and aural tests.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ticked an item off my bucket list by going blonde. This came about as my hairdresser needed a model (for hair not looks - just as well!) who wanted to go blonde.  I&#39;m delighted with the results.  The kids thought I&#39;d be going platinum blonde, to a colour more like Felix&#39;s, so weren&#39;t too impressed with the change.  Pesky kids. :-)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Anna and Fiona organised a party for me at the Rugby Club.  The idea was to extend the Gin&#39;s I received for #GinForJulia to the Dad&#39;s so they could enjoy it as well.  We managed to get through a fair bit of it, but I had to leave early, due to reaching my limit after 2 G&amp;amp;T&#39;s, but feeling like I had a skinful.  I&#39;ll be glad when I&#39;m not taking the medication that affects me in this way.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ross&#39;s parents offered to look after the bairns for a weekend.  So, taking full advantage, we dropped them off in Newbury, and went on to Winchester.  
We had a lovely weekend, we walked a lot, we shopped, we chilled, we used the spa, we talked, and we missed the kids.  They hardly missed us, but I was delighted to hear how well they&#39;d behaved, how polite they were, and how generally wonderful they were.  I know they can play up for Ross and I, but they&#39;re ours and we are proud of them.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/winchester_collage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Winchester&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I think that’s us up to date…oh then comes radiotherapy… that’s a new post…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/birthdays-races&quot;&gt;Birthdays, Races and other stuff...&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on August 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Out the Otherside]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/out-the-otherside" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/out-the-otherside</id>
  <published>2016-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">It&#39;s been two weeks and five days since my surgery.&lt;p&gt;I had my operation in The Royal National Orthopaedic Hospital, Stanmore, North West London.  If you are having a tricky orthopaedic operation, you want to be in the best place, with the best equipment, and the best surgical team. I had that.  Even if the hospital is a bit wonky with sloped corridors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official name for my op was: “Combined anterior vertebrectomy with posterior fusion and instrumentation”.  In other words: Remove some of the vertebrae that had collapsed into bits, fix it into place with cement, wire, metal and screws to the vertebrae above and below.  A big operation.  However, no one told me how awful I would feel afterwards.  It took them a while, (and some tense words with a doctor) to get my pain under control, and in that time, I regretted everything.  I wish I hadn’t agreed to the op.  I was crying in the night as I was in so much pain, but the nurse wouldn’t believe I was in pain and I couldn’t move to get comfortable. The op was on the Saturday, I was in HDU until Monday, when I got moved to the regular ward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in hospital for 6 days.  Considering the surgery could have potentially left me paralysed below the waist, or with no bladder or bowel function, I think 6 days just shows how good the surgical team was and how determined I was to get home to my babies and Ross.  The hospital was 30 miles away from home, and on a good run would take 45 minutes.  Ross visited every day, but always made sure he left at a time when he wouldn’t get caught in A1/M25 traffic. My Dad and the bairns visited too, but they found it boring, so it wouldn’t be long before they were taken home. The hospital was a world away from the Garden House Hospice, which not only gave the kids things to do, but it was less than 5 minutes away, so friends and family could just pop in for as little or as long as they could. They could even take me out of the Hospice for a little while, which was an absolute no-no in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At times, in the hospital,  I found myself a bit lonely.  In general, I quite like my own company, I like pottering.  Unfortunately, I was unable to potter, as I was tied my bed, literally, with a catheter bag.  I was given various physiotherapy tasks that I had to do before I could be set free so I made sure I worked hard to get them right.  Once I was free, I had to do the Stair assessment, which made sure I was safe to go up and down stairs.  By 11am on Friday, I was all packed ready to come home.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for me to heal properly I have to be careful that I don’t bend down at the waist too far.  For example, I can’t bend in the middle to put my own socks and shoes on.  I have a grabber to help me pick things up from the floor.  I have to have a raised loo seat (sorry, to much information), and I have an Old Lady Chair, which we have borrowed from the British Red Cross.  The sofa’s in our front room are too low for me to sit on without causing damage to my newly cemented spine, and whilst the surgeon assured me, I couldn’t do any damage to his handiwork, I’d hate to think I could.  By the way, the Old Lady Chair doesn’t smell of wee.  Phew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m home, I get tired easily, but I enjoy having visitors, as long as they don’t  mind making their own tea.  I’m also enjoying online shopping, although Ross will be pleased to know I am trying to reign it in, so as not to bankrupt us.  Although, he’s giving it as good go himself with his new Bonsai obsession. (That needs a whole post to itself!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’re just waiting for the histology of the tissue taken from my spine now, which will dictate what happens next.  If the tissue is benign, then my treatment remains the same: Herceptin and Zometa infusions every 3 weeks, and hormone blockers in the form of an injection every 4 weeks, and daily tablets.  (There’s talk of surgery to remove my one remaining ovary, but I’ve asked for that to be put on hold for a bit first.)
 If the tissue is not benign (therefore cancerous), then my infusions will change to, most likely,  contain some form of chemotherapy - goodbye hair - again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t walk too far, as it hurts, but I’m not allowed to use a walking stick, unless I know we are going for a long walk, then it is necessary.  Progress is slow, but we’ll do what we have to:  keep on, keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/out-the-otherside&quot;&gt;Out the Otherside&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 23, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Half Term?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-half-term" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-half-term</id>
  <published>2016-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">This half term is busy...&lt;p&gt;…really busy.  It started with an inset day on Friday, but rather than be able to put it to good use and have a nice day out in the sunshine, we had to go to the hospital to get a CT scan.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thursday evening before the inset day, I went to see The Sons of Pitches in Bury St Edmunds, just over an hours drive away.  Tash had bought me the ticket and had said that I didn’t need to decide whether I wanted to go or not, until the day came.  She knew someone else in the choir would jump at the chance to take my place.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so pleased I went!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was amazing, they are so talented. The way they use there voices is incredible.  It felt like there was a band there, but it was just the 6 of them. We had really good seats which were right over the stage.  It was quite an insightful position!  I got a picture with Joe after, and got a CD signed by Mide, and we got a group of with the ladies from the choir with him too. I also got a T-shirt, poster, and two CD’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sonjoe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Son Joe&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sat there enjoying the music, I realised that I have never been to a music gig before.  I’ve performed with various music groups either singing or playing some type of musical instrument where people have paid to see it, mostly in the North East of England. However I have performed in the Royal Festival Hall (I think, or it might have been the Queen Elizabeth Hall next door, but either way it was on the South Bank of London.) and in a beautiful church in Bergen, Norway. The groups also played in schools in London and Bergen. (I’ve just realised that I have been to a few Classical concerts, including the BBC Proms, and a couple of Picnic in the Park’s on Hampstead Heath.  What a nerd.)  It got me thinking.  I need to do a bucket list.  Not a grand, bungee jumping or potholing list, but watching a ballet at the Royal Opera House.  Punting on the Cam. Have a spa day with my friends, a boating holiday.  Little things, but things I haven’t done before.  Things that I should do.  Things I think I should do sooner rather than later.  Oh, and make a Will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Friday…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michelle offered to have the bairns, on Friday morning, which was really appreciated as she’d only just moved into her new house.  I’d gone to bed late, and had to get up early so I could eat something as I had a 4 hour fast before the CT scan.  I’ve had lots of scans, but this one I’ll remember for a while as the two tubes which connected my port to the saline and contrast solution weren’t tightened enough and came undone covering my hair me in rather sticky fluid. So that was pleasant.  They also threw in a doppler ultrasound of my legs to see if there was a clot anywhere.  There wasn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the rest of the half term is taken up with:&lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday - Appointment with the Orthopaedic Surgeon who will perform the surgery.&lt;br /&gt;
Wednesday - The 3 weekly Herceptin and Zometa infusion&lt;br /&gt;
Thursday - My Counseling session, and my Dad coming down (yay!)&lt;br /&gt;
Friday - Admitted into hospital&lt;br /&gt;
Saturday - Surgery&lt;br /&gt;
Sunday - Recovering from Surgery&lt;br /&gt;
Monday - I’m still in hospital, the bairns go back to school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I don’t feel we really get a half term.  I feel so bad for the kids. It’s all full of stupid medical stuff. This was the week we were going to go abroad on holiday.  Somewhere with a pool, somewhere reasonably hot. To get away from it all, have fun as a family.  But we can’t, because the stupid cancer got in the way.  I hate it.  I hate the way we have to change our plans to make room for it.  I hate it that form now on, I’m going to struggle to get travel insurance.  Get stuffed Cancer.  I want you out of my life.  I want it to be how it was before.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/what-half-term&quot;&gt;What Half Term?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on June 01, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Boy is 8]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/boy-is-8" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/boy-is-8</id>
  <published>2016-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">8!&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Felix had a few friends round to run around, have Nerf gun battles, and eat pizza.  Imogen got stuck in too, and a good time was had by all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is his birthday.  Ross and I had to wrap the birthday presents that were contained in a number of Amazon boxes.  We’d left pretty much everything until the last minute.  But luckily, we pulled it off and we got it all done on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/boyis8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Boy is 8&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felix was very pleased with his presents including “Exploding Kittens” which I had been a bit dubious about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Birthday Tea was a curry at the Lancer.  Everyone was a winner with that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Birthday to my Beautiful Boy.   Love you to the Moon and Back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/boy-is-8&quot;&gt;The Boy is 8&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 'C' Word]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-c-word" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-c-word</id>
  <published>2016-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">And I don&#39;t mean the book...&lt;p&gt;…written by Lisa Lynch. Not because I found it difficult or to close to home, but because I borrowed it from the library and had to give it back when I tried to renew it, as someone else wanted it. (humph). I had to buy it in the end, but I haven’t managed to pick up where I left off, as I’m reading another book.  Slowly.  Very S L O W L Y. I used to be able to read books very quickly.  I don’t know why, but I’ve been finding it hard going.  I’m still trying to finish ‘The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August’ which I started last October, when I was recovering from my Reconstruction.  It’s very good, and I’d tell you who it was by, but I can’t be bothered to walk up stairs and find out.  You’ll have to look it up for yourselves.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, whilst I’ve been writing this blog, I am very inconsistent with the case (Grammar, yawn) of the ‘c’ in Cancer.  Should it be a lower case ‘c’, or an upper case ‘C’?  If you know, can you put it in the comments section belong, so if I do get an answer from someone who knows, I’ll try (ha!) to be more consistent in future.  I promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s.  I probably do know, but it’s been filed away in the deep, dark depths of my brain under - “Not Relevant at Present.”  Cancer has a habit of slowly taking over your brain. To be clear, I’m not talking literally, more metaphorically. At present, I do not have cancer in my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/the-c-word&quot;&gt;The 'C' Word&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 25, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Secondary + Silver]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/secondary+silver" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/secondary+silver</id>
  <published>2016-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Cancer.  It&#39;s a word everyone is frightened of.&lt;p&gt;Most people have been touched by it in many ways, either them themselves, a friend or a relative.  For some, it’s caught early, treated fast, and life can continue as usual.&lt;br /&gt;
 For others it’s not quite as straightforward.  The cancer may have started in one place and spread somewhere else.  Like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when people learn you have secondary cancer, it baffles me when they say something like, “You’ll be glad when this is all over!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, with secondary cancer, it will never be ‘all over’.  There is no cure there is only ‘management’.  The Oncologists and Surgeons have a lot of tricks up their sleeves in order to manage the secondary cancer in order to keep me alive for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve realised looking back over the blog, the posts the first time round were quite frequent.  Sometimes once a day.  This time round, after a flurry of posts when I was first re-diagnosed, I haven’t written any posts. I don’t know why.  Possibly, because the treatment has been largely the same.  Every 3 weeks I have my Herceptin and Zometa infusion.  Nothing has really happened.  Except something has happened…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The L4 vertebrae, which was the one the cancer spread to, and had the cyberknife radiotherapy to, has now collapsed, and is unstable, which could cause huge problems if something isn’t done.   I’ve been seeing an Spinal surgeon who has seen my scans and between him and the oncologist, they have come up with a plan.  So, on the 4th of June, I shall be having a Partial Vertebrectomy.  (If you want to look up the details, the internet is a marvelous thing!  But as far as I can tell, it’s surgery done with play dough and meccano.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another news, due to my hand swelling up, I have not been able to wear my wedding rings, although my eternity ring hung in there the longest.  I’ve been married to Ross for 11 years, and we were engaged for 18 months prior to that, so it felt very odd not having a ring on my ring finger.  Whilst I was out buying a friend’s birthday present, I started look in the trays of silver rings.  Once Ross realised what I was doing, and why, he started looking too.  Eventually we found one that we both agreed on, and I love it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ring.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wedding Ring&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jx&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/secondary+silver&quot;&gt;Secondary + Silver&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 24, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time marches on]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/time-marches-on" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/time-marches-on</id>
  <published>2016-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">I can&#39;t quite believe my last post was in January. It seems an age away, but time marches on.&lt;p&gt;Looking at the blog we’ve missed out April and there’s been good reason, life settled back into some sort of routine. I’ve noticed Julia’s previous post was on mothers day, March 6th. The post made me smile because of the happy picture of Imogen with her “tackle monster” badge. A few hours after that photo was taken, I headed off to A&amp;amp;E with Imogen who was suffering from concussion after an blow to the head in a ruck earlier that day. Luckily, it was just a mild concussion but a confused and eccentric Imogen in the A&amp;amp;E waiting room is something I can chuckle at now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back now at February, it was a hard month. Lots of low points. As Julia’s pain is bought under control, she had to stay at the Garden House Hospice. However, life tries to be balanced and there were some good memories to! Julia’s birthday was one that comes to mind, a nice cream tea at Tapps and then Julia and I went out for dinner at The George. The amount of morphine swishing around her, meant that Julia couldn’t make it to pudding but it was good for her to get out the hospice for a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This neatly brings me back to the Garden House Hospice, what an amazing place. I didn’t really have a clue about such places, Julia’s initial reaction to the suggestion of going in to get some care was not positive. It shows how little we knew, quite simply they have been brilliant. They quickly got Julia’s pain under control and offered support for the family as a whole. That support is still ongoing and has and continues to be amazing. I’m so glad that such places exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia was back home from the Hospice with pain meds aplenty. These pain medicines have all sorts of side effects. The single worst being the smell that MST can make a person produce, at times it’s bordering chemical warfare grade. The first night back from the hospice, I was nearly gassed out of the bed! Thankfully with home cooking this side effect has settled, although there are times when in the supermarket when Julia suggests we quickly change aisle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike and Julie visited lots in March and April, their support was phenomenal and allowed me to get work and home life back on track. I can’t say thank you enough, those two little words don’t seem big enough. Over the Easter holidays we headed up to Cullercoats to see Julia’s family. The kids and I enjoyed plodging in the sea on Tynemouth Longsands and kicking the rugby ball about. We got to see Grandad’s boat before it was apparently nearly sunk in an incident that had been colourfully likened to an act as high sea piracy. Julia got to see her family and catch up, and although fatigue meant we had to return home early it was a good trip. The road trip also turned the kids into avid Archers fans as we listened to an Archers omnibus there and back, the rural intrigue kept them very quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fatigue we saw up in Cullercoats unfortunately has hung around. Julia rested for a couple of days then attended a weekend course for young people with secondary breast cancer in a hotel in London. It was hard for us both, her being away for the night. I found myself in a melancholic mood, missed her terribly and thought it a glimpse of the future to come. This was the result of being overly tired, something I try to avoid as it doesn’t help ones mood. Happily, it was only for a night and Julia was back home and very tired. I think she slept for the whole of Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve missed out many things really in this catchup post but the main theme is, February was hard and sucked. March was much better and quickly rolled into April where life felt pretty normal. There have been ups and downs and Julia’s recent fatigue curtailed her ability to potter or take the kids to school. But as much as we can we’ve cried, we’ve smiled and laughed together.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/time-marches-on&quot;&gt;Time marches on&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on May 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fireside Eggs & Mother's Day]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/eggs" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/eggs</id>
  <published>2016-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">On Saturday night, Ross and I go out.  Out!&lt;p&gt;The town where we live, is a quirky old place.  There are several festivals that run during the year, one of which is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firesidefestival.org/&quot;&gt;The Fireside Festival.&lt;/a&gt;  It’s a Storytelling Festival, and Ross and I decide to give it a go and see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anarchistcook.info/&quot;&gt; George Egg: Anarchist Cook.&lt;/a&gt;  The premise is a man who cooks a three course meal, in an hour, using items commonly found in a hotel room.  It was good, it was funny, but I got Wobbly Head again.  I wish I didn’t get it.  Ross and Michelle both noticed that I got Wobbly Head half way through the show.  Still, I persevered, and afterwards we went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theorangetreebaldock.com/&quot;&gt;The Orange Tree&lt;/a&gt; for a quick drink.  However, after just one, I was ready to come home. I was conscious I needed to take my evening medication, so Ross walked me home, sorted my meds and then he went back out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, that I had a little cry.  It was Saturday night, we had a babysitter, we had a legitimate reason to go out.  But I just didn’t have the energy.  It just didn’t seem fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I took myself off to bed, and with the help of the sleeping pills, I was off to the Land of Nod, and soon enough woken up with cuddles from the bairns on Mother’s Day.  They had made me some lovely hand made cards, the top one in the picture being from Imy.  The the bottom right is a list of things that make me a good mum according to Felix,  I’m particularly pleased with the Bedroom Tidier - I had rather hoped that they would be doing it themselves by now, but they obviously appreciate the help.  The glass cat makes me smile.  They know me well.  Crazy Cat Lady!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mothersday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mothers Day Gift and Cards&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After breakfast, (not in bed, as that would make too many crumbs and I want to spend the time with the family), I decide to go to the rugby club and catch up with the news from there.  It was good to see people who I hadn’t seen for a while, and we also see the smiley faces of the kids as they came in from their training session covered in mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tacklemonster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tackle Monster&quot; style=&quot;width: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick sprint (as much as you can with a stick) round the supermarket, once home, I was told to go and enjoy a Mother’s Day nap.   Which I did.  Very much so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Mather’s Day to all you lovely Mum’s out there.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/eggs&quot;&gt;Fireside Eggs & Mother's Day&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sing When You're Winning]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/choir" />
  <id>http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/choir</id>
  <published>2016-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Lawleys</name>
    <uri>http://teamrj.co.uk</uri>
    <email>ross.lawley@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">Once home, life starts to settle, into the new, new normal.&lt;p&gt;The day after I return home, Dad decides that it’s time for him to go back home, and I have to admit, Julie needs him more than I do now.  I don’t want to be greedy, he’s spent so much time with us, and for that I will be eternally grateful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more visitors cross the threshold, and I begin to start to go out and do normal things again.  I watch Felix’s swimming lesson, I go to the supermarket, just normal things.  Normal things are good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday evening, I manage to pull off the biggest coup to date.  And that was to return to choir.  I only managed the first half of the session as I found it difficult to keep up with the pace of things, but I enjoyed it, and I’m really glad I went. After an hour, I start to get what I call Whirly Eyes and Wobbly Head.  This is where my eyes start to roll back in their sockets, or where I can’t keep my head held up.  Everyone gets it at some point or another but they are more frequent for me these days.  Luckily, Tash gives me a lift home, and hopefully, all things being equal, I’ll be there again next week, failing that, the week after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to be well enough to sing in a couple of concerts this Spring/Summer.  Fingers Crossed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jx   &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk/articles/choir&quot;&gt;Sing When You're Winning&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Lawleys at &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrj.co.uk&quot;&gt;Big lump and the Lawleys&lt;/a&gt; on March 02, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>